<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dallas on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/dallas/</link><description>Recent content in dallas on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/dallas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unveiling White Rock Hospital's 1-Star Medicare Rating</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/white-rock-hospital-1-star-rating/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/white-rock-hospital-1-star-rating/</guid><description>The Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) a federal agency, recently named Baylor Scott &amp;amp; White Medical Center-White Rock, in Dallas, as one of the worst performing hospitals in America.&amp;nbsp;
The dubious 1-star ranking is based on 46 hospital quality measures that CMS uses to compare hospitals nationwide.
Only 248 hospitals nationwide received Medicare&amp;#39;s 1-star designation. This Dallas hospital was one of only seven hospitals in Texas to be named to Medicare&amp;#39;s 1-star list.</description></item><item><title>Dallas Medical Malpractice Lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/areas-we-serve/dallas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/areas-we-serve/dallas/</guid><description>Accidents can turn lives upside down, causing physical pain and unexpected financial strain. Even with health insurance, you may still face out-of-pocket expenses. If you or a loved one has been a victim of medical malpractice in the Dallas area, know that there are legal options available to you.
Welcome to Painter Law Firm, where our medical malpractice attorneys are dedicated to helping you seek the compensation you need to cover your injury-related losses.</description></item><item><title>Dallas court of appeals finds that claim against facility isn't limited by tort reform measures</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-court-of-appeals-finds-that-claim-against-facility-isnt-limited-by-tort-reform-measures/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-court-of-appeals-finds-that-claim-against-facility-isnt-limited-by-tort-reform-measures/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;When I use a word,&amp;rdquo; Humpty Dumpty said in rather a scornful tone, &amp;ldquo;it means just what I choose it to mean &amp;mdash; neither more nor less.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;The question is,&amp;rdquo; said Alice, &amp;ldquo;whether you can make words mean so many different things.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;The question is,&amp;rdquo; said Humpty Dumpty, &amp;ldquo;which is to be master &amp;mdash; that&amp;rsquo;s all.&amp;rdquo;
I often think about this quote from Lewis Carroll&amp;rsquo;s book Through the Looking Glass. I find that it fits well to Texas medical malpractice litigation.</description></item><item><title>Dallas court of appeals: Visitor slip and fall in hallway is not health care liability claim</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-court-of-appeals-visitor-slip-and-fall-in-hallway-is-not-health-care-liability-claim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-court-of-appeals-visitor-slip-and-fall-in-hallway-is-not-health-care-liability-claim/</guid><description>I recently wrote an article about a Houston court of appeals opinion dealing with a slip and fall injury at the hospital in the Texas Medical Center. It addresses the safety duty owed by hospital to visitors.
In a December 2020 opinion, the Dallas Court of Appeals considered another thorny issue for health care facility visitors injured in a slip and fall, namely whether the tort reform requirements and limitations of the Texas Medical Liability Act apply.</description></item><item><title>What can the trial court consider at a Chapter 74 preliminary expert report hearing in a Texas medical malpractice case?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-can-the-trial-court-consider-at-a-chapter-74-preliminary-expert-report-hearing-in-a-texas-medical-malpractice-case/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-can-the-trial-court-consider-at-a-chapter-74-preliminary-expert-report-hearing-in-a-texas-medical-malpractice-case/</guid><description>Texas law requires medical malpractice plaintiffs to produce one or more medical expert reports within 120 days of each defendant filing an answer and a lawsuit. The standards for these reports are demanding, requiring separate statements of the applicable standard of care (what should have been done), how the standard of care was violated (what wasn&amp;rsquo;t done correctly), and how those medical mistakes proximately caused harm to the plaintiff.
How do defendants respond to the preliminary expert reports, and what are the potential consequences?</description></item><item><title>Dallas court of appeals defines when a hospital or doctor's duty to disclose malpractice ends</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-court-of-appeals-defines-when-a-hospital-or-doctors-duty-to-disclose-malpractice-ends/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-court-of-appeals-defines-when-a-hospital-or-doctors-duty-to-disclose-malpractice-ends/</guid><description>A statute of limitations is a law that limits the amount of time that a plaintiff has to file a particular type of case. For Texas breach of contract cases, the statute of limitations is four years. For medical malpractice cases, and all types of negligence, the general statute of limitations is two years.
The analysis isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly that easy, though.
There are a variety of situations that may extend or toll the statute of limitations in medical negligence cases.</description></item><item><title>Medical malpractice wrongful death lawsuit: Routine CT scan with contrast ends in death at Gateway Diagnostic Imaging, LLC d/b/a Gateway Diagnostic Mid-Cities</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medical-malpractice-wrongful-death-lawsuit-routine-ct-scan-with-contrast-ends-in-death-at-gateway-diagnostic-imaging-llc-d/b/a-gateway-diagnostic-mid-cities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medical-malpractice-wrongful-death-lawsuit-routine-ct-scan-with-contrast-ends-in-death-at-gateway-diagnostic-imaging-llc-d/b/a-gateway-diagnostic-mid-cities/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm filed a medical malpractice wrongful death lawsuit yesterday against Gateway Diagnostic Imaging, LLC d/b/a Gateway Diagnostic Mid-Cities and three physicians arising from the death of a healthy 52-year-old man following a CT scan of the abdomen and pelvis for suspected kidney stones.
The case is pending in the 101st District Court of Dallas County, Texas, where the presiding judge is The Hon. Staci Williams. You can read the original petition here.</description></item><item><title>Do large hospital mergers and chains necessarily equal quality patient care?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/do-large-hospital-mergers-and-chains-necessarily-equal-quality-patient-care/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/do-large-hospital-mergers-and-chains-necessarily-equal-quality-patient-care/</guid><description>On October 1, 2018, Houston-based Memorial Hermann Health System and Dallas-based Baylor Scott &amp;amp; White Health announced plans to merge into a new entity. Currently, the two systems combined have 68 hospitals, over 14,000 physicians on their medical staffs, and around 10 million patient visits annually.
If the merger goes through, the new hospital system would dominate a huge swath of Texas, including Houston, Dallas, and Austin. Officials from both hospitals contend that combining ownership and operations would create efficiencies and reduce costs.</description></item><item><title>Dallas court of appeals rules in favor of patient/plaintiff on expert report</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-court-of-appeals-rules-in-favor-of-patient/plaintiff-on-expert-report/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-court-of-appeals-rules-in-favor-of-patient/plaintiff-on-expert-report/</guid><description>As a Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I handle cases all over the Lone Star State, including Houston, Dallas, Austin, San Antonio, Corpus Christi, and Waco.
One of the factors that I consider in deciding whether I can help someone injured by hospital or physician care is whether it is likely that we could secure the support of a medical expert very early in the case.
Unlike other types of negligence cases, Texas Civil Practice &amp;amp; Remedies Code chapter 74 requires medical malpractice plaintiffs to serve on all defendants one or more expert reports within 120 days of each defendant filing an answer in the lawsuit.</description></item><item><title>Profits over patients in hospice and end-of-life care</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/profits-over-patients-in-hospice-and-end-of-life-care/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/profits-over-patients-in-hospice-and-end-of-life-care/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I have had a lot of cases involving end-of-life and hospice care. While for most patients and families, this type of care is compassionate, helpful, and appreciated. In other instances, healthcare providers suggest hospice care for selfish reasons.
Frisco, Texas hospice debacle
In May 2018, a hospice executive in Frisco, Texas admitted to her role in overdosing patients to &amp;ldquo;hasten their deaths.&amp;rdquo; According to court documents, an operations director for Novus Health Services, Inc.</description></item><item><title>Baylor Scott &amp; White Medical Center Grapevine medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-scott-white-medical-center-grapevine-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-scott-white-medical-center-grapevine-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I handle cases throughout the State of Texas, including hospitals located in Grapevine, which is largely within Tarrant County, Texas.
Baylor Scott &amp;amp; White Medical Center Grapevine is located at 1650 W College St., Grapevine, Texas 76051. This 302-bed hospital offers medical services for heart and vascular, women and children (including birthing, labor, and delivery services), neurosciences (including neurosurgery), stroke, orthopedics, spine, diagnostic imaging, intensive care (ICU), neonatal intensive care (NICU), and emergency care (ER).</description></item><item><title>Methodist Dallas Medical Center medical malpractice lawyer/attorney</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/methodist-dallas-medical-center-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/methodist-dallas-medical-center-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I represent patients and family members in medical malpractice and wrongful death lawsuits in the Houston area, as well as all over the State of Texas.
Methodist Dallas Medical Center Methodist Dallas Medical Center is located at 1441 N. Beckley Avenue, Dallas, TX 75203. The hospital is part of the nonprofit Methodist Health System, which has multiple locations throughout the Dallas/Fort Worth Metroplex area.</description></item><item><title>Dallas Medical Center medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-medical-center-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-medical-center-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>Although my law office is in Houston, Texas, I handle medical malpractice cases all over Texas, including the Dallas area.
One of the hospitals in the Dallas area is Dallas Medical Center, located at 7 Medical Parkway, Dallas, TX 75234. Located in the Farmers Branch part of the city, the 155-bed hospital offers an emergency room, a complete laboratory, digital x-ray machines, a CT scanner, an MRI machine, ultrasound equipment, a heart catheterization lab, and operating room suites.</description></item><item><title>Mammogram interpretations botched at Arlington, Texas hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/mammogram-interpretations-botched-at-arlington-texas-hospital/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/mammogram-interpretations-botched-at-arlington-texas-hospital/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I have handled cases involving patients who suffered serious injury or death as a result of cancer misdiagnosis.
One of the most popular cancer-screening tests is the mammogram. Mammograms are specialized x-rays of the breasts that, when done properly, allow early detection of cancer-related abnormalities.
American Cancer Society guidelines for the early detection of cancer recommend that women ages 40-44 should have the choice to start annual breast cancer screening with mammograms.</description></item></channel></rss>