<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>settlement on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/settlement/</link><description>Recent content in settlement on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/settlement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jury awards $18 million verdict against nurse practitioner in breast cancer misdiagnosis case</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/jury-awards-18-million-verdict-against-nurse-practitioner-in-breast-cancer-misdiagnosis-case/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/jury-awards-18-million-verdict-against-nurse-practitioner-in-breast-cancer-misdiagnosis-case/</guid><description>Cancer is a dreaded diagnosis that shocks families and wrecks lives. It&amp;rsquo;s even worse when they find out there was a missed opportunity to diagnose and treat it.
In 2022, a jury entered a verdict for over $18 million in favor of Kerri Downes, a woman in her 20s who found a lump on her breast that was about the size of a grape. Kerri sought treatment from Eileen Carpenter, a nurse practitioner (NP).</description></item><item><title>Dallas $10+ million verdict shows that Texas tort reform didn't make all emergency room cases impossible</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-10-million-verdict-shows-that-texas-tort-reform-didnt-make-all-emergency-room-cases-impossible/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-10-million-verdict-shows-that-texas-tort-reform-didnt-make-all-emergency-room-cases-impossible/</guid><description>In Texas there&amp;rsquo;s a prevailing sentiment that hospital emergency room (ER) medical malpractice cases are simply unwinnable. It&amp;rsquo;s not only the public that feels that way&amp;mdash;I hear the same thing from many lawyers. That&amp;rsquo;s why many injured patients have a problem finding representation.
The reason for this involves a tort reform law that was enacted in Texas back in 2003. It creates a higher standard of proof for hospital emergency room cases called willful and wanton negligence.</description></item><item><title>Texan rejected by lawyers after poor ER care, we took his case and got him a $1+ million settlement</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texan-rejected-by-lawyers-after-poor-er-care-we-took-his-case-and-got-him-a-1-million-settlement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texan-rejected-by-lawyers-after-poor-er-care-we-took-his-case-and-got-him-a-1-million-settlement/</guid><description>A Texas resident contacted our law firm about his severe and disabling injuries after he wasn&amp;rsquo;t properly worked up, diagnosed, and treated in a hospital emergency room for the worst headache of his life. He was sent home with painkillers but actually was in the process of having a stroke.
Even though his injuries were profound and permanent, he&amp;rsquo;d been turned down by other law firms. When he called us, we took his case and got him a settlement of over $1,000,000.</description></item><item><title>Jury awards $8 million verdict against Texas Health Harris Methodist Hospital Southwest Fort Worth and anesthesiologist in brain damage case</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/jury-awards-8-million-verdict-against-texas-health-harris-methodist-hospital-southwest-fort-worth-and-anesthesiologist-in-brain-damage-case/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/jury-awards-8-million-verdict-against-texas-health-harris-methodist-hospital-southwest-fort-worth-and-anesthesiologist-in-brain-damage-case/</guid><description>A Tarrant County, Texas jury awarded a substantial verdict of over $8 million in an anesthesia medical malpractice case. According to the lawsuit petition and evidence introduced by the plaintiff, a woman named Angela Davis sustained serious, irreversible brain damage and other significant injuries from a medication error when she received anesthesia.
Her hospital-acquired injury left her unable to communicate in any way other than blinking and grunting. Now she can&amp;rsquo;t feed herself and requires round-the-clock care.</description></item><item><title>Painter Law Firm wins medical malpractice settlement of $3,925,000</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-wins-medical-malpractice-settlement-of-3925000/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-wins-medical-malpractice-settlement-of-3925000/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm attorney Robert Painter recently settled a Houston medical malpractice lawsuit for $3,925,000. We cannot identify the defendants because of a confidentiality agreement.
We represented a teenager who sustained a permanent, severely-disabling brain injury at a hospital after she developed hyponatremia while in the hospital.
Hyponatremia is a condition where a person develops a low serum sodium level. It is fairly common among runners who get dehydrated. In a hospital setting, it can be life-threatening.</description></item></channel></rss>