<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>corpus christi on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/corpus-christi/</link><description>Recent content in corpus christi on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/corpus-christi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Corpus Christi Medical Malpractice Lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/areas-we-serve/corpus-christi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/areas-we-serve/corpus-christi/</guid><description>Accidents happen, and sometimes they result in serious injuries or damages. In Corpus Christi, Texas, if you or a loved one has suffered harm due to medical malpractice, it&amp;#39;s crucial to seek legal assistance from a local attorney specializing in medical malpractice cases. The process of gathering evidence and dealing with legal complexities can be overwhelming, but with the right guidance, you can pursue justice and compensation for the harm you&amp;#39;ve experienced.</description></item><item><title>Compartment syndrome symptoms and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/compartment-syndrome-symptoms-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/compartment-syndrome-symptoms-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I handle cases in Harris County, as well as throughout the State of Texas.
A new client recently contacted Painter Law Firm regarding her teenage son who broke his lower leg (fibula) while playing football.
He went to a Corpus Christi, Texas hospital, where he was admitted and an orthopedic surgery was scheduled. The young man remained in the hospital for around four days after surgery.</description></item><item><title>HCA is purchasing another Houston area hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/hca-is-purchasing-another-houston-area-hospital/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/hca-is-purchasing-another-houston-area-hospital/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas attorney focusing on medical malpractice lawsuits, I like to keep abreast of hospital ownership changes.
One of the most dramatic changes in the Houston area hospital landscape in recent years is how many hospitals are being purchased by Hospital Corporation of America (HCA). HCA is a huge chain of hospitals based in Nashville, Tennessee.
To understand the wide reach of HCA&amp;rsquo;s hospital ownership and operation, consider these statistics.</description></item><item><title>The Corpus Christi Medical Center medical malpractice lawyer/attorney</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-corpus-christi-medical-center-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-corpus-christi-medical-center-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</guid><description>While I am a medical malpractice attorney based in Houston, Texas, I handle medical negligence and wrongful death cases throughout the State of Texas, including the Corpus Christi area.
The Corpus Christi Medical Center is one of the major hospital groups in the area, with four hospitals in Corpus Christi. All four of the hospitals are affiliated with the mega-chain hospital system HCA, which is out of Nashville, Tennessee.
The Corpus Christi Medical Center Bay Area is located at 7101 S.</description></item><item><title>Christus Spohn Hospital Corpus Christi—Shoreline medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/christus-spohn-hospital-corpus-christi%C3%A2shoreline-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/christus-spohn-hospital-corpus-christi%C3%A2shoreline-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm is based in Houston, Texas, and handles medical malpractice and wrongful death claims throughout the Houston area and the State of Texas, including Corpus Christi.
Christus Spohn Hospital Corpus Christi&amp;mdash;Shoreline, located at 600 Elizabeth Street, Corpus Christi, TX 78404, is part of the large nonprofit Christus hospital chain. This hospital advertises itself as the largest and foremost acute-care Medical Center in South Texas. It offers surgical services including back, spine, orthopedic, bone, joint, neurosurgery, robotic, cardiac/heart, colorectal, gynecological, thoracic, and urological.</description></item></channel></rss>