<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>baylor scott white on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/baylor-scott-white/</link><description>Recent content in baylor scott white on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/baylor-scott-white/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unveiling White Rock Hospital's 1-Star Medicare Rating</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/white-rock-hospital-1-star-rating/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/white-rock-hospital-1-star-rating/</guid><description>The Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) a federal agency, recently named Baylor Scott &amp;amp; White Medical Center-White Rock, in Dallas, as one of the worst performing hospitals in America.&amp;nbsp;
The dubious 1-star ranking is based on 46 hospital quality measures that CMS uses to compare hospitals nationwide.
Only 248 hospitals nationwide received Medicare&amp;#39;s 1-star designation. This Dallas hospital was one of only seven hospitals in Texas to be named to Medicare&amp;#39;s 1-star list.</description></item><item><title>Baylor Scott &amp; White Medical Center Plano (formerly known as Baylor Regional Medical Center at Plano) medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-scott-white-medical-center-plano-formerly-known-as-baylor-regional-medical-center-at-plano-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-scott-white-medical-center-plano-formerly-known-as-baylor-regional-medical-center-at-plano-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I handle medical negligence cases throughout the State of Texas, including those involving care hospitals and Plano.
One of the major facilities and Plano is Baylor Scott &amp;amp; White Medical Center&amp;mdash;Plano (formerly known as Baylor Regional Medical Center at Plano), which is located at 4700 Alliance Boulevard, Plano, TX 75093, in Collin County. This hospital has 160 beds.
Baylor Scott &amp;amp; White Medical Center&amp;mdash;Plano offers specialty services including allergy and immunology, anesthesiology, asthma care, back and spine care, behavioral and psychological health, breast imaging, cancer care, cosmetic and plastic surgery, critical and intensive care (ICU), dentistry and oral surgery, dermatology, diabetes, digestive diseases, ear, nose, and throat, emergency room, endocrinology, eye care, footcare, heart/cardiac/vascular, hematology, diagnostic imaging and radiology, infectious diseases, inpatient medicine and hospitalists, kidney disease, liver disease, lung care/pulmonary, men&amp;rsquo;s health, neurosurgery, neurology, occupational and environmental medicine, orthopedic surgery, pharmacy, primary care, rehabilitation and physical therapy, rheumatology, scoliosis care, sports medicine, supportive and palliative care, surgery services, urology, weight-loss surgery, wellness and fitness, women&amp;rsquo;s health, and wound care.</description></item><item><title>Baylor Scott &amp; White Hospital Brenham medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-scott-white-hospital-brenham-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-scott-white-hospital-brenham-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I handle cases involving medical and healthcare mistakes throughout the State of Texas, including the Brenham area.
Baylor Scott &amp;amp; White Hospital Brenham is located at 700 Medical Pkwy, Brenham, TX 7783. It is a 60-bed acute care hospital that offers healthcare to patients in Washington, Austin, Burleson, Colorado, Fayette, Grimes, Lee and Waller counties.
The hospital offers services in areas including breast imaging, oral surgery, diabetes care, ear, nose and throat (ENT), optometry/ophthalmology, foot care and podiatry, cardiac/heart/vascular, diagnostic imaging and radiology, men&amp;rsquo;s health, orthopedic surgery, pain management, pediatrics, primary care, sports medicine, urology, and women&amp;rsquo;s health.</description></item><item><title>Baylor Scott &amp; White Medical Center Grapevine medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-scott-white-medical-center-grapevine-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-scott-white-medical-center-grapevine-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I handle cases throughout the State of Texas, including hospitals located in Grapevine, which is largely within Tarrant County, Texas.
Baylor Scott &amp;amp; White Medical Center Grapevine is located at 1650 W College St., Grapevine, Texas 76051. This 302-bed hospital offers medical services for heart and vascular, women and children (including birthing, labor, and delivery services), neurosciences (including neurosurgery), stroke, orthopedics, spine, diagnostic imaging, intensive care (ICU), neonatal intensive care (NICU), and emergency care (ER).</description></item><item><title>Baylor Scott &amp; White Medical Center—Hillcrest Waco medical malpractice lawyer/attorney</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-scott-white-medical-center%C3%A2hillcrest-waco-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-scott-white-medical-center%C3%A2hillcrest-waco-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</guid><description>As a Texas medical malpractice lawyer based in Houston, I handle medical negligence and wrongful death cases all over the state. Many clients from all over Texas call our law firm because their hometown lawyers are nervous about tackling prominent local hospitals or doctors.
Even in this era of pro-doctor, pro-hospital tort reform, I continue to focus my practice on medical malpractice cases. And, as my track record shows, I am not intimidated to take even the largest healthcare providers in Texas to court.</description></item></channel></rss>