<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cancer on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/cancer/</link><description>Recent content in cancer on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/cancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Misdiagnosed Breast Cancer and Medical Malpractice: What You Need to Know</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/misdiagnosed-breast-cancer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/misdiagnosed-breast-cancer/</guid><description>Breast cancer is one of the most common cancers affecting women. Early detection is a critical factor to improve outcomes and survival rates.
The cornerstone of preventive healthcare is regular breast cancer screening, primarily through mammograms. When doctors, nurse practitioners, and physician assistants don’t follow established standards of care, such as notifying patients about dense breast tissue or offering supplemental screening, the consequences can be devastating.
This article explores the importance of breast cancer screening, the role of dense breast tissue in detection, and how medical malpractice can arise when providers deviate from the standard of care, potentially delaying a breast cancer diagnosis.</description></item><item><title>Jury awards $18 million verdict against nurse practitioner in breast cancer misdiagnosis case</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/jury-awards-18-million-verdict-against-nurse-practitioner-in-breast-cancer-misdiagnosis-case/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/jury-awards-18-million-verdict-against-nurse-practitioner-in-breast-cancer-misdiagnosis-case/</guid><description>Cancer is a dreaded diagnosis that shocks families and wrecks lives. It&amp;rsquo;s even worse when they find out there was a missed opportunity to diagnose and treat it.
In 2022, a jury entered a verdict for over $18 million in favor of Kerri Downes, a woman in her 20s who found a lump on her breast that was about the size of a grape. Kerri sought treatment from Eileen Carpenter, a nurse practitioner (NP).</description></item><item><title>Oral cancer misdiagnosis and dental malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/oral-cancer-misdiagnosis-and-dental-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/oral-cancer-misdiagnosis-and-dental-malpractice/</guid><description>June is Oral Health Month. This brings to mind one of the important functions of regular dental visits, oral cancer screening.
The standard of care requires dentists to perform a complete examination of the mouth and tongue to look for signs of oral cancer. Otolaryngologists (ear, nose, and throat/ENT physicians) may also perform this type of exam when consulted.
According to the American Cancer Society, oral cancer is most common in the tongue, tonsils, throat (oropharynx), floor of the mouth, and other parts of the mouth.</description></item><item><title>Houston appellate court: Ophthalmologist qualified to diagnose ganglioglioma tumor</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-appellate-court-ophthalmologist-qualified-to-diagnose-ganglioglioma-tumor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-appellate-court-ophthalmologist-qualified-to-diagnose-ganglioglioma-tumor/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s probably not a more dreaded word to hear a doctor say than &amp;ldquo;cancer.&amp;rdquo; When it is uttered about a child, though, it&amp;rsquo;s even more heart wrenching.
This was the topic addressed in an opinion entered today by Houston&amp;rsquo;s 14th Court of Appeals, in a case styled Charlise Gunderson, M.D. and Coastal Eye Associates, P.L.L.C. v. Wade, No. 14-20-00795-CV. You can read the opinion here.
In that case, a pediatrician noticed that the seven-year-old patient&amp;rsquo;s left eye was looking outward.</description></item><item><title>Lawsuit: Infant dies after nurse practitioner fails to tell family about spot that's suspicious for cancer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-infant-dies-after-nurse-practitioner-fails-to-tell-family-about-spot-thats-suspicious-for-cancer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-infant-dies-after-nurse-practitioner-fails-to-tell-family-about-spot-thats-suspicious-for-cancer/</guid><description>A wrongful death medical malpractice lawsuit recently filed in Maryland illustrates the life-and-death dangers of poor health care communication.
The case arises from the death of a two-year-old little girl.
She was born at the prestigious Johns Hopkins Hospital and then admitted to the hospital&amp;rsquo;s neonatal intensive care unit (NICU).
A nurse practitioner working in the NICU became aware of ultrasound findings of a cyst-like mass on the baby&amp;rsquo;s right adrenal gland.</description></item><item><title>What you should know about surgical and medical oncology cancer malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-surgical-and-medical-oncology-cancer-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-surgical-and-medical-oncology-cancer-malpractice/</guid><description>Like so many other types of medical malpractice matters, the situations faced by cancer malpractice victims are tragic. Sometimes forms of cancer could be treated and cured when found early. A delay in diagnosis and proper treatment can lead to a long, painful course of surgical, radiation, and chemotherapy treatment or even worse, and untimely death.
Oncologists are physicians with specialized training in handling cancer patients. Medical oncologists treat cancer with chemotherapy and other medications, while surgical oncologists perform surgical procedures to resect or remove cancerous tumors.</description></item><item><title>Ovarian cancer awareness, early diagnosis, and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/ovarian-cancer-awareness-early-diagnosis-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/ovarian-cancer-awareness-early-diagnosis-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>Ovarian cancer is a somewhat rare, dreaded form of cancer that affects the female reproductive system. It often begins in the ovaries&amp;mdash;the organs that produce eggs.
Some healthcare providers consider ovarian cancer notorious because they think that there are no symptoms whatsoever in the early stages. In an interesting opinion piece in the&amp;nbsp;Houston Business Journal, Runsi Sen, an advocate for ovarian cancer awareness at Houston-based Ovarcome, pushed back on this belief, contending that, &amp;ldquo;We need to remember that the symptoms are persistent and not silent.</description></item><item><title>Three common types of cancer surgery medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-common-types-of-cancer-surgery-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-common-types-of-cancer-surgery-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>The first line of treatment for many forms of cancer is surgical resection. This involves a surgeon physically removing the visible tumor plus sufficient margins of healthy-appearing tissue around the tumor to remove cancer cells that aren&amp;rsquo;t visible to the naked eye.
This requires a careful balance. Surgeons and their patients don&amp;rsquo;t want to remove too much tissue&amp;mdash;sometimes causing unsightly scars&amp;mdash;but want to remove enough tissue to get all the cancer.</description></item><item><title>New melanoma surgery guidelines may help reduce medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-melanoma-surgery-guidelines-may-help-reduce-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-melanoma-surgery-guidelines-may-help-reduce-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>Melanoma is an aggressive form of skin cancer that grows in width and depth. As a whole, skin cancer is the most common type of cancer, and melanoma makes up about 1% of skin cancer diagnoses.
Cancer experts believe that exposure to the sun&amp;rsquo;s ultraviolet rays leads to most cases of skin cancer. Any blistering sunburn increases a person&amp;rsquo;s risk of developing skin cancer or melanoma. The best treatment is prevention.</description></item><item><title>Colorectal cancer awareness and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/colorectal-cancer-awareness-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/colorectal-cancer-awareness-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>March is Colorectal Cancer Awareness Month, a time set aside to raise awareness of a group of different cancers affecting the colorectal tract. Lumped together, colorectal cancer is the third most common type of cancer in the world.
In adults, the colorectal tract is nearly five feet in length. It has lots of segments, including the ascending, transverse, descending, and sigmoid colon. These parts occupy a lot of space in the abdominal cavity on both sides.</description></item><item><title>Study: Stomach cancer rate is on the rise and affecting younger people</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/study-stomach-cancer-rate-is-on-the-rise-and-affecting-younger-people/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/study-stomach-cancer-rate-is-on-the-rise-and-affecting-younger-people/</guid><description>One of the many frustrating things about cancer is that there are so many types of it. This fact makes it tough for researchers to find &amp;ldquo;a cure&amp;rdquo; for cancer, because each type of cancer works differently and requires a different treatment.
Some cancers are random about what age of person they plague, while others are thought to target older people. This conventional medical wisdom is evolving, though.
Take stomach cancer (gastric cancer), which is a type of cancer that begins in the inner lining of the stomach and grows into a tumor.</description></item><item><title>The three most common types of misdiagnosis</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-three-most-common-types-of-misdiagnosis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-three-most-common-types-of-misdiagnosis/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating to go to the doctor, urgent care, emergency room, or hospital with concerning symptoms only to be sent home after being told that nothing&amp;rsquo;s wrong. After all, you seek professional medical help when you know something&amp;rsquo;s wrong!
As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I&amp;rsquo;ve handled countless cases where this happened to my clients. That&amp;rsquo;s why I wasn&amp;rsquo;t surprised to read a recent peer-reviewed medical study that concluded that an astounding 40,000 to 80,000 patients die every year in the United States because of misdiagnosis in a hospital.</description></item><item><title>Cancer surgery is successful when there are clean margins, but when the surgeon stops short it can spell trouble</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/cancer-surgery-is-successful-when-there-are-clean-margins-but-when-the-surgeon-stops-short-it-can-spell-trouble/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/cancer-surgery-is-successful-when-there-are-clean-margins-but-when-the-surgeon-stops-short-it-can-spell-trouble/</guid><description>I attended an interesting deposition today in a pending medical malpractice wrongful death case. The witness was a surgeon who is serving as an expert witness for our client, the plaintiff. The defense attorney repeatedly used the term &amp;ldquo;invisible cancer&amp;rdquo; while questioning the expert.
The case involves the tragic death of a young mother from colon cancer. She got diagnosed before the cancer spread (metastasized). That means that, for this type of cancer, surgery and chemotherapy offered her an excellent outlook and normal life expectancy.</description></item><item><title>What you should know about the new colorectal cancer screening recommendations</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-the-new-colorectal-cancer-screening-recommendations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-the-new-colorectal-cancer-screening-recommendations/</guid><description>In November 2019, the American College of Physicians released a new guidance statement that recommends screening of people with an average risk for colorectal cancer aged 50&amp;ndash;75.
Of all cancer types, colorectal cancer ranks second in cancer-related deaths in the United States. Although it&amp;rsquo;s possible that a person of any age&amp;mdash;whether a teenager or someone in their 20s, 30s, or 40s&amp;mdash;can develop colorectal cancer, its risk is known to be more age-related.</description></item><item><title>Radiologist and doctors didn't inform patient about suspicious bladder mass, leading to extensive cancer, $8+ million jury verdict</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/radiologist-and-doctors-didnt-inform-patient-about-suspicious-bladder-mass-leading-to-extensive-cancer-8-million-jury-verdict/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/radiologist-and-doctors-didnt-inform-patient-about-suspicious-bladder-mass-leading-to-extensive-cancer-8-million-jury-verdict/</guid><description>A Pennsylvania jury recently awarded a couple over $8 million in a medical malpractice case involving botched communication of the results of a CT scan. The jury found that the lack of communication led to development of extensive bladder cancer, which could have been avoided if the physicians involved had informed the patient about it.
It all started when the patient (the husband) went to a hospital emergency room (ER) because of right-sided flank and abdominal pain and urinary problems.</description></item><item><title>What you should know about mammograms and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-mammograms-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-mammograms-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>In March 2019, the U.S. Food &amp;amp; Drug Administration (FDA) announced major proposed new rules for mammogram centers that should help keep some higher-risk women safer.
What are mammograms?
Mammograms are considered the best primary tool for detecting breast cancer. To perform a mammogram, the patient is positioned standing in front of an x-ray machine and a technologist places the breast on the shelf-like platform. The technologist then uses a plastic plate to push down and compress the breast tissue while a series of low-dose x-rays are taken.</description></item><item><title>FDA cautions that robotic surgery is unproven and potentially dangerous for cancer surgeries</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/fda-cautions-that-robotic-surgery-is-unproven-and-potentially-dangerous-for-cancer-surgeries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/fda-cautions-that-robotic-surgery-is-unproven-and-potentially-dangerous-for-cancer-surgeries/</guid><description>The men and women in suits who run hospitals love to advertise when their facilities offer robotic surgery. In many cases, they suggest that robotic surgery offers greater safety and other benefits to patients when compared to conventional surgical procedures.
It&amp;rsquo;s understandable that they want to recover the significant investment required to purchase robotic surgical equipment. Yet, a growing body of research shows that claims about the superiority of robotic surgery aren&amp;rsquo;t backed up by any evidence.</description></item><item><title>Breast cancer after a negative mammogram</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/breast-cancer-after-a-negative-mammogram/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/breast-cancer-after-a-negative-mammogram/</guid><description>A mammogram is a specialized x-ray scan of the breasts used to look for breast cancer. It&amp;rsquo;s currently the best screening test to look for signs of early breast cancer.
Mammogram recommendations
The American Cancer Society&amp;rsquo;s guidelines for mammograms recommend that women:
&amp;bull; Ages 40-44 should have the option to start having mammograms for breast cancer screening.
&amp;bull; Ages 45-54 should have a mammogram every year.
&amp;bull; Ages 55 and older could switch to mammograms every other year, or could continue to have one annually.</description></item><item><title>Radiologist and urologist don't talk, man isn't treated for cancer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/radiologist-and-urologist-dont-talk-man-isnt-treated-for-cancer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/radiologist-and-urologist-dont-talk-man-isnt-treated-for-cancer/</guid><description>One of the things I see over and over as a Houston, Texas, medical malpractice attorney is how important information can fall through the cracks in medicine.
For instance, a man went to see a urologist because he was having pain between his ribs and hips (the flank area). The doctor thought it was likely a kidney stone but ordered an abdominal CT scan just to be sure.
A radiologist interpreted the CT scan and, sure enough, found the kidney stone.</description></item><item><title>Melanoma symptoms, misdiagnosis, and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/melanoma-symptoms-misdiagnosis-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/melanoma-symptoms-misdiagnosis-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>Years ago, I handled a medical malpractice wrongful death case involving a man who died from malignant melanoma that started as a tiny spot in his thumbnail.
Melanoma is the most dangerous form of skin cancer. It starts in the melanocytes, or pigment-producing cells, of the skin. Melanoma is fast-growing and can generate deadly malignant tumors. Nearly 180,000 cases of melanoma will be diagnosed in the United States and 2018 alone.</description></item><item><title>What you should know about liver cancer diagnosis, treatment, and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-liver-cancer-diagnosis-treatment-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-liver-cancer-diagnosis-treatment-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>The U.S. Centers for Disease Control (CDC) recently announced an increase in the liver cancer rate. From 2000 to 2016, the liver death (mortality) rate is increased by 43%. This is a surprising development, considering that the combined death rate for all types of cancer has declined over the past 25 years.
According to CDC data, the age-adjusted liver cancer mortality rate for adults 25 and older was 7.2 per 100,000 people in 2000, but is now 10.</description></item><item><title>Study concludes that most early-stage breast cancer patients do not need chemotherapy</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/study-concludes-that-most-early-stage-breast-cancer-patients-do-not-need-chemotherapy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/study-concludes-that-most-early-stage-breast-cancer-patients-do-not-need-chemotherapy/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas attorney focusing on medical malpractice cases, I have handled many cases where a physician missed or delayed a diagnosis of cancer. Many types of cancer are curable if they are diagnosed and treated early. A delay of months is sometimes equivalent to a death sentence.
I have handled medical negligence cases involving breast cancer, colon cancer, rectal cancer, pancreatic cancer, testicular cancer, and gallbladder cancer.
When a client hires Painter Law Firm to investigate a cancer medical malpractice case, we look at both the timeliness of the diagnosis and whether the treatment met the standard of care.</description></item><item><title>Melanoma skin cancer risk, diagnosis, treatment, and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/melanoma-skin-cancer-risk-diagnosis-treatment-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/melanoma-skin-cancer-risk-diagnosis-treatment-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>Studies show that melanoma rates are rising and that men over 50 years old are more at risk than women. Melanoma is a skin cancer that develops from the pigment-containing melanocyte cells.
According to the American Academy of Dermatology, skin cancer is the most common form of cancer in the United States. Some 9,500 patients are diagnosed with some form of skin cancer every day. In 2018, nearly 180,000 Americans will be diagnosed with melanoma.</description></item><item><title>Family practice providers do not notice missing mammogram report for two years, woman dies of breast cancer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/family-practice-providers-do-not-notice-missing-mammogram-report-for-two-years-woman-dies-of-breast-cancer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/family-practice-providers-do-not-notice-missing-mammogram-report-for-two-years-woman-dies-of-breast-cancer/</guid><description>Many clients have hired me, as a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, to investigate and handle lawsuits against their doctors for not following up on test results.
To me, this is one of the saddest types of medical malpractice because the information that would have likely led to timely, successful treatment was available, but ignored. As a patient, it makes one think what is the value of tests and laboratory or radiology workups if the results are not reviewed and acted upon.</description></item><item><title>Colon and rectal cancer screening and misdiagnosis medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/colon-and-rectal-cancer-screening-and-misdiagnosis-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/colon-and-rectal-cancer-screening-and-misdiagnosis-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>March 2018 is Colorectal Cancer Awareness Month. According to the American Cancer Society, colorectal cancer is the third most common cancer, excluding skin cancers, diagnosed in the United States. It is the second leading cause of cancer death, and is expected to cause over 50,000 deaths in 2018.
The overall lifetime risk of developing colorectal cancer is about 1 in 22 for men and 1 in 24 for women. These statistics show why the medical community has made such a colorectal cancer screening, which is resulted in a drop in the death rate from this type of cancer over the last several decades.</description></item><item><title>Bladder cancer risks, treatment, and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/bladder-cancer-risks-treatment-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/bladder-cancer-risks-treatment-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>In my practice as a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I have represented a number of clients who missed an opportunity for prompt cancer treatment because of misdiagnosis.
Bladder cancer is the sixth most common type of cancer in the United States, with around 68,000 diagnoses every year.
Signs and symptoms of bladder cancer
The classic symptom for bladder cancer is blood in the urine, which is also called hematuria. As laypeople, we can spot potential blood in the urine by an appearance that is bright red or cola colored.</description></item><item><title>Nurse practitioner misreads genetic testing results, causing unnecessary hysterectomy and double mastectomy</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/nurse-practitioner-misreads-genetic-testing-results-causing-unnecessary-hysterectomy-and-double-mastectomy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/nurse-practitioner-misreads-genetic-testing-results-causing-unnecessary-hysterectomy-and-double-mastectomy/</guid><description>A woman in her 30s had an annual exam with her obstetrician/gynecologist (OB/GYN), and discussed her family history of cancer. The doctor and patient agreed to genetic testing to assess the risk of breast and other cancers.
According to her medical malpractice lawsuit, the genetic testing for cancer risk came back negative, but the OB/GYN nurse practitioner misread them, and informed the patient that she had the MLH1 gene mutation and Lynch syndrome.</description></item><item><title>Mammogram interpretations botched at Arlington, Texas hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/mammogram-interpretations-botched-at-arlington-texas-hospital/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/mammogram-interpretations-botched-at-arlington-texas-hospital/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I have handled cases involving patients who suffered serious injury or death as a result of cancer misdiagnosis.
One of the most popular cancer-screening tests is the mammogram. Mammograms are specialized x-rays of the breasts that, when done properly, allow early detection of cancer-related abnormalities.
American Cancer Society guidelines for the early detection of cancer recommend that women ages 40-44 should have the choice to start annual breast cancer screening with mammograms.</description></item><item><title>Melanoma cancer diagnosis, treatment, and malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/melanoma-cancer-diagnosis-treatment-and-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/melanoma-cancer-diagnosis-treatment-and-malpractice/</guid><description>Recently, a number of new clients have hired Painter Law Firm to investigate medical malpractice cases regarding undiagnosed cancer. Each of these cases is tragic, involving a patient who sought treatment early, but was incorrectly told that everything was fine.
Hearing this type of story over and over again reminded me of a malignant melanoma case that I handled many years ago. In that case, a man noticed a small area of discoloration on one of his thumbs.</description></item><item><title>Colorectal cancer rates are on the rise for adults under 50</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/colorectal-cancer-rates-are-on-the-rise-for-adults-under-50/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/colorectal-cancer-rates-are-on-the-rise-for-adults-under-50/</guid><description>A recent research letter written by an epidemiologist with the American Cancer Society and published in the Journal of the American Medical Association (JAMA) provides updated information on colorectal cancer death rates.
For reasons that researchers do not yet understand, colorectal cancer death rates for adults under 55 years old have been on the rise since the 1990s.
Colorectal cancer causes more deaths among men and women than any other type of cancer except lung cancer.</description></item><item><title>Surgeon does not tell patient about pathology results, delays cancer treatment</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/surgeon-does-not-tell-patient-about-pathology-results-delays-cancer-treatment/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/surgeon-does-not-tell-patient-about-pathology-results-delays-cancer-treatment/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas attorney with a practice focused on medical malpractice, I speak with clients every day who have been injured because of poor hospital, surgical, anesthesia, nursing, and physician care.
It is always sad to meet with a new client who responsibly sought treatment early-on, but is now facing a limited life expectancy because health care providers did not take the time to follow up on information is right in front of them.</description></item><item><title>Why do healthy people get cancer?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/why-do-healthy-people-get-cancer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/why-do-healthy-people-get-cancer/</guid><description>Have you ever noticed that people who make healthy diet, exercise, and living choices still seem to get cancer more frequently than you might expect? I cannot count the number of times that I have heard that remark from family and friends.
Recent studies by a mathematician and cancer geneticist team at Johns Hopkins University help to explain why healthy people still develop cancer.
This new research suggests that a lot of generally-held beliefs about what causes cancer may be misplaced.</description></item></channel></rss>