<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>new cases on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/new-cases/</link><description>Recent content in new cases on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/new-cases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>True Results affiliated lap band surgeon Dr. Richard Wilkenfeld misdiagnoses holes in stomach &amp; infection</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/true-results-affiliated-lap-band-surgeon-dr.-richard-wilkenfeld-misdiagnoses-holes-in-stomach-infection/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/true-results-affiliated-lap-band-surgeon-dr.-richard-wilkenfeld-misdiagnoses-holes-in-stomach-infection/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm&amp;rsquo;s bariatric surgery malpractice attorneys recently filed a lawsuit against Conroe, Texas surgeon Richard Wilkenfeld, M.D. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
In October 2013, our client, a U.S. Army veteran named Jonathan, saw a True Results commercial about weight loss options, including bariatric surgery, and decided to get more information.
True Results is a trade name used by the Dallas-based American Institute of Gastric Banding, Ltd. True Results does not actually employ bariatric surgeons, but refers patients to surgeons who will use True Results facilities to do their procedures.</description></item><item><title>Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney Robert Painter files lawsuit that claims: Conroe Regional Medical Center nurses cause pressure sore, bone infection</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-files-lawsuit-that-claims-conroe-regional-medical-center-nurses-cause-pressure-sore-bone-infection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-files-lawsuit-that-claims-conroe-regional-medical-center-nurses-cause-pressure-sore-bone-infection/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm&amp;rsquo;s Texas medical malpractice lawyers recently filed a medical malpractice lawsuit on behalf of a 50-year old Montgomery man, named Raymond, against Conroe Regional Medical Center. The case is pending in the 410th District Court of Montgomery County, Texas.
Raymond is an otherwise healthy middle-aged man who works for an oil service company. He was admitted to Conroe Regional Hospital because of injuries from a motorcycle accident. During an admission of over one month, he completely recovered from those injuries, but left the hospital with a pressure sore on the heel of his left foot.</description></item><item><title>Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney Robert Painter files lawsuit that claims: Cypress OBGYN doctors fail to do Rh factor test &amp; cause newborn brain damage</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-files-lawsuit-that-claims-cypress-obgyn-doctors-fail-to-do-rh-factor-test-cause-newborn-brain-damage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-files-lawsuit-that-claims-cypress-obgyn-doctors-fail-to-do-rh-factor-test-cause-newborn-brain-damage/</guid><description>Every person is born with a blood type, which could be A, B, AB, or O. Blood type is also called positive or negative; if Rh factor is present, the blood type of called positive. For example, my blood is O negative, which means that I have O type blood without Rh factor.
Rh factor is the name of a protein on the surface of red bloods of people with Rh-positive blood.</description></item><item><title>Infections in nursing homes or rehabilitation facilities can be deadly</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/infections-in-nursing-homes-or-rehabilitation-facilities-can-be-deadly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/infections-in-nursing-homes-or-rehabilitation-facilities-can-be-deadly/</guid><description>When patients are near the end of a hospitalization for a surgery or other illness, they sometimes need some additional care before they can go home. In these situations, case managers and doctors will often transfer patients to a nursing home or skilled nursing facility, like Manor Care Willowbrook, in Houston, or a rehabilitation facility, like Reliant Rehabilitation Hospital North Houston, in Shenandoah.
Patients and their families should realize that skilled nursing and rehabilitation facilities are frequently not set up to treat serious infections or to manage patients who are on multiple strong medications.</description></item><item><title>Lawsuit: The Methodist Hospital ignores stroke symptoms and causes permanent brain injury</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-the-methodist-hospital-ignores-stroke-symptoms-and-causes-permanent-brain-injury/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-the-methodist-hospital-ignores-stroke-symptoms-and-causes-permanent-brain-injury/</guid><description>The Texas medical malpractice lawyers at Painter Law Firm filed a lawsuit against The Methodist Hospital (now called Houston Methodist Hospital), as well as an&amp;nbsp;emergency room doctor,&amp;nbsp;attending neurologist and neurology resident who worked at that facility. The case is pending the 113th District Court of Harris County, Texas, where Judge Michael Landrum is presiding.&amp;nbsp;
We filed the case on behalf of our client, Binti Lee, who was a 34-year-old African American woman in December 2012, when a medical malpractice tragedy occurred.</description></item><item><title>Lawsuit: St. Luke's Sugar Land Hospital pain killer overmedication causes patient death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-st.-lukes-sugar-land-hospital-pain-killer-overmedication-causes-patient-death/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-st.-lukes-sugar-land-hospital-pain-killer-overmedication-causes-patient-death/</guid><description>The Houston medical malpractice lawyers at Painter Law Firm filed a lawsuit, on behalf of the family of Nell Kerr, against St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Sugar Land Hospital and two doctors. The was filed in the 270th District Court of Harris County, Texas, with Judge Brent Gamble presiding.
In June 2012, Nell Kerr was an otherwise healthy 75 year old woman who saw an orthopedic surgeon, for back pain and numbness in her fingers.</description></item><item><title>Lawsuit: Botched propofol anesthesia care kills 33-year old father and teacher</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-botched-propofol-anesthesia-care-kills-33-year-old-father-and-teacher/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-botched-propofol-anesthesia-care-kills-33-year-old-father-and-teacher/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm filed a wrongful death medical malpractice lawsuit involving the tragic, avoidable death of Eli Tella. Mr. Tella, age 33, died at Knapp Medical Center, in Weslaco, Texas.
In February 2013, Mr. Tella went to the emergency room at Knapp Medical Center, with stomach pain and nausea. Prior to this illness, he had had a pretty clean bill of health. The emergency room doctor diagnosed Mr. Tella with pancreatitis and related conditions and admitted him to the intensive care unit.</description></item><item><title>Houston Press coverage of firm's Memorial Hermann lawsuit</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-press-coverage-of-firms-memorial-hermann-lawsuit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-press-coverage-of-firms-memorial-hermann-lawsuit/</guid><description>Harris County District Clerk records show that Memorial Hermann, a so-called nonprofit hospital system, regularly files lawsuits to collect hundreds of thousands of dollars from its uninsured patients. When Memorial Hermann sued a severely injured patient, Ignacio Alaniz, for over $400,000 in medical bills, he retained Painter Law Firm to help.
Read the thorough coverage by the Houston Press by clicking here.</description></item><item><title>Lawsuit over botched gastric surgery on 43 year old Conroe woman</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-over-botched-gastric-surgery-on-43-year-old-conroe-woman/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-over-botched-gastric-surgery-on-43-year-old-conroe-woman/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm filed a medical malpractice case in Montgomery County, Texas today on behalf of our client. The petition names as defendants Conroe Regional Medical Center, Dr. Richard Wilkenfeld, Dr. Susan Babb and Dr. John Marriott.
Our client was only 43-years old in 2010, when she was diagnosed with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease, which caused cirrhosis of the liver. Her liver doctor recommended a lap band surgery to slow down the progression of cirrhosis.</description></item><item><title>Painter Law Firm files suit for family against First Colony Health and Rehabilitation Center</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-suit-for-family-against-first-colony-health-and-rehabilitation-center/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-suit-for-family-against-first-colony-health-and-rehabilitation-center/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm filed a lawsuit in Houston, Texas against First Colony Health and Rehabilitation Center and a physician, on behalf of the family of Bernice Twardowski.
In October 2010, Mrs. Twardowski was a 73 year old lady who was involved in a car wreck. After initial treatment at Memorial Hermann Hospital, she went to First Colony Health and Rehabilitation Center for skilled nursing care and rehabilitation.
Shortly after she arrived at the facility, Mrs.</description></item><item><title>Painter Law Firm files suit for family against Heartland Health Care Center at Willowbrook and Hunaid Dollar, M.D.</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-suit-for-family-against-heartland-health-care-center-at-willowbrook-and-hunaid-dollar-m.d./</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-suit-for-family-against-heartland-health-care-center-at-willowbrook-and-hunaid-dollar-m.d./</guid><description>Painter Law Firm filed a lawsuit in Houston, Texas against Heartland Health Care Center at Willowbrook and Hunaid Dollar, M.D., on behalf of the family of Joy Robinson.
In December 2009, 63 year old Joy Robinson went to Heartland Health Care Center at Willowbrook for rehabilitation following a hospitalization at Tomball Regional Medical Center. Her goal was to return home. Mrs. Robinson&amp;rsquo;s doctor at Heartland Health Care Center at Willowbrook was Hunaid Dollar, M.</description></item><item><title>Painter Law Firm files suit for family against Memorial Hermann The Woodlands Hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-suit-for-family-against-memorial-hermann-the-woodlands-hospital/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-suit-for-family-against-memorial-hermann-the-woodlands-hospital/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm filed a lawsuit in Houston, Texas against Memorial Hermann The Woodlands Hospital, on behalf of the family of Irene Dixon.
In March 2010, Mrs. Dixon was a 78 year old lady who tripped at church and broke her hip. An ambulance took her to Memorial Hermann The Woodlands Hospital and doctors planned for a hip surgery.
Before that happened, though, she started acting confused and had a change in mental status.</description></item><item><title>Painter Law Firm files suit for family against North Cypress Medical Center</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-suit-for-family-against-north-cypress-medical-center/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-suit-for-family-against-north-cypress-medical-center/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm filed a lawsuit in Houston, Texas against North Cypress Medical Center, on behalf of the family of Mildred Clark.
In February 2010, 93 year old Mildred Clark went from her home to the emergency room of North Cypress Medical Center because she had experienced stomach bug symptoms for a few days and could not keep down food or water.
On the first night of her admission to the hospital, Mrs.</description></item></channel></rss>