<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>baylor chi st. lukes on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/baylor-chi-st.-lukes/</link><description>Recent content in baylor chi st. lukes on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/baylor-chi-st.-lukes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Houston Methodist charges almost double for a surgery than the cost at a nearby academic hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-charges-almost-double-for-a-surgery-than-the-cost-at-a-nearby-academic-hospital/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-charges-almost-double-for-a-surgery-than-the-cost-at-a-nearby-academic-hospital/</guid><description>According to the focus group research, the number one reason that people select a hospital is location. Not quality. Not whether you&amp;rsquo;ll be seen by a physician as opposed to a physician assistant (PA) or nurse practitioner (NP). Not even cost. Location.
I believe some of this phenomenon is because of the lack of information available to consumers. Most hospitals advertise that they offer top-notch care. Texas law allows hospitals to conceal the credentials and performance reviews of their physicians.</description></item><item><title>Medicare penalizes CHI St. Luke's Health Baylor College of Medicine Medical Center over readmission rate</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medicare-penalizes-chi-st.-lukes-health-baylor-college-of-medicine-medical-center-over-readmission-rate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medicare-penalizes-chi-st.-lukes-health-baylor-college-of-medicine-medical-center-over-readmission-rate/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s in a name?
CHI St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Health Baylor College of Medicine Medical Center (St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Baylor) is quite a mouthful. It&amp;rsquo;s a joint venture of two of the most storied and well-known names in Houston&amp;rsquo;s Texas Medical Center, St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Hospital and Baylor College of Medicine.
It&amp;#39;s an academic or teaching hospital where St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s provides the nursing, therapy, technical, and administrative employees. Baylor completes the health care team by providing the physician medical staff, including attending physicians and professors, who are fully trained, and residents and fellows, who are doctors still completing their clinical training.</description></item><item><title>Federal lawsuit: Baylor St. Luke's Medical Center &amp; Baylor College of Medicine doctors leave towel inside patient after surgery</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/federal-lawsuit-baylor-st.-lukes-medical-center-baylor-college-of-medicine-doctors-leave-towel-inside-patient-after-surgery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/federal-lawsuit-baylor-st.-lukes-medical-center-baylor-college-of-medicine-doctors-leave-towel-inside-patient-after-surgery/</guid><description>Today, we filed a federal lawsuit in the U.S. District Court for the Southern District of Texas, Houston Division on behalf of a Colorado client who had a whole surgical towel left inside him after a June 14, 2018 surgery at Baylor St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Medical Center, in Houston&amp;rsquo;s Texas Medical Center.
The lawsuit names as defendants both the hospital and Baylor College of Medicine, who employed the principal surgeon and a total of six physicians involved in the procedure.</description></item><item><title>Medicare identifies ongoing quality of care concerns at CHI St. Luke's Health Baylor St. Luke's Medical Center</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medicare-identifies-ongoing-quality-of-care-concerns-at-chi-st.-lukes-health-baylor-st.-lukes-medical-center/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medicare-identifies-ongoing-quality-of-care-concerns-at-chi-st.-lukes-health-baylor-st.-lukes-medical-center/</guid><description>Up until a few years ago, it was unusual to hear a patient or family member complain about care provided at CHI St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Health Baylor St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Medical Center. My, how times have changed. Many people think this fabled hospital where famous surgeons once practiced has lost its way.
As an experienced Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I&amp;rsquo;ve handled many lawsuits and cases involving care provided at the 850-bed St.</description></item><item><title>Is CHI St. Luke's Heath Baylor College of Medicine Medical Center learning from its health care mistakes?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/is-chi-st.-lukes-heath-baylor-college-of-medicine-medical-center-learning-from-its-health-care-mistakes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/is-chi-st.-lukes-heath-baylor-college-of-medicine-medical-center-learning-from-its-health-care-mistakes/</guid><description>CHI St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Heath Baylor College of Medicine Medical Center, located at 6720 Bertner Avenue, Houston, TX 77030, is one of the major academic hospitals in the Texas Medical Center.
Since 2014, the hospital has been jointly owned by Baylor College of Medicine and CHI St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Health.
It offers comprehensive services including bariatric surgery, cardiovascular care and surgery, ear nose and throat (ENT) care, emergency medicine, endocrinology, ophthalmology, gastroenterology, kidney/nephrology care, liver care, neurology and neurosurgery, oncology, orthopedics and sports medicine, plastic and reconstructive surgery, rehabilitation, pulmonology care, rheumatology care, spine surgery and care, general surgical services, urology, and wound care.</description></item><item><title>Medicare issues violation to CHI St. Luke's Health The Woodlands Hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medicare-issues-violation-to-chi-st.-lukes-health-the-woodlands-hospital/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medicare-issues-violation-to-chi-st.-lukes-health-the-woodlands-hospital/</guid><description>The Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services recently issued a violation citation to CHI St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Health&amp;mdash;The Woodlands Hospital. This 231-bed hospital is located in Montgomery County, at 17200 St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Way, The Woodlands, TX 77384. The Medicare health inspector visited CHI St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Health&amp;mdash;The Woodlands Hospital on March 20, 2018, and cited the hospital for a violation of patient rights to participate in care planning.
As a former hospital administrator, I was interested to learn that the hospital had its own internal policy on pain management, which the nursing staff didn&amp;rsquo;t follow in this case.</description></item><item><title>Baylor St. Luke's Medical Center medical malpractice lawyer/attorney</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-st.-lukes-medical-center-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-st.-lukes-medical-center-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I spend a significant amount of time investigating health care provided by hospitals, doctors, surgeons, anesthesiologists, and nurses.
One of the earliest steps in our investigation of potential defendants in medical negligence lawsuits is to look into a hospital&amp;rsquo;s past history of compliance or noncompliance with government regulations. One of the sources for quality of care information is the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services.</description></item><item><title>Have you been injured by medical malpractice at CHI St Luke's Health Baylor College of Medicine Medical Center?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/have-you-been-injured-by-medical-malpractice-at-chi-st-lukes-health-baylor-college-of-medicine-medical-center/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/have-you-been-injured-by-medical-malpractice-at-chi-st-lukes-health-baylor-college-of-medicine-medical-center/</guid><description>While our office is located in Houston, Painter Law Firm&amp;rsquo;s medical malpractice lawyers represent clients who have potential cases against hospitals all over Harris County. This includes hospitals in Houston, like CHI&amp;nbsp;St Luke&amp;rsquo;s Health Baylor College of Medicine Medical Center.
The types of cases we handle include surgical mistakes, anesthesia errors, infections, sepsis, birth injuries, falls, stroke, nerve damage, birth injury, childbirth complications, brain damage, diagnosis mistakes, medical device failures, medication and drug errors, wrongful death, and many others.</description></item></channel></rss>