<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>primary care on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/primary-care/</link><description>Recent content in primary care on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/primary-care/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The educational role of home health and wound care nurses</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-educational-role-of-home-health-and-wound-care-nurses/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-educational-role-of-home-health-and-wound-care-nurses/</guid><description>Most everyone realizes that healthcare is now multidisciplinary. The lines are sometimes blurry between roles and tasks of physicians versus registered nurses, nurse practitioners, and physician assistants.
In some settings, such as home health nursing, responsibilities may even be shared between a nurse and the patient or an unlicensed caregiver. We are currently working on a case where this is an issue.
Our client received home health nursing to assist with a surgical wound following an open cholecystectomy, which is a surgery to remove an inflamed and infected gallbladder.</description></item><item><title>Houston court appeals addresses legally sufficient evidence in suicide medical malpractice case</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-court-appeals-addresses-legally-sufficient-evidence-in-suicide-medical-malpractice-case/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-court-appeals-addresses-legally-sufficient-evidence-in-suicide-medical-malpractice-case/</guid><description>Houston&amp;rsquo;s 14th Court of Appeals recently entered an opinion in a medical malpractice wrongful death case against a group of healthcare providers at a Texas pediatric clinic. Sadly, the case involved the suicide after a minor. The case is styled Pediatrics Cool Care v. Thompson, No. 14-19-00031-CV, 14th Court of Appeals. You can read the opinion here.
As with many full-service pediatric clinics, at Pediatrics Cool Care, a pediatrician oversaw care provided at the clinic by nurse practitioners, physician assistants, and medical assistant.</description></item><item><title>Case shows it's always important to investigate chest pain</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/case-shows-its-always-important-to-investigate-chest-pain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/case-shows-its-always-important-to-investigate-chest-pain/</guid><description>According to the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), over 600,000 Americans die from heart disease each year, accounting for about 25% of all deaths. If the leading cause of death for men, women, people most racial and ethnic groups in America.
The classic signs and symptoms of heart attack include:
&amp;bull; Chest pain or discomfort. For most people, heart attacks involve discomfort in the center or left side of the chest that lasts more than a few minutes with the gauze waiting and returned.</description></item><item><title>Hyperparathyroid disease signs, symptoms, and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/hyperparathyroid-disease-signs-symptoms-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/hyperparathyroid-disease-signs-symptoms-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>The parathyroid glands don&amp;rsquo;t get a lot of attention. Most people are more familiar with their well-known neighbor, the thyroid gland. The parathyroid and thyroid glands, though, have different independent roles that are equally important.
The grain-of-rice-sized parathyroid glands secret an eponymous substance called parathyroid hormone (PTH). When there&amp;rsquo;s a problem with the parathyroid gland that causes PTH levels to get off kilter, it can lead to a cascade of complex problems.</description></item><item><title>What can the trial court consider at a Chapter 74 preliminary expert report hearing in a Texas medical malpractice case?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-can-the-trial-court-consider-at-a-chapter-74-preliminary-expert-report-hearing-in-a-texas-medical-malpractice-case/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-can-the-trial-court-consider-at-a-chapter-74-preliminary-expert-report-hearing-in-a-texas-medical-malpractice-case/</guid><description>Texas law requires medical malpractice plaintiffs to produce one or more medical expert reports within 120 days of each defendant filing an answer and a lawsuit. The standards for these reports are demanding, requiring separate statements of the applicable standard of care (what should have been done), how the standard of care was violated (what wasn&amp;rsquo;t done correctly), and how those medical mistakes proximately caused harm to the plaintiff.
How do defendants respond to the preliminary expert reports, and what are the potential consequences?</description></item><item><title>When does the willful and wanton standard of proof apply in Texas ER medical malpractice cases?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/when-does-the-willful-and-wanton-standard-of-proof-apply-in-texas-er-medical-malpractice-cases/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/when-does-the-willful-and-wanton-standard-of-proof-apply-in-texas-er-medical-malpractice-cases/</guid><description>Texas law treats medical malpractice lawsuits differently from other types of negligence cases. One of the significant differences is a heightened standard of proof in some types of claims.
Texas Civil Practice &amp;amp; Remedies Code Section 74.153 mandates a standard of proof called “willful and wanton negligence” for certain emergency medical care cases. If you’re confused by what that means, join the club. Willful conduct is inconsistent with any theory of negligence, but that discussion is for another day.</description></item><item><title>Sodium, porphyria, and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/sodium-porphyria-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/sodium-porphyria-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how the different systems of our body generally work together seamlessly. When something goes wrong with one of the systems, though, it can cause problems that aren&amp;rsquo;t immediately obvious.
That&amp;rsquo;s why it&amp;rsquo;s important to patient safety that primary care and emergency physicians follow the differential diagnosis process with every patient every time. The differential diagnosis process is taught to medical students in their first year of medical school and is repeated throughout their training.</description></item><item><title>What you should know about primary care providers &amp; medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-primary-care-providers-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-primary-care-providers-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>When I started my graduate career at the Marshall University School of Medicine, in 1992, there was a big emphasis on primary care medicine. Primary care doctors include those who practice in family medicine, pediatrics, and even office-based internal medicine. Where I grew up, in West Virginia, there was a need for more physicians in these practice areas.
Over 25 years later, the medical education community continues to encourage new doctors to pursue a career in primary care.</description></item><item><title>31-year-old teacher dies in front of students, doctor withheld critical test results</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/31-year-old-teacher-dies-in-front-of-students-doctor-withheld-critical-test-results/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/31-year-old-teacher-dies-in-front-of-students-doctor-withheld-critical-test-results/</guid><description>A school teacher in his early 30s had a heart attack in front of his classroom full of students and then died. His family contacted Painter Law Firm to investigate a medical malpractice case.
About five years before this man passed away, he had surgery to replace a faulty heart valve. He had no problems until about five months before his fatal heart attack, when he started having fainting spells.</description></item><item><title>What really matters when you call your doctor's office</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-really-matters-when-you-call-your-doctors-office/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-really-matters-when-you-call-your-doctors-office/</guid><description>Yesterday, I spent most of the day in a deposition of my client, where a key issue was when her surgeon became aware of certain complications she was experiencing.
Calling the surgeon after a procedure
This medical malpractice case is about a middle-aged woman who consulted a bariatric surgeon about a procedure. Several years earlier, she had a successful gastric bypass surgery. She had good results from that surgery for over a decade, but eventually started putting on more weight.</description></item><item><title>Opthalmologist medical malpractice: Eye doctor misdiagnoses serious eye condition</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/opthalmologist-medical-malpractice-eye-doctor-misdiagnoses-serious-eye-condition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/opthalmologist-medical-malpractice-eye-doctor-misdiagnoses-serious-eye-condition/</guid><description>Have you ever lost a contact lens? It can be annoying. What happened to a British woman, though, took this common frustration to a whole new level.
The woman, aged 42 years old, had lost a contact lens when she was a teenager. Almost two decades later, she went to see an eye doctor after she discovered a pea-sized lump on her lower left eyebrow that was causing her eyelid to droop.</description></item><item><title>Can a doctor properly diagnose and treat you without listening to what's wrong?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/can-a-doctor-properly-diagnose-and-treat-you-without-listening-to-whats-wrong/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/can-a-doctor-properly-diagnose-and-treat-you-without-listening-to-whats-wrong/</guid><description>One of the hardest things for most people to do is listen&amp;mdash;I mean really listen&amp;mdash;when another person is speaking. When psychologists train people on this important skill, they often describe it as &amp;ldquo;active listening.&amp;rdquo; I like that phrase because it emphasizes that listening is not a passive task but takes attention and work.
For physicians the challenge is no different, but the stakes are much higher. From medical school forward, doctors are trained on how to conduct a &amp;ldquo;history&amp;rdquo; when seeing patients.</description></item><item><title>DVT and pulmonary embolism diagnosis, treatment, and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dvt-and-pulmonary-embolism-diagnosis-treatment-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dvt-and-pulmonary-embolism-diagnosis-treatment-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>Venous thromboembolism (VTE), or formation of blood clots in the veins, is the top cause of death and disability in hospitalized patients. The most common site for VTE development is the deep veins of the legs, called deep vein thrombosis (DVT).
Clots are known to form in the veins in some patients who are lying down and immobilized. Surgical patients are particularly at risk because they can be in the operating room and under general anesthesia for extended periods of time.</description></item><item><title>Cardiovascular heart disease misdiagnosis and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/cardiovascular-heart-disease-misdiagnosis-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/cardiovascular-heart-disease-misdiagnosis-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I have noticed a recent trend in misdiagnosis of serious medical conditions both in primary care office settings and in emergency rooms.
In my experience, there is a patient safety problem arising from physicians overlooking or downplaying classic symptoms of serious cardiovascular conditions and instead settling on benign, incorrect diagnoses.
Risk factors for cardiovascular disease
Cardiovascular disease (also called heart disease) is a broad group of illnesses including four major diagnostic categories:</description></item><item><title>Why you should repeat your story every time you see the doctor</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/why-you-should-repeat-your-story-every-time-you-see-the-doctor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/why-you-should-repeat-your-story-every-time-you-see-the-doctor/</guid><description>Last month, my family traveled to Guatemala for Spring Break. One of the highlights of the trip was hiking Pacaya Volcano near Antigua. It is a rather steep volcano, so we took what the locals call the &amp;ldquo;taxi&amp;rdquo; on the way up&amp;mdash;each of us rode a horse. On the way back down, I decided to hike with my own two feet.
A few weeks later, I started having bad pain that I knew originated in my left Achilles tendon.</description></item><item><title>What to do when your doctor is misbehaving</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-to-do-when-your-doctor-is-misbehaving/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-to-do-when-your-doctor-is-misbehaving/</guid><description>The Texas Medical Board recently suspended the medical license of a pediatrician, Kurt Loring Pflieger, M.D., who practiced in Rockwall and Forney, because of his apparent unstable mental health status.
Practicing pediatrician in a mental health breakdown
It is always sad to see someone suffer from a mental health condition and physicians, like everyone else, are not immune from having such problems. When a doctor continues to practice medicine, with an unstable, untreated mental health illness, it can pose an immediate danger to patient safety.</description></item><item><title>Nurse practitioners: Texas law and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/nurse-practitioners-texas-law-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/nurse-practitioners-texas-law-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>Nurse practitioners are mid-level providers that are an increasingly common part of medical care, both in office practices as well as hospitals.
While many people may be most familiar with nurse practitioners providing primary care, they also participate in other specialty areas, including post-operative care for surgical patients.
Under Texas law, the Nursing Practice Act refers to nurse practitioners as Advanced Practice Registered Nurses (APRNs). While nurse practitioners are allowed to see patients independently, the Nursing Practice Act requires them to have a written collaborative practice agreement with at least one medical doctor.</description></item><item><title>Family practice providers do not notice missing mammogram report for two years, woman dies of breast cancer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/family-practice-providers-do-not-notice-missing-mammogram-report-for-two-years-woman-dies-of-breast-cancer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/family-practice-providers-do-not-notice-missing-mammogram-report-for-two-years-woman-dies-of-breast-cancer/</guid><description>Many clients have hired me, as a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, to investigate and handle lawsuits against their doctors for not following up on test results.
To me, this is one of the saddest types of medical malpractice because the information that would have likely led to timely, successful treatment was available, but ignored. As a patient, it makes one think what is the value of tests and laboratory or radiology workups if the results are not reviewed and acted upon.</description></item><item><title>Doctor, nurse practitioner ignore MRI results for two years, woman dies of cancer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/doctor-nurse-practitioner-ignore-mri-results-for-two-years-woman-dies-of-cancer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/doctor-nurse-practitioner-ignore-mri-results-for-two-years-woman-dies-of-cancer/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, many of the lawsuits that I handle for patients and family members involve a failure of communication. &amp;nbsp;This type of medical error usually occurs when there is a hand-off from one healthcare provider to another.
Think about it. &amp;nbsp;The provision of modern health care involves a lot of different players including, doctors, specialists, nurses, laboratory techs, radiologists, and pathologists. &amp;nbsp;When one healthcare provider refers an order or consultation to another provider, poor systems allow results to get lost in the shuffle.</description></item><item><title>Colon and rectal cancer screening and misdiagnosis medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/colon-and-rectal-cancer-screening-and-misdiagnosis-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/colon-and-rectal-cancer-screening-and-misdiagnosis-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>March 2018 is Colorectal Cancer Awareness Month. According to the American Cancer Society, colorectal cancer is the third most common cancer, excluding skin cancers, diagnosed in the United States. It is the second leading cause of cancer death, and is expected to cause over 50,000 deaths in 2018.
The overall lifetime risk of developing colorectal cancer is about 1 in 22 for men and 1 in 24 for women. These statistics show why the medical community has made such a colorectal cancer screening, which is resulted in a drop in the death rate from this type of cancer over the last several decades.</description></item><item><title>What to do when your doctor downplays your symptoms</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-to-do-when-your-doctor-downplays-your-symptoms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-to-do-when-your-doctor-downplays-your-symptoms/</guid><description>A new client recently called our office about poor health care he received at a primary care clinic in San Antonio.
The man went to see his primary care provider because of ear pain that radiated down into his jaw. Strangely, the physician did not examine or look into the patient&amp;rsquo;s ear but instead quickly concluded that he had arthritis.
Over the course of the next two months, the pain did not resolve so he returned to the primary care clinic on two more occasions.</description></item><item><title>Sport physical essentials and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/sport-physical-essentials-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/sport-physical-essentials-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>Most school districts and private schools require student athletes to have a physical for playing on a school sports team. Quite often, many people view the sports physical, or pre-participation screening, as a check-the-box exercise that has little importance. Sometimes schools have a rushed assembly line for sports physicals, just before the deadline.
Thinking back to when I played high school basketball, I think I understand why this frequently happens. I was like most young people, thinking that I had no physical limitation that would prevent me from engaging in sports.</description></item><item><title>New adult high blood pressure guidelines and what they mean for you</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-adult-high-blood-pressure-guidelines-and-what-they-mean-for-you/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-adult-high-blood-pressure-guidelines-and-what-they-mean-for-you/</guid><description>According to the World Health Organization, hypertension, or high blood pressure, is the number one cardiovascular risk factor, as well as the world&amp;rsquo;s greatest risk factor for death and disability.
Because of hypertension significant role in causing life-changing illnesses and death, medical researchers have invested significant time and resources into studying risk factors and treatment recommendations. These efforts resulted in new guidelines, which were released in September 2017.
For the first time since 2003, the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Clinical Practice Guidelines released new guidelines concerning high blood pressure in adults.</description></item><item><title>Nurse practitioner misreads genetic testing results, causing unnecessary hysterectomy and double mastectomy</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/nurse-practitioner-misreads-genetic-testing-results-causing-unnecessary-hysterectomy-and-double-mastectomy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/nurse-practitioner-misreads-genetic-testing-results-causing-unnecessary-hysterectomy-and-double-mastectomy/</guid><description>A woman in her 30s had an annual exam with her obstetrician/gynecologist (OB/GYN), and discussed her family history of cancer. The doctor and patient agreed to genetic testing to assess the risk of breast and other cancers.
According to her medical malpractice lawsuit, the genetic testing for cancer risk came back negative, but the OB/GYN nurse practitioner misread them, and informed the patient that she had the MLH1 gene mutation and Lynch syndrome.</description></item><item><title>Why neurological examinations are important</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/why-neurological-examinations-are-important/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/why-neurological-examinations-are-important/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, one of the quality of care issues that I most frequently encounter is the overreliance of healthcare providers on technology, rather than using their own eyes and ears to perform a clinical evaluation of patients.
In October 2017, the Journal of the American Medical Association (JAMA) published a physician&amp;rsquo;s opinion piece about the dying art of neurologic examination. Neurological examinations are frequently performed by physicians, with orders for follow-up neuro checks by the nursing staff.</description></item><item><title>What can nurse practitioners and physician assistants do in Texas?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-can-nurse-practitioners-and-physician-assistants-do-in-texas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-can-nurse-practitioners-and-physician-assistants-do-in-texas/</guid><description>Over 20 years ago, when I was a hospital administrator, I had a first-hand vantage point to the emergence of physician assistants (PA&amp;rsquo;s) and nurse practitioners (NP&amp;rsquo;s) as mid-level providers.
It is easy to understand why business-savvy hospitals started hiring PA&amp;rsquo;s and NP&amp;rsquo;s&amp;mdash;they are cheaper than physicians. In addition to their cost effectiveness, the general idea is these mid-level providers can handle common, basic illnesses, freeing up doctors to handle more complex diagnoses and conditions.</description></item><item><title>Infant spit-up medications increase bone fracture risk later in childhood</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/infant-spit-up-medications-increase-bone-fracture-risk-later-in-childhood/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/infant-spit-up-medications-increase-bone-fracture-risk-later-in-childhood/</guid><description>Around 65% of all babies have mild infant gastroesophageal reflux, which parents refer to as spitting up. This is why parents of newborns always seem to have a towel around.
Until recent years, parents would go through the feeding ritual every two hours of making and heating a bottle, feeding the baby, burping the baby, and then putting the little one back to sleep.
Now, many pediatricians are prescribing stomach-acid suppressors medications, such as proton pump inhibitors and histamine 2 receptor agonists (H2 blockers), to prevent healthy babies from spitting up at all.</description></item><item><title>Risk factors for sudden cardiac arrest</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/risk-factors-for-sudden-cardiac-arrest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/risk-factors-for-sudden-cardiac-arrest/</guid><description>Sudden cardiac arrest (also called sudden cardiac death) is the single most common cause of death in America.
Medical research shows that sudden cardiac arrest is fatal 95% of the time. Most of the patients who received very quick treatment survive, but it is often challenging to get that treatment initiated before there is permanent damage to the brain and other vital organs. Experts recommend rapid treatment with an automated external defibrillator.</description></item><item><title>Study: Few medical students &amp; new doctors are competent in basic clinical skills, like measuring blood pressure</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/study-few-medical-students-new-doctors-are-competent-in-basic-clinical-skills-like-measuring-blood-pressure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/study-few-medical-students-new-doctors-are-competent-in-basic-clinical-skills-like-measuring-blood-pressure/</guid><description>In the United States, medical school is a four-year program after college. An undergraduate college degree provides no useful training related to caring for patients. Thus, when new doctors are licensed to practice medicine upon graduation from medical school, their knowledge base is obtained in the preceding four-year period.
Speaking from experience, medical students are bombarded with vast amounts of information and new clinical skills that they are expected to master in a short amount of time.</description></item><item><title>A simple rule for when to ask your doctor for a referral to a specialist</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/a-simple-rule-for-when-to-ask-your-doctor-for-a-referral-to-a-specialist/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/a-simple-rule-for-when-to-ask-your-doctor-for-a-referral-to-a-specialist/</guid><description>In my practice as a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I have represented many clients who knew something was wrong with their health and quickly went to their doctor. The problem arose when the doctor saw the patients over and over, but never arrived at the correct diagnosis or treatment.
Sadly, delayed treatment and diagnosis can cause life-threatening permanent injuries or even death.
This leads to the question of how long you should wait&amp;mdash;or keep making appointments&amp;mdash;for the same doctor to make the right diagnosis and treatment.</description></item><item><title>Research shows that many doctors need to work on communicating with their patients</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/research-shows-that-many-doctors-need-to-work-on-communicating-with-their-patients/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/research-shows-that-many-doctors-need-to-work-on-communicating-with-their-patients/</guid><description>The medical journal JAMA Internal Medicine recently published an interesting article entitled &amp;ldquo;Shared Understanding With Patients.&amp;rdquo;
As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, the title of this article captured my attention. Time after time, I meet with new clients who have been seriously injured from poor medical care who say something like, &amp;ldquo;If the doctor (or nurse) would have just listened, this never would have happened.&amp;rdquo;
Poor communication during treatment</description></item><item><title>When you add breathing problems to a sore throat, it is time to get medical help</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/when-you-add-breathing-problems-to-a-sore-throat-it-is-time-to-get-medical-help/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/when-you-add-breathing-problems-to-a-sore-throat-it-is-time-to-get-medical-help/</guid><description>One of the health care challenges that we all face is trying to decide if symptoms, like a sore throat or congestion, require medical care, or if they are rather benign and will go away on their own.
Here is a good example. A person has a fever and sore throat for two days, and then wakes up the next morning with loud breathing sounds. While many people may choose to treat a short-term fever and sore throat at home, when a breathing issue is added into the mix, it merits a trip to the doctor or emergency room.</description></item><item><title>Is care from a nurse practitioner as safe as care from a doctor?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/is-care-from-a-nurse-practitioner-as-safe-as-care-from-a-doctor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/is-care-from-a-nurse-practitioner-as-safe-as-care-from-a-doctor/</guid><description>Nursing groups are taking advantage of today&amp;rsquo;s climate of out-of-control health care costs to lobby for advanced practice registered nurses (APRNs or nurse practitioners) to be able to practice independently.
Under current Texas law, APRNs have to sign a delegation agreement with a collaborating physician in order to practice. Under such agreements, the doctor supervises the nurse practitioner, and delegates authority to diagnose, treat, write prescriptions, and even perform minor procedures in an office setting.</description></item><item><title>Four ways to uncover a harmful mistake or error by your doctor or hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/four-ways-to-uncover-a-harmful-mistake-or-error-by-your-doctor-or-hospital/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/four-ways-to-uncover-a-harmful-mistake-or-error-by-your-doctor-or-hospital/</guid><description>For the past several years, veterans all over America have faced dangerously-long wait times to see a doctor at many Veterans Administration (VA) hospitals. A 2014 CNN story summed up the problem with this headline: &amp;ldquo;A fatal wait: Veterans languish and die on a VA hospital&amp;#39;s secret list.&amp;rdquo;
The sad state of the VA hospital system was a major issue in the 2016 presidential campaign. President Donald Trump has pledged to get our veterans out of this mess, but it will take time.</description></item><item><title>Video: Prenatal visits and fundal height measurement can save lives</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/video-prenatal-visits-and-fundal-height-measurement-can-save-lives/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/video-prenatal-visits-and-fundal-height-measurement-can-save-lives/</guid><description>Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to speak about something that happens in every prenatal visit&amp;mdash;or at least it should in any prenatal visit with an OB/GYN&amp;mdash;and that&amp;rsquo;s the fundal height measurement.
I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you one of the most exciting things that ever happened in my life is when I learned that I was going to be a father&amp;mdash;a dad. And, of course, once we learned of this news my wife started having a lot of prenatal visits with her OB/GYN.</description></item></channel></rss>