<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>news on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/news/</link><description>Recent content in news on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Robert Painter receives Houston Bar Association President's Award</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/robert-painter-receives-houston-bar-association-presidents-award/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/robert-painter-receives-houston-bar-association-presidents-award/</guid><description>On May 15, 2014, at Houston&amp;#39;s River Oaks Country Club, Houston Bar Association President David Chaumette presented Painter Law Firm attorney Robert Painter with the President&amp;#39;s Award. The award recognize&amp;#39;s Robert Painter&amp;#39;s service as 2013-2014 editor-in-chief of The Houston Lawyer magazine, the official journal of the Houston Bar Association.</description></item><item><title>Houstonia magazine Top Lawyers recognition</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houstonia-magazine-top-lawyers-recognition/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houstonia-magazine-top-lawyers-recognition/</guid><description>Houstonia magazine recently recognized&amp;nbsp;Painter Law Firm attorneys Robert Painter and Taunya Painter on its listing of Houston&amp;#39;s top lawyers.&amp;nbsp;
Among other factors, Houstonia magazine considered the superb Avvo ranking of Houston medical malpractice and brain injury&amp;nbsp;attorney&amp;nbsp;Robert Painter and Houston business and commercial litigation attorney&amp;nbsp;Taunya Painter.</description></item><item><title>Robert Painter elected Fellow of Texas Bar Foundation</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/robert-painter-elected-fellow-of-texas-bar-foundation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/robert-painter-elected-fellow-of-texas-bar-foundation/</guid><description>In July 2013, Robert Painter, an attorney at Painter Law Firm PLLC, was elected to membership in the prestigious Fellows of the Texas Bar Foundation. Fellows of the Foundation are selected for their outstanding professional achievements and their demonstrated commitment to the improvement of the justice system throughout the state of Texas. Election to the Foundation is a mark of distinction and highlights Painter&amp;#39;s significant contributions to the legal profession.</description></item><item><title>Mongolian President Elbegdorj bestows Order of the Polar Star on Robert Painter</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/mongolian-president-elbegdorj-bestows-order-of-the-polar-star-on-robert-painter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/mongolian-president-elbegdorj-bestows-order-of-the-polar-star-on-robert-painter/</guid><description>On May 6, 2013, in New York City, attorney Robert Painter received the Order of Altan Gadas (Order of the Polar Star), pursuant to Decree 58 of the President of Mongolia, Tsakhiagiin Elbegdorj. The Altan Gadas (Order of the Polar Star) is the highest state honor bestowed on foreign nationals by the president of Mongolia and past recipients have included U.S. President Barack Obama and Russian President Vladimir Putin. President Elbegdorj bestowed the award in recognition of Robert Painter&amp;#39;s successful representation of the President and Government of Mongolia that led to the repatriation the great Tyrannosaurus bataar fossil, which had been illegally smuggled out of the country.</description></item><item><title>Robert Painter and Taunya Painter recognized among &amp;quot;Houston's Top Lawyers&amp;quot;</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/robert-painter-and-taunya-painter-recognized-among-quothoustons-top-lawyersquot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/robert-painter-and-taunya-painter-recognized-among-quothoustons-top-lawyersquot/</guid><description>In July 2012, H Texas magazine recognized Painter Law Firm attorneys Robert Painter and Taunya Painter as being among &amp;ldquo;Houston&amp;rsquo;s Top Lawyers&amp;rdquo; for their significant work in plaintiff&amp;rsquo;s medical malpractice cases.
H Texas magazine selects its picks for &amp;ldquo;Top Lawyers&amp;rdquo; from peer votes and reader nominations. The votes are tabulated, backgrounds are checked, and the list is narrowed down to the top 2% of lawyers voted as the best in the Houston area.</description></item><item><title>Firm attorneys, clients and friends enjoy The Pointer Sisters at Houston NW Chamber gala</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/firm-attorneys-clients-and-friends-enjoy-the-pointer-sisters-at-houston-nw-chamber-gala/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/firm-attorneys-clients-and-friends-enjoy-the-pointer-sisters-at-houston-nw-chamber-gala/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm attorneys Robert and Taunya Painter, clients Darrin Murray, Beatrice Lopez, Lyn Robertson, Albert Cheng, Leonor Cheng, and friends/co-counsel Richard Morrison, and Ann Morrison attended the Houston Northwest Chamber of Commerce&amp;rsquo;s annual gala on 1/29/11.
The firm sponsored the gala, with a $10,000 gift, which benefited economic development efforts in Northwest Houston.
The Chamber honored Harris County Judge Ed Emmett, and Houston Northwest Medical Center and its former chief executive, Drew Kahn, who recently moved to Dallas to become a system executive.</description></item><item><title>National College of Advocacy recognizes Robert Painter</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/national-college-of-advocacy-recognizes-robert-painter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/national-college-of-advocacy-recognizes-robert-painter/</guid><description>On September 7, 2010, the American Association for Justice National College of Advocacy recognized Robert Painter as an &amp;#39;Advocate&amp;#39;.
This recognition is bestowed to attorneys who complete over 30 hours of continuing legal education programs through the Association, showing a commitment to effective representation of clients through professional development.
Robert Painter&amp;#39;s commitment to keeping current on legal trends and education has also led to his admission to the College of the State Bar of Texas.</description></item></channel></rss>