<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bottom on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/bottom/</link><description>Recent content in bottom on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/bottom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dangerous low sodium needs prompt and proper medical care</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dangerous-low-sodium-needs-prompt-and-proper-medical-care/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dangerous-low-sodium-needs-prompt-and-proper-medical-care/</guid><description>I recently was contacted by the family of a middle-aged man who died from complication of hyponatremia, following care at Christus St. Elizabeth&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, in Beaumont, Texas.
Hyponatremia is a dangerous condition caused when a person has a low serum sodium level. Sodium is a very important electrolyte for our bodies, with roles in maintaining blood pressure, nerve communication and fluid balance. When a person has hyponatremia, it requires urgent and correct medical attention.</description></item><item><title>Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney Robert Painter files lawsuit that claims: Conroe Regional Medical Center nurses cause pressure sore, bone infection</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-files-lawsuit-that-claims-conroe-regional-medical-center-nurses-cause-pressure-sore-bone-infection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-files-lawsuit-that-claims-conroe-regional-medical-center-nurses-cause-pressure-sore-bone-infection/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm&amp;rsquo;s Texas medical malpractice lawyers recently filed a medical malpractice lawsuit on behalf of a 50-year old Montgomery man, named Raymond, against Conroe Regional Medical Center. The case is pending in the 410th District Court of Montgomery County, Texas.
Raymond is an otherwise healthy middle-aged man who works for an oil service company. He was admitted to Conroe Regional Hospital because of injuries from a motorcycle accident. During an admission of over one month, he completely recovered from those injuries, but left the hospital with a pressure sore on the heel of his left foot.</description></item><item><title>Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney Robert Painter files lawsuit that claims: Cypress OBGYN doctors fail to do Rh factor test &amp; cause newborn brain damage</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-files-lawsuit-that-claims-cypress-obgyn-doctors-fail-to-do-rh-factor-test-cause-newborn-brain-damage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-files-lawsuit-that-claims-cypress-obgyn-doctors-fail-to-do-rh-factor-test-cause-newborn-brain-damage/</guid><description>Every person is born with a blood type, which could be A, B, AB, or O. Blood type is also called positive or negative; if Rh factor is present, the blood type of called positive. For example, my blood is O negative, which means that I have O type blood without Rh factor.
Rh factor is the name of a protein on the surface of red bloods of people with Rh-positive blood.</description></item><item><title>Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer Robert Painter files lawsuit that claims: Doctor &amp; CVS prescription error causes patient death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-lawyer-robert-painter-files-lawsuit-that-claims-doctor-cvs-prescription-error-causes-patient-death/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-lawyer-robert-painter-files-lawsuit-that-claims-doctor-cvs-prescription-error-causes-patient-death/</guid><description>The Houston medical malpractice attorneys at Painter Law Firm filed a wrongful death lawsuit against CVS Pharmacy, Inc. and a local OB/GYN doctor, concerning the tragic and needless death of a 37-year-old wife and mother of two.
In August 2012, this lady saw an OB/GYN because her monthly cycle had lasted for 14 days, and it was heavy and unusually painful. The OB/GYN prescribed Lysteda, a medication that prevents blood clots from breaking down, which the patient then filled at CVS Pharmacy, Inc.</description></item><item><title>Infections in nursing homes or rehabilitation facilities can be deadly</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/infections-in-nursing-homes-or-rehabilitation-facilities-can-be-deadly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/infections-in-nursing-homes-or-rehabilitation-facilities-can-be-deadly/</guid><description>When patients are near the end of a hospitalization for a surgery or other illness, they sometimes need some additional care before they can go home. In these situations, case managers and doctors will often transfer patients to a nursing home or skilled nursing facility, like Manor Care Willowbrook, in Houston, or a rehabilitation facility, like Reliant Rehabilitation Hospital North Houston, in Shenandoah.
Patients and their families should realize that skilled nursing and rehabilitation facilities are frequently not set up to treat serious infections or to manage patients who are on multiple strong medications.</description></item><item><title>Nurses and doctors have to watch for dangerous gastric outlet obstruction after bariatric surgery</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/nurses-and-doctors-have-to-watch-for-dangerous-gastric-outlet-obstruction-after-bariatric-surgery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/nurses-and-doctors-have-to-watch-for-dangerous-gastric-outlet-obstruction-after-bariatric-surgery/</guid><description>I recently presented an expert witness bariatric surgeon for deposition in beautiful Salt Lake City, Utah.
Bariatric surgery is a field that is still rapidly developing and includes numerous procedures including lap-band, gastric sleeve, plication, bypass and imbrication. Generally speaking, bariatric procedures may help people suffering from obesity by decreasing the volume that the stomach can hold.
One of the known risks of any bariatric surgery is gastric outlet obstruction. This is a pretty easy concept to understand.</description></item><item><title>Video: Prenatal visits and fundal height measurement can save lives</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/video-prenatal-visits-and-fundal-height-measurement-can-save-lives/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/video-prenatal-visits-and-fundal-height-measurement-can-save-lives/</guid><description>Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to speak about something that happens in every prenatal visit&amp;mdash;or at least it should in any prenatal visit with an OB/GYN&amp;mdash;and that&amp;rsquo;s the fundal height measurement.
I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you one of the most exciting things that ever happened in my life is when I learned that I was going to be a father&amp;mdash;a dad. And, of course, once we learned of this news my wife started having a lot of prenatal visits with her OB/GYN.</description></item><item><title>How to spot life-threatening infections and sepsis</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-spot-life-threatening-infections-and-sepsis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-spot-life-threatening-infections-and-sepsis/</guid><description>Infections occur when bacteria or fungi invade the human body and then start multiplying and feeding. There are many types of infections that we commonly hear about, including staph infections, MRSA infections (methicillin-resistant staph aureus), bedsores and infected catheters or lines.
It is always a serious matter when a patient has an active infection. Prompt diagnosis is important because the faster treatment begins, the more likely the infection can be killed and the patient can go on with his or her life.</description></item></channel></rss>