<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cardiac on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/cardiac/</link><description>Recent content in cardiac on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/cardiac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What you should know about an EKG ST elevation and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-an-ekg-st-elevation-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-an-ekg-st-elevation-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>Doctors order an electrocardiogram (also called an EKG or ECG) to check for heart abnormalities. They&amp;rsquo;re sometimes performed as part of regular cardiac workup and other times to assess a patient&amp;rsquo;s cardiovascular risk for a non-cardiac surgery.
There are different kinds of EKG, and they are typically described by the number of leads. There are 1, 3, 6, and 12-lead EKGs. The EKG machine records changes in the electrical potential between electrodes placed on the skin.</description></item><item><title>What you need to know about cardiac clearance and how it might save your life</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-need-to-know-about-cardiac-clearance-and-how-it-might-save-your-life/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-need-to-know-about-cardiac-clearance-and-how-it-might-save-your-life/</guid><description>Cardiac clearance is a medical assessment or workup that a surgeon and anesthesia provider (anesthesiologist or certified registered nurse anesthetist, or CRNA) should consider before an elective, non-cardiac surgery.
The idea behind cardiac clearance is to assess a patient&amp;rsquo;s risk of a cardiovascular event occurring during the surgery and what interventions and plans can be made to manage them. If a serious heart condition is uncovered, the elective surgery will be delayed or canceled so the life-threatening cardiac issues can be addressed.</description></item></channel></rss>