<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>austin on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/austin/</link><description>Recent content in austin on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/austin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Austin Medical Malpractice Attorney</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/areas-we-serve/austin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/areas-we-serve/austin/</guid><description>If you or a loved one has suffered injuries due to medical malpractice in the vibrant city of Austin or the surrounding picturesque neighborhoods, you may be entitled to seek justice and compensation for your losses. Medical malpractice cases can be complex and emotionally challenging, but with the right legal representation, you can hold negligent parties accountable for their actions. At Painter Law Firm, we are dedicated exclusively to medical malpractice cases and have a deep understanding of the laws that govern them in Austin, as well as the surrounding neighborhoods and hospitals.</description></item><item><title>Texas doctors can't blame hospital policies for lack of proper medical care</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-doctors-cant-blame-hospital-policies-for-lack-of-proper-medical-care/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-doctors-cant-blame-hospital-policies-for-lack-of-proper-medical-care/</guid><description>The Austin Court of Appeals tackled an interesting legal issue on the effect of hospital policies on physician care. The case arose from alleged hospital emergency room (ER) medical malpractice involving treating a rattlesnake bite on a teenage girl.
The case is styled Dunnick v. Kristy Marsillo, DO; No. 03-21-00296-CV, Austin Court of Appeals, and you can read the opinion here.
The terrible events began when a rattlesnake bit teenager Raynee&amp;rsquo;s left foot.</description></item><item><title>Medicare issues report on Ascension Seton Medical Center Austin's substantial deficient practices</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medicare-issues-report-on-ascension-seton-medical-center-austins-substantial-deficient-practices/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medicare-issues-report-on-ascension-seton-medical-center-austins-substantial-deficient-practices/</guid><description>The Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services recently released a report of its surveyor inspection of Ascension Seton Medical Center Austin, which is located at 1201 W 38th St., in Austin, Texas. This Ascension hospital is part of the large Ascension Health system.
Hospitals, such as Ascension Seton Medical Center Austin, that participate in Medicare and Medicaid must allow on-site surveys by state agencies and accrediting organizations, such as The Joint Commission, to ensure that they&amp;rsquo;re complying with federal regulations.</description></item><item><title>St. David’s South Austin Medical Center medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/st.-david%C3%A2s-south-austin-medical-center-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/st.-david%C3%A2s-south-austin-medical-center-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas based medical malpractice lawyer, I handle cases all over the State of Texas. I am currently investigating a surgical infection case involving care that was provided at St. David&amp;rsquo;s South Austin Medical Center, which is located at 901 W. Ben White Boulevard, Austin, TX 78704.
Any time that Painter Law Firm accept representation in a case related to hospital care, we do thorough research into the hospital.</description></item></channel></rss>