<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>medical records and documents on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/medical-records-and-documents/</link><description>Recent content in medical records and documents on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/medical-records-and-documents/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Nightmare Unleashed: The Shocking Reality of Medical Identity Mix-ups</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/a-nightmare-unleashed-the-shocking-reality-of-medical-identity-mix-ups/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/a-nightmare-unleashed-the-shocking-reality-of-medical-identity-mix-ups/</guid><description>A few years ago, Painter Law Firm represented a woman in her 70s who lived in a Houston suburb. Let&amp;#39;s refer to her as Sarah.
Sarah was a delightful lady with a grandmotherly smile that brightened everyone&amp;#39;s day. Prior to hiring our firm, she underwent abdominal surgery and was scheduled for a short stay in a skilled nursing facility (SNF) to recover and regain strength before returning home. Despite some hearing difficulties, Sarah led an independent life and was generally healthy.</description></item><item><title>Missing, mistaken, and manufactured medical records</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/missing-mistaken-and-manufactured-medical-records/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/missing-mistaken-and-manufactured-medical-records/</guid><description>Our medical malpractice clients are often surprised at what they read in their own medical records. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty common for us to hear that key information is missing, other things are inaccurate, and some things that are documented never happened at all.
A recent closed claim study by a major medical malpractice insurance carrier found that medical record documentation issues play a role in about 20% of claims. The study broke down the medical records problems into three categories: (1) insufficient/lack of documentation; (2) content decisions; and (3) mechanics.</description></item><item><title>Texas courts can consider absent or missing medical records when determining expert report sufficiency</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-courts-can-consider-absent-or-missing-medical-records-when-determining-expert-report-sufficiency/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-courts-can-consider-absent-or-missing-medical-records-when-determining-expert-report-sufficiency/</guid><description>Attorneys for victims of medical malpractice regularly have to confront the challenge of proving negligence when medical records are absent or incomplete. Under Texas law, this is particularly difficult because of the tort reform mandate that plaintiffs produce a medical expert report early in litigation, before depositions or other discovery can occur.
The public policy by requiring medical reports at the beginning of a lawsuit is two-fold. First, it weeds out frivolous claims.</description></item><item><title>Medical records, texts, and chats: The sources of physician and healthcare provider patient care documentation</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medical-records-texts-and-chats-the-sources-of-physician-and-healthcare-provider-patient-care-documentation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medical-records-texts-and-chats-the-sources-of-physician-and-healthcare-provider-patient-care-documentation/</guid><description>One of the first things that medical malpractice lawyers do when starting an investigation into a new case is order all the relevant medical records.
You&amp;rsquo;d think that this would be an easy proposition. It&amp;rsquo;s not.
Quite often, our clients believe that they already have a complete set of their medical records. In reality, though, when a patient asks for their medical records, hospital release of information offices often only provide a small fraction of them, typically limited to physician notes.</description></item><item><title>Executing a document in Texas when physical disability prevents signing</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/executing-a-document-in-texas-when-physical-disability-prevents-signing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/executing-a-document-in-texas-when-physical-disability-prevents-signing/</guid><description>We are sometimes asked by potential clients about how they can get a power of attorney to sign a document or make decisions on behalf of someone who&amp;rsquo;s already incapacitated. The answer to that question is easy&amp;mdash;you can&amp;rsquo;t.
When a person is already incapacitated, by definition they lack the capacity to sign a power of attorney, medical power of attorney, or will. In those situations, families may be left with one alternative, a filing for a guardianship, which is neither inexpensive nor quick.</description></item><item><title>The legal documents everyone should have in the era of COVID and beyond</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-legal-documents-everyone-should-have-in-the-era-of-covid-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-legal-documents-everyone-should-have-in-the-era-of-covid-and-beyond/</guid><description>Years ago, I took a phone call from a potential client requesting our urgent assistance in preparing a will for her hospitalized husband. She wanted us to prepare the documents, travel to the hospital, and provide a notary and witnesses&amp;mdash;and it needed done pronto.
As we got into the discussion, I learned that her husband was unconscious, facing a surgery the next day, and not expected to survive. When I explained that a person must be awake and sufficiently alert to demonstrate capacity to sign a will, she asked if we could just do a power of attorney instead.</description></item><item><title>What you should know about HIPAA in the age of COVID and beyond</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-hipaa-in-the-age-of-covid-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-hipaa-in-the-age-of-covid-and-beyond/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s HIPAA. Not HIPPA. And definitely not HIPPO.
Regardless of the abbreviation, the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act, signed into law in 1996, is a chronically misunderstood statute&amp;mdash;perhaps now more than ever in the era of COVID-19.
As a Texas medical malpractice law firm, we regularly receive questions from potential clients about HIPAA violations. This article will answer some of the most common ones.
You can&amp;rsquo;t sue for a HIPAA violation</description></item><item><title>How to pursue a Texas medical malpractice case when medical records are silent or missing</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-pursue-a-texas-medical-malpractice-case-when-medical-records-are-silent-or-missing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-pursue-a-texas-medical-malpractice-case-when-medical-records-are-silent-or-missing/</guid><description>Early in my legal career, the main challenge in reviewing medical records was deciphering handwriting. As a group, doctors are legendary for having terrible penmanship.
With the advent of electronic medical records, new issues emerged in medical record analysis. Electronic medical records are easy to read because they&amp;rsquo;re typewritten, but perhaps 75% of a typical patient chart is regurgitated or repeated text from prior injuries.
Repeated make it difficult to determine what a doctor or provider actually reviewed, or what was auto-populated by the computer system.</description></item><item><title>Proposed federal rule would improve patient access and cost for medical records</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/proposed-federal-rule-would-improve-patient-access-and-cost-for-medical-records/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/proposed-federal-rule-would-improve-patient-access-and-cost-for-medical-records/</guid><description>One of the challenges straight out of the gate in a medical malpractice case is getting a complete set of the medical records. I could write a whole series of articles on this topic, including very real hurdles like incomplete production of records and audit trails. Today, though, I&amp;rsquo;m going to focus to the federally-protected right of access.
I bet that most people don&amp;rsquo;t think of medical records as a profit center.</description></item><item><title>When it comes to patient clinical data, there are places to look other than just the medical records</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/when-it-comes-to-patient-clinical-data-there-are-places-to-look-other-than-just-the-medical-records/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/when-it-comes-to-patient-clinical-data-there-are-places-to-look-other-than-just-the-medical-records/</guid><description>When reviewing medical records forensically, there has always been a challenge in ensuring that the date and time entries are accurate.
When I began my career as a medical malpractice lawyer over 20 years ago, the most common question was whether the clocks in each room where care was provided were synchronized.
In an obstetrical or birth injury case, for example, the clock in the emergency room (ER) might have a different time than the clock in the labor and delivery room, which could have a different time than the clock on the wall in the C-section operating room.</description></item><item><title>What do Texas physicians have to document in the medical record after each visit?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-do-texas-physicians-have-to-document-in-the-medical-record-after-each-visit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-do-texas-physicians-have-to-document-in-the-medical-record-after-each-visit/</guid><description>I spent several hours today deposing a defendant surgeon in a medical malpractice case. My client, the surgeon&amp;rsquo;s patient, was left severely disfigured after the surgeon botched some elective plastic/cosmetic surgical procedures.
One of the focuses on the case is the surgeon&amp;rsquo;s lack of involvement in the preoperative planning, consent process, and surgical plan. From my experience in handling other health care liability claims against plastic surgeons, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t surprised to learn about the high-pressure sales staff or the hands-off surgeon.</description></item><item><title>Why are emergency room discharge instructions so important?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/why-are-emergency-room-discharge-instructions-so-important/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/why-are-emergency-room-discharge-instructions-so-important/</guid><description>As the name suggests, emergency rooms (ER) are intense places. Triage nurses perform a quick assessment of patients to determine who needs seen most urgently. ER physicians, physician assistants (PAs), and nurse practitioners (NPs) evaluate patients and order testing to determine which patients need admitted to the hospital and those who should be discharged home.
One of the important determining factors concerning discharges is whether a patient is medically stable. The federal Emergency Treatment and Active Labor Act (EMTALA) was signed into law by President Ronald Reagan to prevent patient dumping.</description></item><item><title>What can the trial court consider at a Chapter 74 preliminary expert report hearing in a Texas medical malpractice case?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-can-the-trial-court-consider-at-a-chapter-74-preliminary-expert-report-hearing-in-a-texas-medical-malpractice-case/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-can-the-trial-court-consider-at-a-chapter-74-preliminary-expert-report-hearing-in-a-texas-medical-malpractice-case/</guid><description>Texas law requires medical malpractice plaintiffs to produce one or more medical expert reports within 120 days of each defendant filing an answer and a lawsuit. The standards for these reports are demanding, requiring separate statements of the applicable standard of care (what should have been done), how the standard of care was violated (what wasn&amp;rsquo;t done correctly), and how those medical mistakes proximately caused harm to the plaintiff.
How do defendants respond to the preliminary expert reports, and what are the potential consequences?</description></item><item><title>When does the willful and wanton standard of proof apply in Texas ER medical malpractice cases?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/when-does-the-willful-and-wanton-standard-of-proof-apply-in-texas-er-medical-malpractice-cases/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/when-does-the-willful-and-wanton-standard-of-proof-apply-in-texas-er-medical-malpractice-cases/</guid><description>Texas law treats medical malpractice lawsuits differently from other types of negligence cases. One of the significant differences is a heightened standard of proof in some types of claims.
Texas Civil Practice &amp;amp; Remedies Code Section 74.153 mandates a standard of proof called “willful and wanton negligence” for certain emergency medical care cases. If you’re confused by what that means, join the club. Willful conduct is inconsistent with any theory of negligence, but that discussion is for another day.</description></item><item><title>Medication error temporarily paralyzes Houston patient, causes brain injury</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medication-error-temporarily-paralyzes-houston-patient-causes-brain-injury/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medication-error-temporarily-paralyzes-houston-patient-causes-brain-injury/</guid><description>Medication errors come in all shapes and sizes.
We&amp;rsquo;ve recently been working on a case where a major pharmacy chain dispensed and filled a prescription for a heart medication. The same bottle contained some pills for the correct medication that was ordered by the patient&amp;rsquo;s doctor and other pills that were a different medication. When the man took the medication, he became extremely dizzy and had an irregular heartbeat. His coworkers called an ambulance that took him to a hospital, where his doctors and nurses fortunately discovered the medication error.</description></item><item><title>When your medical records leave out information, you can fill in the blanks</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/when-your-medical-records-leave-out-information-you-can-fill-in-the-blanks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/when-your-medical-records-leave-out-information-you-can-fill-in-the-blanks/</guid><description>Here at Painter Law Firm, we regularly speak with victims of medical malpractice who are upset and worried that their medical records aren&amp;rsquo;t accurate or have a lot of missing information.
Right now, in fact, we&amp;rsquo;re working on two cases where there are huge gaps in the medical record documentation precisely at the time of key events. It&amp;rsquo;s hard not to be cynical in these situations. We definitely understand our clients&amp;rsquo; angst.</description></item><item><title>Can I pursue a Texas medical malpractice case if my medical records are inaccurate?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/can-i-pursue-a-texas-medical-malpractice-case-if-my-medical-records-are-inaccurate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/can-i-pursue-a-texas-medical-malpractice-case-if-my-medical-records-are-inaccurate/</guid><description>When we meet with a new medical malpractice client at Painter Law Firm, we do a thorough interview to make sure we understand exactly what happened during the relevant healthcare that led to serious injury.
The next step is ordering all of the relevant medical records for a careful review. It&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon for our legal nurses to find discrepancies between the client recollection of events and what&amp;rsquo;s recorded in the medical records.</description></item><item><title>Federal judge enters opinion increasing the cost for medical records</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/federal-judge-enters-opinion-increasing-the-cost-for-medical-records/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/federal-judge-enters-opinion-increasing-the-cost-for-medical-records/</guid><description>Medical records can be expensive. Some hospitals and doctors view them as profit centers and charge hefty fees for them.
That&amp;rsquo;s why the federal government stepped in, in 2009. The HITECH Act established a federal right of access to medical records and generally capped the fees that doctors and hospitals can charge for medical records at $6.50. You can read about that here.
Plus, the HITECH Act regulations put out by the U.</description></item><item><title>Audit trails can uncover doctored, altered, or forged medical records</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/audit-trails-can-uncover-doctored-altered-or-forged-medical-records/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/audit-trails-can-uncover-doctored-altered-or-forged-medical-records/</guid><description>In medical malpractice cases, there is one thing for sure: The medical records will be front and center for the parties, medical experts, and judge and jury to see. They&amp;rsquo;re so important because medical records are usually the only contemporaneous documentation of what happened in the healthcare at issue.
From handling countless Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawsuits, I can say that it&amp;rsquo;s pretty common to have situations where there is an issue with the medical records.</description></item><item><title>What does patient noncompliance mean?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-does-patient-noncompliance-mean/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-does-patient-noncompliance-mean/</guid><description>Compliance and noncompliance are words used by doctors and nurses to describe whether a patient is following instructions and cooperating with recommended treatments.
Compliance means that a patient is being cooperative.
Noncompliance means that a patient isn&amp;rsquo;t being cooperative.
Health care providers document in medical records whether a patient is compliant or noncompliant to help guide future care and, in some cases, to point the blame at patients when something is going wrong.</description></item><item><title>What happens when your medical records are wrong?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-happens-when-your-medical-records-are-wrong/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-happens-when-your-medical-records-are-wrong/</guid><description>One of the major changes that I have witnessed in my career, first as a hospital administrator, and now for almost 20 years as a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, is the transition from paper medical records to electronic medical records.
I cannot remember speaking to anyone in medicine, nursing, or law who believes that electronic medical records are a step forward when it comes to taking care of patients. The only advantage that I see is that electronic records are easy to read and search; however, a chart that used to be 100-200 pages can now easily be 10 times that amount because of unnecessarily-repeated information that is auto-populated by the software.</description></item><item><title>Guardianships and alternatives in Texas, and why you should plan ahead</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/guardianships-and-alternatives-in-texas-and-why-you-should-plan-ahead/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/guardianships-and-alternatives-in-texas-and-why-you-should-plan-ahead/</guid><description>I attended the Houston Bar Association&amp;rsquo;s (HBA) annual all-day guardianship seminar today. By the way, the HBA was founded in 1870, and I was elected to its board of directors this year.
As the seminar got underway, I thought about the different situations where I have represented clients in guardianships, as well as the alternatives to guardianship. As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, these issues come up from time to time, and I think everyone should think about them far in advance.</description></item><item><title>New system provides doctors and nurses instant access to hospital records nationwide</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-system-provides-doctors-and-nurses-instant-access-to-hospital-records-nationwide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-system-provides-doctors-and-nurses-instant-access-to-hospital-records-nationwide/</guid><description>I spent most of today in the deposition of a nursing expert. I retained this wound care and rehabilitation nursing expert in a medical malpractice lawsuit involving healthcare at Mainland Medical Center, in Webster, Texas.
During our lunch break, the nursing expert and I discussed some of the challenges involving electronic medical records.
Nursing documentation that used to be made on a few pages of flowsheets now consumes hundreds of pages.</description></item><item><title>Do-not-resuscitate (DNR) orders increase likelihood of ICU death, less overall care</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/do-not-resuscitate-dnr-orders-increase-likelihood-of-icu-death-less-overall-care/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/do-not-resuscitate-dnr-orders-increase-likelihood-of-icu-death-less-overall-care/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, patients and family members frequently ask me questions about the legal impact of advance directives.
An advance directive is a written document that summarizes a person&amp;rsquo;s health care wishes and preferences. I think it is a good idea to have an advance directive because it benefits both healthcare providers and family members in making treatment decisions when a person is incapacitated.
Some people create advance directives that request all measures to be taken to preserve life.</description></item><item><title>The important reason to always get your medical records and radiology CDs before leaving a hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-important-reason-to-always-get-your-medical-records-and-radiology-cds-before-leaving-a-hospital/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-important-reason-to-always-get-your-medical-records-and-radiology-cds-before-leaving-a-hospital/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I speak with people every day about how things in their health care went wrong. One of the things that I always look out for is trends on how things fall through the cracks.
I have noticed that one area where there is an increased risk of a mistake is when health care is provided at different facilities. Two examples immediately come to mind.</description></item><item><title>Understanding HIPAA, patient privacy laws, and medical records requests</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/understanding-hipaa-patient-privacy-laws-and-medical-records-requests/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/understanding-hipaa-patient-privacy-laws-and-medical-records-requests/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, my office deals with medical records constantly. In doing so, we deal with the federal HIPAA law every day.
HIPAA is a short name for the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996. It became law in a period when electronic information was still emerging, and was aimed at ensuring patient privacy. The law defines covered entities, which include healthcare providers like hospitals and doctors, and requires them to implement privacy standards and security standards for &amp;ldquo;protected health information.</description></item><item><title>VA hospital nurse mixes up resuscitation order, patient dies</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/va-hospital-nurse-mixes-up-resuscitation-order-patient-dies/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/va-hospital-nurse-mixes-up-resuscitation-order-patient-dies/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I have represented many clients in medical negligence or wrongful death cases arising from hospital care provided after the surgery.
Recently, the Office of the Inspector General released report critical of a VA Hospital&amp;rsquo;s handling of a patient&amp;rsquo;s care after a bypass surgery. The patient was admitted to the hospital for surgery to address leg pain from a blocked artery.
While he was recovering from the surgery, the patient experienced chest pain and nausea.</description></item><item><title>What happens when critical lab or radiology results are not communicated to the doctor</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-happens-when-critical-lab-or-radiology-results-are-not-communicated-to-the-doctor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-happens-when-critical-lab-or-radiology-results-are-not-communicated-to-the-doctor/</guid><description>I focus my Houston, Texas-based law practice on representing patients and family members in medical malpractice cases. This gives me an opportunity to see trends in medical errors generally, as well as bad outcomes that happen over and over again at particular hospitals.
Another organization that has the unique vantage point for medical errors is the Joint Commission, which is a major accrediting organization for hospitals and healthcare facilities. Each year, the Joint Commission issues a list of several National Patient Safety Goals, based on its analysis of common medical errors and recommendations on how to reduce them.</description></item><item><title>Doctor and physician assistant alter patient's medical recordâ€”you won't believe what happened next</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/doctor-and-physician-assistant-alter-patients-medical-record%C3%A2you-wont-believe-what-happened-next/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/doctor-and-physician-assistant-alter-patients-medical-record%C3%A2you-wont-believe-what-happened-next/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I frequently meet with patients and family members who express concern that their medical records are inaccurate, or have been changed, altered, or falsified.
Undocumented healthcare
When Painter Law Firm files medical malpractice or wrongful death lawsuits on behalf of our clients, the defendant doctors or nurses often claim to have provided care that is not documented in the medical records. When this happens, the defendants invariably testify that their primary responsibility is to provide healthcare, with documentation playing second fiddle.</description></item><item><title>New Texas law will protect patients from hostile do-not-resuscitate/DNR orders</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-texas-law-will-protect-patients-from-hostile-do-not-resuscitate/dnr-orders/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-texas-law-will-protect-patients-from-hostile-do-not-resuscitate/dnr-orders/</guid><description>In my experience as a Houston , Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I believe that the most shocking Texas laws that I share with clients is that doctors can enter a do not resuscitate (DNR) without the patient or family&amp;rsquo;s consent&amp;mdash;or even knowledge.
Thanks to recent legislation, though, it will not be long before this practice will end.
Before discussing the current Texas DNR law, and how it is about to change, we should really talk about what a DNR order is in the first place.</description></item><item><title>Texas law lets hospitals and doctors override your advance directive and terminate curative care</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-law-lets-hospitals-and-doctors-override-your-advance-directive-and-terminate-curative-care/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-law-lets-hospitals-and-doctors-override-your-advance-directive-and-terminate-curative-care/</guid><description>On September 22, 2017, I attended a hearing in the 189th District Court of Harris County, Texas, where Judge Bill Burke was presiding. The case is styled Evelyn Kelly, Individually and On Behalf of the Estate of David Christopher Dunn v. The Methodist Hospital; Cause No. 2015-69681. Ms. Kelly is Mr. Dunn&amp;rsquo;s mother. Mr. Dunn died while a patient at Houston Methodist Hospital.
This very interesting oral hearing addressed competing motions for summary judgment filed by both sides over whether Texas Health &amp;amp; Safety Code Section 166.</description></item><item><title>How to get your medical records, how much you can be charged, and why you need them</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-get-your-medical-records-how-much-you-can-be-charged-and-why-you-need-them/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-get-your-medical-records-how-much-you-can-be-charged-and-why-you-need-them/</guid><description>As a medical malpractice lawyer, one of the most common things I hear from my clients is how difficult it is to get a copy of their medical records.
Time and time again I hear how patients feel like they are getting the run-around from hospitals and doctors&amp;rsquo; offices. Then, even if they finally get a copy of the medical records, they seem to be missing key pages and information.</description></item><item><title>Rushed doctors can place outdated, inaccurate information in your electronic medical record</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/rushed-doctors-can-place-outdated-inaccurate-information-in-your-electronic-medical-record/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/rushed-doctors-can-place-outdated-inaccurate-information-in-your-electronic-medical-record/</guid><description>How reliable is the information that your doctor is using to diagnose and treat you? Is it comprehensive? Is it detailed? Is it even accurate?
As a Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I have handled case after case where there were serious medical mistakes because doctors were using incomplete and just plain wrong information to make treatment decisions for their patients.
In my experience, the advent of electronic medical records has only made this worse.</description></item><item><title>When you sign a medical consent form, does it excuse the doctor's negligence or mistakes?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/when-you-sign-a-medical-consent-form-does-it-excuse-the-doctors-negligence-or-mistakes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/when-you-sign-a-medical-consent-form-does-it-excuse-the-doctors-negligence-or-mistakes/</guid><description>As an experienced Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I meet with people practically every day who have been seriously injured as a result of poor medical care.
During these consultations, these new clients tell me about what happened to them, the pain and suffering that they have gone through, and how it has changed their lives.
Every so often, one of them will almost express a guilty feeling about consulting a lawyer.</description></item><item><title>Three documents that you should have in place today, and certainly before you go into a hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-documents-that-you-should-have-in-place-today-and-certainly-before-you-go-into-a-hospital/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-documents-that-you-should-have-in-place-today-and-certainly-before-you-go-into-a-hospital/</guid><description>I recently spoke with the aunt of a 50-year-old woman who is currently on life support at a major hospital in the Texas Medical Center, in Houston.
As an experienced medical malpractice lawyer, I get calls like this all the time. Sadly, this is one of those times when there is nothing that we can do to help because the poor lady who is now unconscious did not plan ahead for something like this.</description></item><item><title>What can you do if you think that a doctor or nurse altered your medical record?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-can-you-do-if-you-think-that-a-doctor-or-nurse-altered-your-medical-record/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-can-you-do-if-you-think-that-a-doctor-or-nurse-altered-your-medical-record/</guid><description>As a Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I frequently represent clients who suspect that hospitals, doctors, and nurses have changed, altered, or doctored the medical records.
Sometimes these patients and family members believe that the medical records are incomplete, contain false information, or have been manipulated or altered after-the-fact to cover-up a negligence, a mistake, or bad care.
One of the benefits of hiring an attorney who focus on medical malpractice cases is getting the experience in analyzing medical records.</description></item><item><title>Texas allows doctors to sign unauthorized do not resuscitate (DNR) orders without telling you</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-allows-doctors-to-sign-unauthorized-do-not-resuscitate-dnr-orders-without-telling-you/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-allows-doctors-to-sign-unauthorized-do-not-resuscitate-dnr-orders-without-telling-you/</guid><description>An Illinois family recently filed a wrongful death lawsuit against a nursing home facility after the healthcare providers failed to resuscitate their 52-year-old loved one.&amp;nbsp;
According to the lawsuit, the woman had indicated her desire that the nursing home &amp;ldquo;render full treatment including all resuscitation efforts medically available to her in the event of a cardiac or respiratory arrest.&amp;rdquo;
This type of advance directive decision refers to a patient&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;do not resuscitate&amp;rdquo; or DNR status.</description></item><item><title>Four ways to uncover a harmful mistake or error by your doctor or hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/four-ways-to-uncover-a-harmful-mistake-or-error-by-your-doctor-or-hospital/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/four-ways-to-uncover-a-harmful-mistake-or-error-by-your-doctor-or-hospital/</guid><description>For the past several years, veterans all over America have faced dangerously-long wait times to see a doctor at many Veterans Administration (VA) hospitals. A 2014 CNN story summed up the problem with this headline: &amp;ldquo;A fatal wait: Veterans languish and die on a VA hospital&amp;#39;s secret list.&amp;rdquo;
The sad state of the VA hospital system was a major issue in the 2016 presidential campaign. President Donald Trump has pledged to get our veterans out of this mess, but it will take time.</description></item><item><title>Three ways to improve the accuracy and safety of your medical records</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-ways-to-improve-the-accuracy-and-safety-of-your-medical-records/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-ways-to-improve-the-accuracy-and-safety-of-your-medical-records/</guid><description>A 2017 study has confirmed what I already knew from years of practice as a Texas medical malpractice attorney. A report in the journal JAMA Ophthalmology shows that the symptom information given by patients did not match what doctors wrote in the medical records for the following:
&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Glare:&amp;nbsp;48 percent of the time
&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Pain:&amp;nbsp;27 percent of the time
&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Redness: 25 percent of the time</description></item><item><title>Protect yourself from the risks of electronic medical records</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/protect-yourself-from-the-risks-of-electronic-medical-records/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/protect-yourself-from-the-risks-of-electronic-medical-records/</guid><description>You may have noticed over the past few years that more and more doctors and hospitals are using electronic medical records, rather than the older style of mostly handwritten records.
The reason that this has happened in such a rush if the 2009 passage of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act, which created funding, incentives and penalties to get hospitals and doctors to adopt and meaningfully use electronic medical records by 2014.</description></item><item><title>Protect against medical malpractice with a hospital journal</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/protect-against-medical-malpractice-with-a-hospital-journal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/protect-against-medical-malpractice-with-a-hospital-journal/</guid><description>Any time you or someone you care about is admitted to a hospital, nursing home, skilled nursing facility or rehabilitation center, I encourage you to keep a hospital journal.
As a medical malpractice lawyer who has represented patients and families in Houston, all over Texas and various states, I have seen time and time again how valuable this information can be.&amp;nbsp;
In most medical malpractice cases, the statute of limitations is two years.</description></item></channel></rss>