<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Texas Supreme Court on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/texas-supreme-court/</link><description>Recent content in Texas Supreme Court on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/texas-supreme-court/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Texas Malpractice Law Evolves: Insights from Hampton v. Thome Case</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-medical-malpractice-hampton-thome/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-medical-malpractice-hampton-thome/</guid><description>Teeing up a Texas medical malpractice case isn’t simple. In fact, for those inexperienced with a specialized area of law, it’s fraught with perils. I’ve often described it as the Texas medical malpractice minefield.
From a practical perspective, investigating a potential medical malpractice claim and preparing it for filing in court revolves around acquiring all the relevant medical records and obtaining opinions from physicians, nursing, and other experts.
Are Pre-Suit Notices a Double-Edged Sword for Medical Malpractice Cases?</description></item><item><title>Texas Supreme Court Raises Bar on ER Malpractice Cases, Leaving Victims with Limited Options</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-supreme-court-marsillo-er-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-supreme-court-marsillo-er-malpractice/</guid><description>Since 2003, tort reform measures that became law in Texas have made medical malpractice cases more difficult to pursue. When it comes to hospital emergency room (ER) care, some medical malpractice claims are downright impossible to pursue under existing law.
On January 12, 2024, the Texas Supreme Court entered an opinion to make it even harder for victims of medical malpractice in hospital emergency rooms to seek justice in Texas courtrooms.</description></item><item><title>Texas Supreme Court addresses how medical malpractice future health care expenses are paid</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-supreme-court-addresses-how-medical-malpractice-future-health-care-expenses-are-paid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-supreme-court-addresses-how-medical-malpractice-future-health-care-expenses-are-paid/</guid><description>When a person is severely injured by medical malpractice, family members often are left wondering how to pay for future health care.
That’s what happened to a young Texas mother whose baby was born with a brain injury and cerebral palsy. The mom, Ana Ramirez, filed a medical malpractice lawsuit on behalf of her son. Let’s call him Andy.
Around 33 weeks into her pregnancy with Andy, Ana went to Valley Regional Hospital on a Friday night after her water broke prematurely and she went into labor.</description></item><item><title>What comes next after filing a Texas medical malpractice lawsuit?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-comes-next-after-filing-a-texas-medical-malpractice-lawsuit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-comes-next-after-filing-a-texas-medical-malpractice-lawsuit/</guid><description>Filing a new Texas medical malpractice lawsuit—like any other civil claim in Texas state court—requires detailed attention to some technical procedural steps. In some situations, messing up one of these details can lead to dismissal of a case.
What is the Fair Notice Pleadings Standard in Texas State Court? Texas uses a fair notice pleadings standard. In Texas state court, the legal document that initiates a new lawsuit is called a petition.</description></item><item><title>Texas Supreme Court addresses medical negligence causation standard in new opinion</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-supreme-court-addresses-medical-negligence-causation-standard-in-new-opinion/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-supreme-court-addresses-medical-negligence-causation-standard-in-new-opinion/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I continually review new Texas appellate opinions that may impact lawsuits that I have filed or cases that I am handling.
Today, the Texas Supreme Court entered a ground-breaking opinion that is favorable to medical malpractice plaintiffs in several areas. The case is styled Debra Gunn, Obstetrical and Gynecological Associates, P.A., and Obstetrical and Gynecological Associates, P.L.L.C. v. Andre McCoy, As Permanent Guardian of Shannon Miles McCoy, an Incapacitated Person; No.</description></item></channel></rss>