<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>military on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/military/</link><description>Recent content in military on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/military/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to file a VA Medical Center medical malpractice claim</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-file-a-va-medical-center-medical-malpractice-claim/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-file-a-va-medical-center-medical-malpractice-claim/</guid><description>When a veteran is seriously injured because of health care provided at a U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center (VA Medical Center), different rules apply for making a medical malpractice claim. By different, I mean the rules aren&amp;rsquo;t the same as if the injury occurred at a non-federal government hospital.
As a U.S. Army veteran, former U.S. Army hospital administrator (the photo is of General Leonard Wood Army Community Hospital, as it looked when I served there), and son of a former VA Medical Center administrator, I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with the unique legal process that applies to VA medical negligence claims.</description></item><item><title>Air Force hospital medical malpractice cases</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/air-force-hospital-medical-malpractice-cases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/air-force-hospital-medical-malpractice-cases/</guid><description>Everyone who serves in the U.S. military sees firsthand things that just are invisible to civilians. The same is true for dependents and family members. For example, try explaining to a civilian the concept of &amp;ldquo;hurry up and wait.&amp;rdquo;
Sadly, one fact that service members, veterans, and their dependents know is that Air Force, Army, and Navy hospital health care often miss the mark when compared with civilian hospitals.
I know that I witnessed this myself.</description></item><item><title>Army hospital medical malpractice cases</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/army-hospital-medical-malpractice-cases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/army-hospital-medical-malpractice-cases/</guid><description>Before going to law school, I served as an officer in the U.S. Army Medical Service Corps, where my MOS was 67B, health care administration. I was stationed at Fort Leonard Wood, where I was the hospital administrator for the Community Medicine Division of the General Leonard Wood Army Community Hospital.
I am thankful for the opportunity that I had to serve our country in the Army. Through that experience I learned firsthand how military hospitals work and saw know the unique challenges to providing health care in a military setting.</description></item><item><title>Navy hospital medical malpractice cases</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/navy-hospital-medical-malpractice-cases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/navy-hospital-medical-malpractice-cases/</guid><description>One of the great things about serving in the U.S. Navy, Army, Marines, or Air Force is the sense of community. Both service members and dependents pull through a lot of challenges and tough times knowing that they are not alone.
Unfortunately, when medical malpractice happens in a Navy, Army, or Air Force hospital, the victims often feel isolated. In a culture where hopes of promotion are pinned on perfect performance reviews, the brass does not usually encourage open talk or investigation of what went wrong when someone is needlessly injured or dies as a result of poor health care on base or on post.</description></item></channel></rss>