<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Attorneys on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/attorneys/</link><description>Recent content in Attorneys on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/attorneys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://painterfirm.com/attorneys/robert-painter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/attorneys/robert-painter/</guid><description>Robert Painter is a former hospital administrator. As an attorney, he focuses on getting justice for patients and family members who’ve experienced life-changing injuries or wrongful death because of medical malpractice.
Robert has always been interested in health care. He started his graduate education in medical school and was awarded a full scholarship from the U.S. Army. Midway through medical school, he worried about the direction of health care in America and decided that he could have a more positive impact for patient safety in health law.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://painterfirm.com/attorneys/taunya-painter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/attorneys/taunya-painter/</guid><description>Taunya Painter, a lawyer and member of Painter Law Firm PLLC, was recognized by H Texas Magazine as one of the Top Lawyers in Houston from 2011-2021. She has significant business and transactional experience with large and small companies, in both domestic and international matters.
Before practicing law in Texas, Mrs. Painter was an attorney and Director of International Trade for Wal-Mart Stores, Inc., in Bentonville, Arkansas. While there, she oversaw the legal work to form the global sourcing and direct buying operations, and helped shape domestic and international strategy regarding supplier relations, countries of production, tariffs and sustainability.</description></item></channel></rss>