<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>christus on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/christus/</link><description>Recent content in christus on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/christus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Christus Santa Rosa Hospital San Antonio medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/christus-santa-rosa-hospital-san-antonio-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/christus-santa-rosa-hospital-san-antonio-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>As a medical malpractice attorney based in Houston, Texas, I handle lawsuits all over the State of Texas, including in the San Antonio area.
Christus Santa Rosa Health System, in the San Antonio area
The Christus Santa Rosa Health System is a division of Christus Health. It traces its roots to 1869, and, as a whole, has 1,159 licensed hospital beds and five full-service hospitals.
The Christus Santa Rosa Health System includes The Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital of San Antonio, Christus Santa Rosa Hospital Alamo Heights, Christus Santa Rosa Hospital Medical Center, Christus Santa Rosa Hospital New Braunfels, Christus Santa Rosa Hospital Westover Hills, Christus Santa Rosa Emergency Center Alon, Christus Santa Rosa Emergency Center Bandera, Christus Santa Rosa Emergency Center Creekside, Christus Transplant Institute, and Christus Santa Rosa Physicians Ambulatory Surgery Centers.</description></item><item><title>Christus Spohn Hospital Corpus Christi—Shoreline medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/christus-spohn-hospital-corpus-christi%C3%A2shoreline-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/christus-spohn-hospital-corpus-christi%C3%A2shoreline-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm is based in Houston, Texas, and handles medical malpractice and wrongful death claims throughout the Houston area and the State of Texas, including Corpus Christi.
Christus Spohn Hospital Corpus Christi&amp;mdash;Shoreline, located at 600 Elizabeth Street, Corpus Christi, TX 78404, is part of the large nonprofit Christus hospital chain. This hospital advertises itself as the largest and foremost acute-care Medical Center in South Texas. It offers surgical services including back, spine, orthopedic, bone, joint, neurosurgery, robotic, cardiac/heart, colorectal, gynecological, thoracic, and urological.</description></item><item><title>Christus St. Elizabeth Hospital Beaumont medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/christus-st.-elizabeth-hospital-beaumont-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/christus-st.-elizabeth-hospital-beaumont-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>Christus St. Elizabeth Hospital (Christus Southeast Texas&amp;mdash;St. Elizabeth Hospital), located at 2830 Calder St., Beaumont, Texas 77702, is a 431-bed hospital owned by Christus Southeast Texas, based in Beaumont.
The hospital provides healthcare in a variety of areas, including emergency medicine (emergency room) and Level III trauma center, labor and deliver, birthing, neonatal care, spine and orthopedic surgery, general surgery, bariatric surgery, cardiology, oncology (cancer), and critical care. The Joint Commission has designated Christus St.</description></item></channel></rss>