<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>podiatry on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/podiatry/</link><description>Recent content in podiatry on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/podiatry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The most common medical malpractice claims against podiatrists</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-most-common-medical-malpractice-claims-against-podiatrists/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-most-common-medical-malpractice-claims-against-podiatrists/</guid><description>Podiatry is a field of medicine and surgery that has the unusual distinction that its practitioners, called podiatrists, do not actually attend medical school. This does not mean that they do not have extensive training, though.
Podiatrists attend podiatry school, which focuses on the diagnosis and treatment of conditions of the foot and ankle. When podiatrists graduate from podiatry school, they are not awarded the familiar &amp;ldquo;MD degree.&amp;rdquo; Instead, they are conferred a &amp;ldquo;DPM,&amp;rdquo; which means a doctor of podiatric medicine.</description></item><item><title>What are podiatrists, and what’s podiatric medical malpractice in Texas?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-are-podiatrists-and-what%C3%A2s-podiatric-medical-malpractice-in-texas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-are-podiatrists-and-what%C3%A2s-podiatric-medical-malpractice-in-texas/</guid><description>Most people don&amp;rsquo;t think much about their feet until something goes wrong with them.
I certainly fell into that category until spring break 2018, when I developed Achilles tendinitis after hiking up Pocaya Volcano in Guatemala. The pain was so intense that it felt like an ice pick was getting jammed into the back of my ankle.
After thinking it would get better after a few days, I did some research on what type of doctor I should see to make sure there wasn&amp;rsquo;t a permanent injury (fortunately there wasn&amp;rsquo;t).</description></item></channel></rss>