<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Client Reviews: Trusted Feedback on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/reviews/</link><description>Recent content in Client Reviews: Trusted Feedback on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Educated and compassionate staff</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/reviews/educated-and-compassionate-staff/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/reviews/educated-and-compassionate-staff/</guid><description>Excelente servicio, todo el personal muy amable y atentos en todo ,lo recomiendo mucho, gracias por su servicio. (English Translation: Excellent service, all the staff are very friendly and attentive to everything, I highly recommend it, thank you for your service.)&amp;ndash; Griselda Rodriguez
Very easy process, keeps me informed of all actions being taken and really knowledgeable on my type of situation.&amp;ndash; Tyler Brown
Wonderful experience. Educated and compassionate staff.</description></item><item><title>He fought for me and the injustice of the situation with extreme passion</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/reviews/fights-injustice-with-extreme-passion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/reviews/fights-injustice-with-extreme-passion/</guid><description>Robert Painter of the Painter Law Firm was absolutely brilliant! My case became very complex but Mr. Painter strategized and executed the plan with precision and perfection to the point he was able to head off potential downfalls and we were prepared. He fought for me and the injustice of the situation with extreme passion. It was impressive to watch him quickly use case law to combat the defendants arguments and objections with his knowledge of the law.</description></item><item><title>Help for my Special Needs son</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/reviews/help-for-my-special-needs-son/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/reviews/help-for-my-special-needs-son/</guid><description>I highly recommend The Painter Law firm. From the initial appointment, I felt comfortable with the staff and the compassion they exuded for my Special Needs son. I appreciate the monthly updates concerning our case. If you have any questions or concerns, they will do their due diligence to respond with an answer. Mr. Painter is so easy to speak with, and he shows a genuine interest in your case.</description></item><item><title>Kindness, Respect and Sympathy</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/reviews/kindness-sympathy-respect/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/reviews/kindness-sympathy-respect/</guid><description>The Painter Law Firm has been thorough, professional, and understanding throughout the entire process of my case. Mr. Painter, Kara, and Julie have kept me informed along the way and have all demonstrated a great deal of kindness, respect, and sympathy toward me from the moment we met. I am very glad to have found them, and I highly recommend their firm in the unfortunate event that you might need personal injury legal assistance.</description></item><item><title>Very personal, professional and attentive to the details</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/reviews/personal-professional-and-attentive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/reviews/personal-professional-and-attentive/</guid><description>Mr. Painter was very personal and professional and attentive to all the details. I highly recommended him, and would use him again. The staff was very professional and friendly, as well. My questions and concerns were always responded to immediately.&amp;ndash; Sinola Sam
A great lawyer who comes highly recommended. Robert is a knowledgeable professional who works diligently for his clients, remaining available to address any concerns. The office is both pleasant and efficiently run, accommodating client interaction.</description></item></channel></rss>