<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>birth on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/birth/</link><description>Recent content in birth on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/birth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Obstetrician office nurse bungles patient call, baby born with brain damage</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/obstetrician-office-nurse-bungles-patient-call-baby-born-with-brain-damage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/obstetrician-office-nurse-bungles-patient-call-baby-born-with-brain-damage/</guid><description>One afternoon, a woman in her late 20s was shopping with her husband in Sugar Land, Texas. She was 32 weeks into her pregnancy with their first child. When she went to the restroom, she noticed some blood in her urine, so they went straight to a local hospital for her to get checked out.
She told the hospital&amp;rsquo;s Labor and Delivery Department nursing staff how her stomach had been tightening for a few weeks.</description></item><item><title>Postpartum hemorrhage is a dangerous risk for moms after delivering a baby</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/postpartum-hemorrhage-is-a-dangerous-risk-for-moms-after-delivering-a-baby/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/postpartum-hemorrhage-is-a-dangerous-risk-for-moms-after-delivering-a-baby/</guid><description>Postpartum hemorrhage (vaginal bleeding of the mother after giving birth that does not slow or stop) is one of the leading causes of injury and death for mothers after pregnancy. In the United States, the rate of this potentially deadly condition increased by 26% between 1994 and 2006.
This condition is dangerous because women can lose huge amounts of blood extremely quickly because of the changes to their metabolism and physiology during pregnancy.</description></item><item><title>How to prevent birth injuries and death during labor &amp; delivery</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-prevent-birth-injuries-and-death-during-labor-delivery/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-prevent-birth-injuries-and-death-during-labor-delivery/</guid><description>As a father of four who has been in the hospital room for every minute of each labor and delivery, I know that having a baby is one of the most exciting and precious events that anyone can experience.
We all have seen the preparations that would-be parents undertake to prepare for the new baby&amp;rsquo;s arrival&amp;ndash;choosing the perfect name, going to baby showers, painting and furnishing the nursery, stocking up on supplies, and selecting that special outfit the baby will wear when leaving the hospital.</description></item><item><title>Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney Robert Painter video: Watch fetal movements &amp; prevent brain injury</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-video-watch-fetal-movements-prevent-brain-injury/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-video-watch-fetal-movements-prevent-brain-injury/</guid><description>One of most rewarding things about helping people as an attorney in the area of medical malpractice is I get to learn a lot about narrow areas of medicine as they relate to the law. One of the areas where I spend a lot on time is cases is brain injuries and, in particular, the tragedies of brain injured babies. And as a father of four, these types of injuries are particularly bothersome to me.</description></item><item><title>How mothers can prevent infant brain injuries during birth</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-mothers-can-prevent-infant-brain-injuries-during-birth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-mothers-can-prevent-infant-brain-injuries-during-birth/</guid><description>One of the interesting things about a law practice focusing on medical malpractice cases is that I get to study and learn a lot about the medical issues surrounding my cases. I have handled a lot of cases involving brain injuries, including birth-related brain injuries. In many of those cases, the pregnancy was normal and the baby was healthy right until the very end. This is one of a series of articles I will share on how many of these permanent brain injuries could have been avoided with proper medical and nursing care.</description></item><item><title>Painter Law Firm wins medical malpractice settlement of $3,925,000</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-wins-medical-malpractice-settlement-of-3925000/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-wins-medical-malpractice-settlement-of-3925000/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm attorney Robert Painter recently settled a Houston medical malpractice lawsuit for $3,925,000. We cannot identify the defendants because of a confidentiality agreement.
We represented a teenager who sustained a permanent, severely-disabling brain injury at a hospital after she developed hyponatremia while in the hospital.
Hyponatremia is a condition where a person develops a low serum sodium level. It is fairly common among runners who get dehydrated. In a hospital setting, it can be life-threatening.</description></item></channel></rss>