<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>radiology on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/radiology/</link><description>Recent content in radiology on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/radiology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1 question to ask before your CT or MRI scan</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/1-question-to-ask-before-your-ct-or-mri-scan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/1-question-to-ask-before-your-ct-or-mri-scan/</guid><description>A man&amp;ndash;we&amp;rsquo;ll call him Mitch&amp;ndash;walked into an outpatient imaging center to have a CT scan. Within two hours, he was dead.
We represent Mitch&amp;rsquo;s wife and children in a wrongful death medical malpractice lawsuit.
How is it that an otherwise healthy, middle-aged man who has suspected kidney stones dies from a CT scan?
What are CT and MRI scans?
CT and MRI are two types of diagnostic radiology scans.
Doctors and surgeons order diagnostic radiology scans so they can have images of internal structures and conditions.</description></item><item><title>Outpatient imaging centers and the increased risk of brain injury or death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/outpatient-imaging-centers-and-the-increased-risk-of-brain-injury-or-death/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/outpatient-imaging-centers-and-the-increased-risk-of-brain-injury-or-death/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a tragic case involving the death of a middle-aged man who went for a routine CT scan for contrast at an outpatient imaging center in the Dallas area. His primary care doctor referred him there because of suspected kidney stones.
The autopsy revealed that this father and husband died from an anaphylactic reaction to the iodine-containing CT contrast media that a CT technologist administered to him intravenously (by IV) shortly before his CT scan.</description></item><item><title>Dallas wrongful death lawsuit alleges misdiagnosis of necrotizing pancreatitis</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-wrongful-death-lawsuit-alleges-misdiagnosis-of-necrotizing-pancreatitis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-wrongful-death-lawsuit-alleges-misdiagnosis-of-necrotizing-pancreatitis/</guid><description>The Dallas Court of Appeals recently entered an opinion that highlights the risks to patient safety when physicians stop short in working up a condition or illness. The case is styled Harsha Aramada, MD, Tomi Ola-Peters MD, Uzoeshi Anukam, MD, Sado Al Bita, MD, Saurabh Patel, MD, and Chandand Koduro, MD v. Yates; No. 05-20-00960-CV. You can read the opinion here.
This medical malpractice wrongful death case arose from care provided to the patient at Methodist Mansfield Hospital.</description></item><item><title>Lawsuit: Infant dies after nurse practitioner fails to tell family about spot that's suspicious for cancer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-infant-dies-after-nurse-practitioner-fails-to-tell-family-about-spot-thats-suspicious-for-cancer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-infant-dies-after-nurse-practitioner-fails-to-tell-family-about-spot-thats-suspicious-for-cancer/</guid><description>A wrongful death medical malpractice lawsuit recently filed in Maryland illustrates the life-and-death dangers of poor health care communication.
The case arises from the death of a two-year-old little girl.
She was born at the prestigious Johns Hopkins Hospital and then admitted to the hospital&amp;rsquo;s neonatal intensive care unit (NICU).
A nurse practitioner working in the NICU became aware of ultrasound findings of a cyst-like mass on the baby&amp;rsquo;s right adrenal gland.</description></item><item><title>What you should know about mediastinal masses</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-mediastinal-masses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-mediastinal-masses/</guid><description>When a physician tells a patient that he or she suspects a mediastinal mass, the first question that many people ask is, &amp;ldquo;What is the mediastinum?&amp;rdquo;
Mediastinum is in the chest, specifically the area that is between the lungs. It&amp;rsquo;s actually pretty large area&amp;mdash;I vividly remember gross anatomy during my first year of medical school and how surprised I was to see the large size of the lungs. The mediastinum contains the heart, esophagus, trachea (windpipe) and the large blood vessels going to heart.</description></item><item><title>What neuroradiologists look for to identify hypoxic-ischemic brain injury</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-neuroradiologists-look-for-to-identify-hypoxic-ischemic-brain-injury/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-neuroradiologists-look-for-to-identify-hypoxic-ischemic-brain-injury/</guid><description>When there&amp;rsquo;s a suspicion or confirmation that a newborn infant has a brain injury, it&amp;rsquo;s common for a neonatologist or physician to order an MRI scan of the brain. This is the diagnostic radiology study of choice for determining the basic cause and timing of the serious brain injury.
One devastating type of newborn brain injury is hypoxic-ischemic encephalopathy (HIE).
HIE is the description for a medical condition that occurs when the brain doesn&amp;rsquo;t get sufficient oxygen and blood flow.</description></item><item><title>Breast cancer misdiagnosis claim against Texas radiologist</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/breast-cancer-misdiagnosis-claim-against-texas-radiologist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/breast-cancer-misdiagnosis-claim-against-texas-radiologist/</guid><description>The San Antonio Court of Appeals recently entered an important opinion in a breast cancer misdiagnosis case where the defendant radiologist challenged the sufficiency of the patient&amp;rsquo;s preliminary expert report. The case is styled Mark Healy, MD v. Orinda Mowa-Cudd, 04-20-00479-CV, San Antonio Court of Appeals (2/17/21) you can read the opinion here.
The plaintiff&amp;rsquo;s allegations are straightforward.
In 2018, radiologist Dr. Healy reviewed a mammogram of the plaintiff, compared it to her 2016 mammogram, and concluded that it showed no suspicion for malignancy.</description></item><item><title>Jury awards $10.8 million in MRI contrast anaphylaxis brain injury case</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/jury-awards-10.8-million-in-mri-contrast-anaphylaxis-brain-injury-case/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/jury-awards-10.8-million-in-mri-contrast-anaphylaxis-brain-injury-case/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine that having a CT or MRI scan with contrast could cause a patient to die or have a disabling injury.
Sure, there has been concerns that have been reported and discussed about the long-term additive effect of radiation exposure from CT scans. However, that&amp;rsquo;s not what I&amp;rsquo;m referencing, though.
I&amp;rsquo;m talking about going in for a diagnostic radiology scan and having a permanent brain injury or being deceased just an hour later.</description></item><item><title>Botched radiology reports, passive clinical doctors lead to errors in diagnosis</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/botched-radiology-reports-passive-clinical-doctors-lead-to-errors-in-diagnosis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/botched-radiology-reports-passive-clinical-doctors-lead-to-errors-in-diagnosis/</guid><description>Radiologists are physicians with specialized training in the interpretation of diagnostic scans including x-rays, CT scans, MRI scans, and other forms of imaging. They do not see or evaluate patients in person. Instead, their medical practice is focused on reviewing images on a computer screen, often off-site and away from the hospital.
In contrast, clinical physicians, including specialties such as&amp;nbsp;emergency medicine, hospitalist medicine, internal medicine, neurology, and surgical specialties, actually see patients in person, interview them for a medical&amp;nbsp;history, and order tests and studies to put together the complete picture of what&amp;rsquo;s causing the patient&amp;rsquo;s problems.</description></item><item><title>What can the trial court consider at a Chapter 74 preliminary expert report hearing in a Texas medical malpractice case?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-can-the-trial-court-consider-at-a-chapter-74-preliminary-expert-report-hearing-in-a-texas-medical-malpractice-case/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-can-the-trial-court-consider-at-a-chapter-74-preliminary-expert-report-hearing-in-a-texas-medical-malpractice-case/</guid><description>Texas law requires medical malpractice plaintiffs to produce one or more medical expert reports within 120 days of each defendant filing an answer and a lawsuit. The standards for these reports are demanding, requiring separate statements of the applicable standard of care (what should have been done), how the standard of care was violated (what wasn&amp;rsquo;t done correctly), and how those medical mistakes proximately caused harm to the plaintiff.
How do defendants respond to the preliminary expert reports, and what are the potential consequences?</description></item><item><title>Radiology follow through and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/radiology-follow-through-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/radiology-follow-through-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>Where I grew up, basketball is a big deal. The high school basketball coach would go to elementary school games as a sort of scout for future team members. During the summers, he hosted basketball camps at the local YMCA to teach basic skills.
Needless to say, this coach was pretty intense. One of the things that he pounded into us over and over was the need to follow through when making a shot.</description></item><item><title>Insurance companies steer patients to freestanding imaging centers, but are they safe?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/insurance-companies-steer-patients-to-freestanding-imaging-centers-but-are-they-safe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/insurance-companies-steer-patients-to-freestanding-imaging-centers-but-are-they-safe/</guid><description>There is a clear trend going on in American healthcare. Day by day, there&amp;rsquo;s an erosion of healthcare decision-making out of the hands of patients, and even their doctors. Control is being wrestled away by Medicare and insurance companies who are more concerned about cost savings and profitability than patient safety.
As a former hospital administrator, I know that this isn&amp;rsquo;t a new trend and it&amp;rsquo;s one that&amp;rsquo;s affected all types of healthcare.</description></item><item><title>Artificial intelligence may enhance radiology interpretation</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/artificial-intelligence-may-enhance-radiology-interpretation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/artificial-intelligence-may-enhance-radiology-interpretation/</guid><description>A major focus in medical research is how to apply artificial intelligence (AI) as a safety net to the interpretation of diagnostic radiology scans by radiologists.
Radiologists are doctors with specialized training after medical school focused on how to interpret a variety of diagnostic radiological studies including x-rays, CT scans, MRI scans, and angiograms. Neuroradiologists have additional training focused on interpreting images of the brain and nervous system.
The most frequent allegation in medical malpractice claims against radiologists and neuroradiologists is that the interpretation was botched.</description></item><item><title>The questions you should ask before getting a CT or MRI scan at a stand-alone imaging center</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-questions-you-should-ask-before-getting-a-ct-or-mri-scan-at-a-stand-alone-imaging-center/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-questions-you-should-ask-before-getting-a-ct-or-mri-scan-at-a-stand-alone-imaging-center/</guid><description>It wasn&amp;rsquo;t long ago that if you needed to have a diagnostic radiology scan, such as an MRI or CT, then your only choice was to do it in a hospital. These days, though, there&amp;rsquo;s the option of having scans done at a freestanding imaging facility.
Here at Painter Law Firm, we&amp;rsquo;ve had numerous clients tell us that the doctor ordering a scan presents the option something like this: &amp;ldquo;We can schedule the scan at an imaging facility where it will cost you $800, or at a hospital where it may cost you $2,000.</description></item><item><title>Surgeons &amp; operating room nurses shouldn't leave surgical items inside patients after a procedure</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/surgeons-operating-room-nurses-shouldnt-leave-surgical-items-inside-patients-after-a-procedure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/surgeons-operating-room-nurses-shouldnt-leave-surgical-items-inside-patients-after-a-procedure/</guid><description>It seems pretty obvious.
When the operating room (OR) team performs a surgery on a patient, the surgeons and nurses shouldn&amp;rsquo;t leave items in the patient&amp;rsquo;s body.
As a former hospital administrator, I know that hospital accrediting organizations, such as The Joint Commission, refer to these situations as &amp;ldquo;never events.&amp;rdquo; Yet, in my experience, they happen a lot more frequently than you might think. In fact, the medical community has come up with a preferred term, &amp;ldquo;retained surgical item&amp;rdquo; (RSI) to try and obscure what they&amp;rsquo;re talking about.</description></item><item><title>What you should know about the common mistakes involving radiology scans</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-the-common-mistakes-involving-radiology-scans/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-the-common-mistakes-involving-radiology-scans/</guid><description>When doctors, physician&amp;rsquo;s assistants, or nurse practitioners order a diagnostic radiology study, such as an MRI or CT scan, it&amp;rsquo;s based on a clinical indication.
The clinical indication on a radiology order is important
The clinical indication refers to the clinical situation that&amp;rsquo;s the reason for the study&amp;nbsp;and is typically the only clinical information that&amp;rsquo;s provided to the radiologist.
For example, if a patient arrived at the emergency room (ER) with symptoms that make the physician suspect stroke, the clinical indication may be &amp;ldquo;stroke.</description></item><item><title>Study uncovers the most common diagnostic errors by radiologists</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/study-uncovers-the-most-common-diagnostic-errors-by-radiologists/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/study-uncovers-the-most-common-diagnostic-errors-by-radiologists/</guid><description>Radiologists are physicians with advanced training in the interpretation of diagnostic radiology studies such as MRI and CT scans. They rarely, if ever, see a patient face to face and aren&amp;rsquo;t typically involved in making treatment decisions. In fact, they might even review radiology images from a remote location rather than in the hospital.
When a clinical physician, such as an internal medicine doctor, hospitalist, surgeon, or neurologist, orders a radiology scan, they usually provide a brief explanation of the reason for the order.</description></item><item><title>Medical malpractice wrongful death lawsuit: Routine CT scan with contrast ends in death at Gateway Diagnostic Imaging, LLC d/b/a Gateway Diagnostic Mid-Cities</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medical-malpractice-wrongful-death-lawsuit-routine-ct-scan-with-contrast-ends-in-death-at-gateway-diagnostic-imaging-llc-d/b/a-gateway-diagnostic-mid-cities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medical-malpractice-wrongful-death-lawsuit-routine-ct-scan-with-contrast-ends-in-death-at-gateway-diagnostic-imaging-llc-d/b/a-gateway-diagnostic-mid-cities/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm filed a medical malpractice wrongful death lawsuit yesterday against Gateway Diagnostic Imaging, LLC d/b/a Gateway Diagnostic Mid-Cities and three physicians arising from the death of a healthy 52-year-old man following a CT scan of the abdomen and pelvis for suspected kidney stones.
The case is pending in the 101st District Court of Dallas County, Texas, where the presiding judge is The Hon. Staci Williams. You can read the original petition here.</description></item><item><title>Are freestanding outpatient imaging centers as safe as hospitals for MRI or CT scans?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/are-freestanding-outpatient-imaging-centers-as-safe-as-hospitals-for-mri-or-ct-scans/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/are-freestanding-outpatient-imaging-centers-as-safe-as-hospitals-for-mri-or-ct-scans/</guid><description>Independent, outpatient, and ambulatory radiology/imaging centers offer an alternative to having an x-ray, MRI, or CT scan performed in a hospital setting. These types of facilities often advertise like a realtor&amp;mdash;location, location, location. Outpatient imaging centers are all over the place and are certainly convenient for many patients.
Plus, there&amp;rsquo;s the cost issue. This has become a big bone of contention between health insurance companies and hospitals, which charge more for the same scans than do freestanding imaging facilities.</description></item><item><title>A CT scan with barium contrast is risky for patients who recently had any abdominal surgery</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/a-ct-scan-with-barium-contrast-is-risky-for-patients-who-recently-had-any-abdominal-surgery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/a-ct-scan-with-barium-contrast-is-risky-for-patients-who-recently-had-any-abdominal-surgery/</guid><description>When a doctor orders a CT scan or MRI scan, it can be with contrast or without contrast. If the diagnostic radiology scan is to be done with contrast, it means that the patient will be asked to swallow some contrast media, or in some cases have it injected, because it will help with identifying the specific things the doctor is looking for.
For most patients, dealing with contrast isn&amp;rsquo;t a big deal.</description></item><item><title>Does your doctor treat your radiology scan rather than you?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/does-your-doctor-treat-your-radiology-scan-rather-than-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/does-your-doctor-treat-your-radiology-scan-rather-than-you/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s a problem in healthcare that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen more often over the past few years, in my practice as a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney at Painter Law Firm. It&amp;rsquo;s the problem of doctors wanting to treat a CT scan instead of a patient sitting right in front of them. To be fair, I could make the same comment about an MRI scan or even some types of lab work.</description></item><item><title>A year and a half after ER doesn't inform patient of x-ray finding, man dies of cancer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/a-year-and-a-half-after-er-doesnt-inform-patient-of-x-ray-finding-man-dies-of-cancer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/a-year-and-a-half-after-er-doesnt-inform-patient-of-x-ray-finding-man-dies-of-cancer/</guid><description>A recent case shows why I think it&amp;rsquo;s important for patients to get a physical copy of any lab work, pathology study, or radiology tests ordered as a part of their healthcare. If it&amp;rsquo;s important enough to order, it&amp;rsquo;s important enough for the patient to know the results.
A 48 year old man went to a hospital emergency room (ER) after a two-day bout of productive coughing, congestion, and shortness of breath.</description></item><item><title>Radiologist and doctors didn't inform patient about suspicious bladder mass, leading to extensive cancer, $8+ million jury verdict</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/radiologist-and-doctors-didnt-inform-patient-about-suspicious-bladder-mass-leading-to-extensive-cancer-8-million-jury-verdict/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/radiologist-and-doctors-didnt-inform-patient-about-suspicious-bladder-mass-leading-to-extensive-cancer-8-million-jury-verdict/</guid><description>A Pennsylvania jury recently awarded a couple over $8 million in a medical malpractice case involving botched communication of the results of a CT scan. The jury found that the lack of communication led to development of extensive bladder cancer, which could have been avoided if the physicians involved had informed the patient about it.
It all started when the patient (the husband) went to a hospital emergency room (ER) because of right-sided flank and abdominal pain and urinary problems.</description></item><item><title>MRI contrast anaphylactic reactions are rare, but potentially deadly</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/mri-contrast-anaphylactic-reactions-are-rare-but-potentially-deadly/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/mri-contrast-anaphylactic-reactions-are-rare-but-potentially-deadly/</guid><description>I recently wrote an article about CT scans and how some patients experience a reaction or dangerous anaphylaxis to the iodine contrast medium that is sometimes used. Afterwards, some people emailed or messaged to ask me if something similar can happen with MRI scans done under contrast.
The short answer is &amp;ldquo;yes,&amp;rdquo; but it&amp;rsquo;s less common.
Gadolinium as a contrast medium
There are about 40 million MRI scans performed each year in the United States.</description></item><item><title>CT scan iodine contrast reaction, anaphylaxis, and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/ct-scan-iodine-contrast-reaction-anaphylaxis-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/ct-scan-iodine-contrast-reaction-anaphylaxis-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>Diagnostic radiology imaging, like CT and MRI scans, are common in the United States. Each year, there are around 80 million CT scans alone in our nation of 327 million people.
Both CT and MRI scans can be ordered with or without contrast. Based on my experience as a former hospital administrator and a long-time Texas medical malpractice attorney, there are some important considerations about CT contrast agents that I think every patient should be aware of.</description></item><item><title>Texas woman dies from botched arteriogram x-ray study</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-woman-dies-from-botched-arteriogram-x-ray-study/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-woman-dies-from-botched-arteriogram-x-ray-study/</guid><description>A grieving son recently called Painter Law Firm for help and to answers about how his mother died at a hospital in Laredo, Texas. As is often the case when something bad happens at a hospital, doctors and administrators are tight-lipped.
He shared with me that his mother was in her 70s and had a past medical history of diabetes, renal failure, and atherosclerosis (build-up on the walls of the arteries).</description></item><item><title>What happens when a doctor orders an MRI or CT scan and cancels it before it’s done?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-happens-when-a-doctor-orders-an-mri-or-ct-scan-and-cancels-it-before-it%C3%A2s-done/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-happens-when-a-doctor-orders-an-mri-or-ct-scan-and-cancels-it-before-it%C3%A2s-done/</guid><description>What happens when a doctor orders an MRI or CT scan and cancels it before it&amp;rsquo;s done?
This is the exact question I investigated on behalf of a client who had a back surgery (lumbar laminectomy) at a Houston-area hospital.
Within a day or two after his surgery, the nursing staff noted in the medical record that he had lower-extremity weakness, urinary retention (he wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to urinate), numbness below the waist, and a bad headache.</description></item><item><title>Waco, Texas surgeon orders wrong radiology study, woman dies from gastric perforation and sepsis</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/waco-texas-surgeon-orders-wrong-radiology-study-woman-dies-from-gastric-perforation-and-sepsis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/waco-texas-surgeon-orders-wrong-radiology-study-woman-dies-from-gastric-perforation-and-sepsis/</guid><description>Time after time, I&amp;rsquo;m confronted with the problem of doctors treating a computer screen instead of the patient. Yesterday, that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I was thinking as I took the deposition of a Waco, Texas general surgeon in a medical malpractice wrongful death case.
The facts underlying that case are sad. An elderly lady who lived independently was suffering from gastric reflux and saw a surgeon. The surgeon diagnosed her with a hiatal hernia.</description></item><item><title>Three mistakes radiologists make when reading a CT, MRI, or scan</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-mistakes-radiologists-make-when-reading-a-ct-mri-or-scan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-mistakes-radiologists-make-when-reading-a-ct-mri-or-scan/</guid><description>Radiologists are the sixth most common type of physician to be sued in a medical malpractice case. In cases that end up in court, the most common claim is errors in diagnosis. Of those errors, the most frequently missed diagnoses involved breast cancer, lung cancer, and bone fractures.
Radiologists are specially trained to interpret all kinds of diagnostic imaging, from x-rays to CT scans, from MRIs to angiograms. Neuroradiologists have additional training to interpret studies involving the brain.</description></item><item><title>Hiatal hernia surgery leads to woman's death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/hiatal-hernia-surgery-leads-to-womans-death/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/hiatal-hernia-surgery-leads-to-womans-death/</guid><description>When a patient has gastrointestinal (GI) problems, physicians and surgeons often use diagnostic radiology studies to help them identify the problem. Unfortunately, some doctors rely so much on radiology images that they forget about the patient right in front of them.
Common GI complaints include abdominal pain, difficulty swallowing, nausea and vomiting, and just an overall difficulty in keeping food or liquids down. These types of symptoms can develop on their own, or after an abdominal surgery like a hiatal hernia repair or bariatric procedure.</description></item><item><title>Woman loses spleen, parts of stomach, and pancreas after surgeon mistakenly overrules radiologist</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/woman-loses-spleen-parts-of-stomach-and-pancreas-after-surgeon-mistakenly-overrules-radiologist/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/woman-loses-spleen-parts-of-stomach-and-pancreas-after-surgeon-mistakenly-overrules-radiologist/</guid><description>I spent yesterday in Waco, Texas, taking the deposition of a vascular surgeon that we sued on behalf of a client of Painter Law Firm for botching the evaluation, management, and surgical repair of an abdominal aneurysm.
The surgeon materially disagreed with a lot of the findings of an interventional radiologist who interpreted an abdominal CT angiogram of the patient that identified a celiac artery aneurysm. The disagreements include:
&amp;bull; Radiologist: Non-emergent, Surgeon: Emergent</description></item><item><title>Radiologist and urologist don't talk, man isn't treated for cancer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/radiologist-and-urologist-dont-talk-man-isnt-treated-for-cancer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/radiologist-and-urologist-dont-talk-man-isnt-treated-for-cancer/</guid><description>One of the things I see over and over as a Houston, Texas, medical malpractice attorney is how important information can fall through the cracks in medicine.
For instance, a man went to see a urologist because he was having pain between his ribs and hips (the flank area). The doctor thought it was likely a kidney stone but ordered an abdominal CT scan just to be sure.
A radiologist interpreted the CT scan and, sure enough, found the kidney stone.</description></item><item><title>Radiology malpractice: The danger of interpreting a CT or MRI without talking to anyone about the patient</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/radiology-malpractice-the-danger-of-interpreting-a-ct-or-mri-without-talking-to-anyone-about-the-patient/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/radiology-malpractice-the-danger-of-interpreting-a-ct-or-mri-without-talking-to-anyone-about-the-patient/</guid><description>I am working on a medical malpractice case now where one of the defendants is a neuroradiologist whom we believe misread a head CT scan. As a result, a patient was misdiagnosed and discharged home only to have a stroke a few hours later.
As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, in this case, as in all medical negligence cases, I retained relevant medical experts to review the records and provide opinions.</description></item><item><title>Patients are endangered when clinical and ER doctors do not communicate with radiologists</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/patients-are-endangered-when-clinical-and-er-doctors-do-not-communicate-with-radiologists/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/patients-are-endangered-when-clinical-and-er-doctors-do-not-communicate-with-radiologists/</guid><description>I recently read the results of an online survey conducted by a physician group that looks at ways to prevent medical malpractice. As a former hospital administrator, I love to see healthcare providers taking a proactive approach, like this, that can improve patient safety.
The survey dealt with whether emergency room (ER) physicians review diagnostic imaging studies, like x-rays, CT scans, and MRIs.
madmimi.com/p/be23fb
While this rather informal survey was not intended to be scientifically or statistically valid, the results &amp;nbsp;were interesting to me, based on my experience in handling many cases involving radiologists and other physicians missing significant findings on radiology studies.</description></item><item><title>Doctor, nurse practitioner ignore MRI results for two years, woman dies of cancer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/doctor-nurse-practitioner-ignore-mri-results-for-two-years-woman-dies-of-cancer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/doctor-nurse-practitioner-ignore-mri-results-for-two-years-woman-dies-of-cancer/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, many of the lawsuits that I handle for patients and family members involve a failure of communication. &amp;nbsp;This type of medical error usually occurs when there is a hand-off from one healthcare provider to another.
Think about it. &amp;nbsp;The provision of modern health care involves a lot of different players including, doctors, specialists, nurses, laboratory techs, radiologists, and pathologists. &amp;nbsp;When one healthcare provider refers an order or consultation to another provider, poor systems allow results to get lost in the shuffle.</description></item><item><title>High school senior dies after doctors botch diagnosis and treatment of acute disseminated encephalomalacia (ADEM)</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/high-school-senior-dies-after-doctors-botch-diagnosis-and-treatment-of-acute-disseminated-encephalomalacia-adem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/high-school-senior-dies-after-doctors-botch-diagnosis-and-treatment-of-acute-disseminated-encephalomalacia-adem/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, every day my law firm hears tragic stories from clients&amp;nbsp;about how lives were changed or ended because of poor medical care.
This week, we met with new clients about a terribly sad situation. Let me tell you their story.
One morning, the parents of a Houston-area high school senior found her on the floor in a room, nauseated and unable to get up or walk.</description></item><item><title>Why it is important for radiologists to review all recent similar CT and MRI images</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/why-it-is-important-for-radiologists-to-review-all-recent-similar-ct-and-mri-images/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/why-it-is-important-for-radiologists-to-review-all-recent-similar-ct-and-mri-images/</guid><description>In my law practice as a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I take a lot of depositions of doctors and nurses. Depositions are an important part of almost every civil lawsuit.
A deposition is basically a meeting where an attorney can ask a party or witness in the lawsuit questions under oath in front of a court reporter, with all of the other attorneys present. It is typically not done in the courthouse, but rather in an attorney&amp;rsquo;s office.</description></item><item><title>X-rays and CT scans: Radiation risk and malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/x-rays-and-ct-scans-radiation-risk-and-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/x-rays-and-ct-scans-radiation-risk-and-malpractice/</guid><description>In most of the cases that I handle, in my career as a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, patients have had some type of radiology study. It could be an x-ray, CT scan, MRI scan, or other study.
While radiology studies are often helpful when it comes to diagnosing a patient, there is an increasing debate in the medical community about the over-use and reliance on imaging. The concern is that doctors should not order radiology studies when it is possible to make a diagnosis without them.</description></item><item><title>What happens when critical lab or radiology results are not communicated to the doctor</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-happens-when-critical-lab-or-radiology-results-are-not-communicated-to-the-doctor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-happens-when-critical-lab-or-radiology-results-are-not-communicated-to-the-doctor/</guid><description>I focus my Houston, Texas-based law practice on representing patients and family members in medical malpractice cases. This gives me an opportunity to see trends in medical errors generally, as well as bad outcomes that happen over and over again at particular hospitals.
Another organization that has the unique vantage point for medical errors is the Joint Commission, which is a major accrediting organization for hospitals and healthcare facilities. Each year, the Joint Commission issues a list of several National Patient Safety Goals, based on its analysis of common medical errors and recommendations on how to reduce them.</description></item><item><title>Two dangerous risks of CT, MRI, and other diagnostic radiology exams</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/two-dangerous-risks-of-ct-mri-and-other-diagnostic-radiology-exams/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/two-dangerous-risks-of-ct-mri-and-other-diagnostic-radiology-exams/</guid><description>Diagnostic imaging is an amazing tool that has rapidly advanced in medicine over the past few decades. In addition to old-school x-rays, radiologists have tools like MRI scans, CT scans, MR angiograms, CT angiograms, and other tests that can help provide insight on what is going on inside a patient&amp;rsquo;s body.
Radiological information can be extremely valuable to doctors caring for a patient because it allows them to link clinical findings, signs, and symptoms, with findings from the scans.</description></item><item><title>'Stat' means 'now': How hospitals bungle urgent CT and MRI orders</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/stat-means-now-how-hospitals-bungle-urgent-ct-and-mri-orders/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/stat-means-now-how-hospitals-bungle-urgent-ct-and-mri-orders/</guid><description>A doctor orders radiology studies for a patient when a physical exam suggests a preliminary diagnosis but additional information is necessary to be certain. Having the correct diagnosis is essential for selecting the correct treatment.
Frequently, a doctor orders a radiology scan, like computer aided tomography (CT or &amp;ldquo;CAT scan&amp;rdquo;) or magnetic resonance image (MRI), when he or she needs detailed information about an internal part of the body.
After the CT or MRI is ordered, a nurse or hospital administrative staff gets the order to a radiology department.</description></item></channel></rss>