<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>infection on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/infection/</link><description>Recent content in infection on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/infection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Infections in nursing homes or rehabilitation facilities can be deadly</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/infections-in-nursing-homes-or-rehabilitation-facilities-can-be-deadly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/infections-in-nursing-homes-or-rehabilitation-facilities-can-be-deadly/</guid><description>When patients are near the end of a hospitalization for a surgery or other illness, they sometimes need some additional care before they can go home. In these situations, case managers and doctors will often transfer patients to a nursing home or skilled nursing facility, like Manor Care Willowbrook, in Houston, or a rehabilitation facility, like Reliant Rehabilitation Hospital North Houston, in Shenandoah.
Patients and their families should realize that skilled nursing and rehabilitation facilities are frequently not set up to treat serious infections or to manage patients who are on multiple strong medications.</description></item><item><title>How to spot life-threatening infections and sepsis</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-spot-life-threatening-infections-and-sepsis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-spot-life-threatening-infections-and-sepsis/</guid><description>Infections occur when bacteria or fungi invade the human body and then start multiplying and feeding. There are many types of infections that we commonly hear about, including staph infections, MRSA infections (methicillin-resistant staph aureus), bedsores and infected catheters or lines.
It is always a serious matter when a patient has an active infection. Prompt diagnosis is important because the faster treatment begins, the more likely the infection can be killed and the patient can go on with his or her life.</description></item><item><title>Painter Law Firm negotiates $550,000 settlement for client in medical malpractice infection case</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-negotiates-550000-settlement-for-client-in-medical-malpractice-infection-case/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-negotiates-550000-settlement-for-client-in-medical-malpractice-infection-case/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm represented a client who was severely injured after a surgery when a nurse missed clear signs and symptoms of an infection.
The patient was being treated at a Houston-area hospital following a lap-band surgery. When the nurse removed a catheter line from the patient&amp;rsquo;s arm, the patient saw pus squirt out and asked for the line to be cultured. The nurse did not culture the line and did not tell the doctor about the incident.</description></item></channel></rss>