<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>waco on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/waco/</link><description>Recent content in waco on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/waco/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Providence Health Center in Waco hit with Medicare quality of care violation in 2019</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/providence-health-center-in-waco-hit-with-medicare-quality-of-care-violation-in-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/providence-health-center-in-waco-hit-with-medicare-quality-of-care-violation-in-2019/</guid><description>Although we are based in Houston, Texas, Painter Law Firm handles medical malpractice cases all over the State of Texas, including those involving care at Providence Health Center, In Waco.
Providence Health Center is located at 6901 Medical Parkway, Waco, Texas 76712. It&amp;rsquo;s part of the Ascension health care system, which is headquartered in St. Louis, Missouri.
Although Texas law prohibits hospitals from practicing medicine&amp;mdash;that&amp;rsquo;s something reserved for licensed physicians&amp;mdash;Providence and Ascension have embraced the growing Lone Star State trend to set up physician organizations that they control.</description></item><item><title>Baylor Scott &amp; White Medical Center Hillcrest performs below average on severe sepsis &amp; septic shock care</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-scott-white-medical-center-hillcrest-performs-below-average-on-severe-sepsis-septic-shock-care/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-scott-white-medical-center-hillcrest-performs-below-average-on-severe-sepsis-septic-shock-care/</guid><description>According to Medicare statistics, Baylor Scott &amp;amp; White Medical Center Hillcrest performs below the Texas average and national average when it comes to a key factor in sepsis care.
As part of Medicare&amp;rsquo;s ongoing program to bring more transparency to the quality of care, hospitals are required to report data regarding their performance on several measures. One of them is the percentage of patients who received appropriate care for severe sepsis and septic shock.</description></item><item><title>Providence Health Center Waco performs below average on severe sepsis &amp; septic shock care</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/providence-health-center-waco-performs-below-average-on-severe-sepsis-septic-shock-care/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/providence-health-center-waco-performs-below-average-on-severe-sepsis-septic-shock-care/</guid><description>As a graduate of Baylor Law School, I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with the two main Waco hospitals, Providence Health Center and Baylor Scott &amp;amp; White Medical Center&amp;mdash;Hillcrest. Even though I moved to Houston and have my office there, I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed the opportunity to represent multiple clients in McLennan County in medical malpractice cases.
As much as Waco has grown because of Magnolia fame and other reasons, it&amp;rsquo;s still a small town in many ways.</description></item><item><title>Waco ER doctor doesn't order head CT scan, two days later young patient has permanent brain injury</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/waco-er-doctor-doesnt-order-head-ct-scan-two-days-later-young-patient-has-permanent-brain-injury/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/waco-er-doctor-doesnt-order-head-ct-scan-two-days-later-young-patient-has-permanent-brain-injury/</guid><description>I spent some time in medical school and as a hospital administrator before going to law school and becoming a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney. One of the very first concepts that I remember learning in medical school is the importance of a differential diagnosis.
Differential diagnosis is an intensive thought process where the doctor considers the patient as an individual and lists every potential diagnosis that could explain the patient&amp;rsquo;s condition or problems.</description></item><item><title>Woman loses spleen, parts of stomach, and pancreas after surgeon mistakenly overrules radiologist</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/woman-loses-spleen-parts-of-stomach-and-pancreas-after-surgeon-mistakenly-overrules-radiologist/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/woman-loses-spleen-parts-of-stomach-and-pancreas-after-surgeon-mistakenly-overrules-radiologist/</guid><description>I spent yesterday in Waco, Texas, taking the deposition of a vascular surgeon that we sued on behalf of a client of Painter Law Firm for botching the evaluation, management, and surgical repair of an abdominal aneurysm.
The surgeon materially disagreed with a lot of the findings of an interventional radiologist who interpreted an abdominal CT angiogram of the patient that identified a celiac artery aneurysm. The disagreements include:
&amp;bull; Radiologist: Non-emergent, Surgeon: Emergent</description></item><item><title>Painter Law Firm files medical malpractice wrongful death lawsuit against surgeons at Providence Health Center, in Waco</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-medical-malpractice-wrongful-death-lawsuit-against-surgeons-at-providence-health-center-in-waco/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-medical-malpractice-wrongful-death-lawsuit-against-surgeons-at-providence-health-center-in-waco/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm filed a medical malpractice wrongful death lawsuit yesterday in Waco, McLennan County, Texas, regarding the care provided to Elizabeth Woosley by surgeons at Providence Health Center.
In August 2016, 78-year-old Elizabeth Woosley was admitted to the hospital for a Type 4 paraesophageal hernia repair surgery. Her surgeons were David Hoffman, M.D. and Karen Burnett, M.D.
According to the medical records, after surgery, Elizabeth had low blood pressure and altered mental status.</description></item><item><title>Providence Health Center Waco medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/providence-health-center-waco-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/providence-health-center-waco-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I handle medical negligence and wrongful death lawsuits all over the State of Texas.
I am currently working on two active lawsuits in McLennan County, Texas based on medical care that was provided at Providence Health Center, which is located at 6901 Medical Parkway, Waco, Texas 76712.
Providence Health Center is a 237-bed general hospital that is part of the large Ascension health system.</description></item><item><title>Read the Waco Tribune Herald's story about a neurosurgery medical malpractice that Painter Law Firm filed in McLennan County, Texas</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/read-the-waco-tribune-heralds-story-about-a-neurosurgery-medical-malpractice-that-painter-law-firm-filed-in-mclennan-county-texas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/read-the-waco-tribune-heralds-story-about-a-neurosurgery-medical-malpractice-that-painter-law-firm-filed-in-mclennan-county-texas/</guid><description>The Waco Tribune Herald reviewed McLennan County, Texas courthouse records and learned about the lawsuit that Painter Law Firm recently filed against Providence Health Center, a local neurosurgeon, and BrainLab, a company that manufacturers surgical equipment. You can read the newspaper story here.</description></item><item><title>Medical malpractice lawsuit: Providence Health Center, in Waco, and others responsible for botched brain surgery</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medical-malpractice-lawsuit-providence-health-center-in-waco-and-others-responsible-for-botched-brain-surgery/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medical-malpractice-lawsuit-providence-health-center-in-waco-and-others-responsible-for-botched-brain-surgery/</guid><description>I filed a medical malpractice lawsuit today in Waco, McLennan County, Texas, today alleging that the healthcare providers at Providence Health Center, in Waco, botched a brain surgery on our client.
At the time of the surgery, our client was a man in his 20s who had rather mild neurological issues. The main reason that he sought medical care was an intention tremor. Intention tremors are slow, broad tremors caused by a damage or problem in a certain part of the brain.</description></item><item><title>Baylor Scott &amp; White Medical Center—Hillcrest Waco medical malpractice lawyer/attorney</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-scott-white-medical-center%C3%A2hillcrest-waco-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-scott-white-medical-center%C3%A2hillcrest-waco-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</guid><description>As a Texas medical malpractice lawyer based in Houston, I handle medical negligence and wrongful death cases all over the state. Many clients from all over Texas call our law firm because their hometown lawyers are nervous about tackling prominent local hospitals or doctors.
Even in this era of pro-doctor, pro-hospital tort reform, I continue to focus my practice on medical malpractice cases. And, as my track record shows, I am not intimidated to take even the largest healthcare providers in Texas to court.</description></item></channel></rss>