<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>chi st. lukes on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/chi-st.-lukes/</link><description>Recent content in chi st. lukes on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/chi-st.-lukes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Houston Methodist charges almost double for a surgery than the cost at a nearby academic hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-charges-almost-double-for-a-surgery-than-the-cost-at-a-nearby-academic-hospital/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-charges-almost-double-for-a-surgery-than-the-cost-at-a-nearby-academic-hospital/</guid><description>According to the focus group research, the number one reason that people select a hospital is location. Not quality. Not whether you&amp;rsquo;ll be seen by a physician as opposed to a physician assistant (PA) or nurse practitioner (NP). Not even cost. Location.
I believe some of this phenomenon is because of the lack of information available to consumers. Most hospitals advertise that they offer top-notch care. Texas law allows hospitals to conceal the credentials and performance reviews of their physicians.</description></item><item><title>Federal lawsuit: Baylor St. Luke's Medical Center &amp; Baylor College of Medicine doctors leave towel inside patient after surgery</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/federal-lawsuit-baylor-st.-lukes-medical-center-baylor-college-of-medicine-doctors-leave-towel-inside-patient-after-surgery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/federal-lawsuit-baylor-st.-lukes-medical-center-baylor-college-of-medicine-doctors-leave-towel-inside-patient-after-surgery/</guid><description>Today, we filed a federal lawsuit in the U.S. District Court for the Southern District of Texas, Houston Division on behalf of a Colorado client who had a whole surgical towel left inside him after a June 14, 2018 surgery at Baylor St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Medical Center, in Houston&amp;rsquo;s Texas Medical Center.
The lawsuit names as defendants both the hospital and Baylor College of Medicine, who employed the principal surgeon and a total of six physicians involved in the procedure.</description></item><item><title>Federal report: Increase in basic errors endangered patients at Baylor St. Luke's Medical Center</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/federal-report-increase-in-basic-errors-endangered-patients-at-baylor-st.-lukes-medical-center/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/federal-report-increase-in-basic-errors-endangered-patients-at-baylor-st.-lukes-medical-center/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;These are really basic errors that I didn&amp;rsquo;t really think happened that often anymore.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s what Dr. Ashish Jha, a Harvard expert in hospital quality, said after reviewing the latest federal government report that&amp;#39;s critical of CHI St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Health Baylor St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Medical Center.
Some people believe that this storied 881-bed hospital, located at 6720 Berner Avenue, in Houston&amp;rsquo;s Texas Medical Center, has been resting on its laurels and in the process has lost its way.</description></item><item><title>Medicare cites Baylor St. Luke's Medical Center with violation for heart transplant quality of care concerns</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medicare-cites-baylor-st.-lukes-medical-center-with-violation-for-heart-transplant-quality-of-care-concerns/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medicare-cites-baylor-st.-lukes-medical-center-with-violation-for-heart-transplant-quality-of-care-concerns/</guid><description>Early in my career as a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, some co-workers and I met legendary heart surgeon Michael DeBakey, M.D. at his office in the Texas Medical Center.
Dr. DeBakey had a large rectangular conference table that was mostly covered with awards and plaques.
One, in particular, caught my eye&amp;mdash;a plaque commemorating an award by the Surgeon General of the United States to Dr. DeBakey. It was probably from the 1950s or 1960s because the central part of the plaque was a black and white photo of the Surgeon General.</description></item><item><title>Medicare issues violation to CHI St. Luke's Health The Woodlands Hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medicare-issues-violation-to-chi-st.-lukes-health-the-woodlands-hospital/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medicare-issues-violation-to-chi-st.-lukes-health-the-woodlands-hospital/</guid><description>The Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services recently issued a violation citation to CHI St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Health&amp;mdash;The Woodlands Hospital. This 231-bed hospital is located in Montgomery County, at 17200 St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Way, The Woodlands, TX 77384. The Medicare health inspector visited CHI St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Health&amp;mdash;The Woodlands Hospital on March 20, 2018, and cited the hospital for a violation of patient rights to participate in care planning.
As a former hospital administrator, I was interested to learn that the hospital had its own internal policy on pain management, which the nursing staff didn&amp;rsquo;t follow in this case.</description></item><item><title>Lawsuit alleges stroke misdiagnosis at CHI St. Luke's The Woodlands Hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-alleges-stroke-misdiagnosis-at-chi-st.-lukes-the-woodlands-hospital/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-alleges-stroke-misdiagnosis-at-chi-st.-lukes-the-woodlands-hospital/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm filed a medical malpractice lawsuit&amp;nbsp;against CHI St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s&amp;mdash;The Woodlands Hospital and an emergency physician over a misdiagnosed stroke.
In November 2016, our 53-year-old client, a man, went to the emergency room at CHI St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s&amp;mdash;The Woodlands Hospital because he was experiencing dizziness, projectile vomiting, and balance issues. He had to be wheeled into the hospital using a hospital wheelchair. He told the triage nurse about how he had fallen four days earlier, hitting his chest hard on the concrete, and that his chest still hurt.</description></item><item><title>St. Luke's Sugar Land Hospital (CHI St. Luke's Health Sugar Land Hospital) medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/st.-lukes-sugar-land-hospital-chi-st.-lukes-health-sugar-land-hospital-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/st.-lukes-sugar-land-hospital-chi-st.-lukes-health-sugar-land-hospital-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>The Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services recently announced that St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Sugar Land Hospital will be penalized for the 2017-2018 fiscal period because of quality of care concerns.
The U.S. Hospital-Acquired Condition Reduction Program included St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Sugar Land Hospital on its annual list of hospitals performing in the bottom 25% of all general hospitals nationwide, based on several categories, including:
Infection rates for hysterectomies, colon surgeries, central lines, and urinary catheters.</description></item><item><title>Baylor St. Luke's Medical Center medical malpractice lawyer/attorney</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-st.-lukes-medical-center-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-st.-lukes-medical-center-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I spend a significant amount of time investigating health care provided by hospitals, doctors, surgeons, anesthesiologists, and nurses.
One of the earliest steps in our investigation of potential defendants in medical negligence lawsuits is to look into a hospital&amp;rsquo;s past history of compliance or noncompliance with government regulations. One of the sources for quality of care information is the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services.</description></item><item><title>Have you been injured by medical malpractice at CHI St Luke's Health Baylor College of Medicine Medical Center?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/have-you-been-injured-by-medical-malpractice-at-chi-st-lukes-health-baylor-college-of-medicine-medical-center/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/have-you-been-injured-by-medical-malpractice-at-chi-st-lukes-health-baylor-college-of-medicine-medical-center/</guid><description>While our office is located in Houston, Painter Law Firm&amp;rsquo;s medical malpractice lawyers represent clients who have potential cases against hospitals all over Harris County. This includes hospitals in Houston, like CHI&amp;nbsp;St Luke&amp;rsquo;s Health Baylor College of Medicine Medical Center.
The types of cases we handle include surgical mistakes, anesthesia errors, infections, sepsis, birth injuries, falls, stroke, nerve damage, birth injury, childbirth complications, brain damage, diagnosis mistakes, medical device failures, medication and drug errors, wrongful death, and many others.</description></item><item><title>Have you been injured by medical malpractice at CHI St Luke's Health-Springwoods Village?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/have-you-been-injured-by-medical-malpractice-at-chi-st-lukes-health-springwoods-village/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/have-you-been-injured-by-medical-malpractice-at-chi-st-lukes-health-springwoods-village/</guid><description>While our office is located in Houston, Painter Law Firm&amp;rsquo;s medical malpractice lawyers represent clients who have potential cases against hospitals all over Harris County. This includes hospitals in Spring, like CHI St Luke&amp;rsquo;s Health-Springwoods Village.
The types of cases we handle include surgical mistakes, anesthesia errors, infections, sepsis, birth injuries, falls, stroke, nerve damage, birth injury, childbirth complications, brain damage, diagnosis mistakes, medical device failures, medication and drug errors, wrongful death, and many others.</description></item></channel></rss>