<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>about on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/about/</link><description>Recent content in about on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Invite Robert Painter to speak at your event</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/invite-robert-painter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/invite-robert-painter/</guid><description>Robert Painter speaks about Medical Malpractice to defense and plaintiff's attorneys as well as health care groups and patient advocacy organizations.
Media&amp;nbsp;Previous media events
Schedule Robert PainterCall 281-580-8800</description></item><item><title>Refer a case to Painter Law Firm</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/refer-a-case/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/refer-a-case/</guid><description>$350,000
That&amp;rsquo;s the amount of the check for a referral fee I just signed before writing this message about medical malpractice referrals.
That&amp;rsquo;s the amount for a referral fee in a case that had been turned down by five firms who were scared to tackle an emergency room case because of the willful and wanton negligence standard.
That&amp;rsquo;s the amount for a referral fee in a case that I got policy limits from the ER practice group and millions more from the hospital.</description></item><item><title>Robert Painter in the Media</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/robert-painter-in-the-media/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/robert-painter-in-the-media/</guid><description>Text for media</description></item><item><title>Practice Areas</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/practice-areas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/practice-areas/</guid><description>Our litigation practice is focused on the following types of cases. If you need a lawyer, contact us for a complimentary evaluation of your case.
Medical Malpractice and Brain Injury
According to a 2000 study by the National Institute of Medicine, as many as 98,000 Americans die and another million people are injured each year by preventable medical errors.
When you go to a hospital or doctor for treatment, you are placing your life in their hands and trust them to know what they are doing.</description></item></channel></rss>