<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>top right on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/top-right/</link><description>Recent content in top right on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/top-right/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Protect yourself from the risks of electronic medical records</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/protect-yourself-from-the-risks-of-electronic-medical-records/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/protect-yourself-from-the-risks-of-electronic-medical-records/</guid><description>You may have noticed over the past few years that more and more doctors and hospitals are using electronic medical records, rather than the older style of mostly handwritten records.
The reason that this has happened in such a rush if the 2009 passage of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act, which created funding, incentives and penalties to get hospitals and doctors to adopt and meaningfully use electronic medical records by 2014.</description></item><item><title>Video: Prenatal visits and fundal height measurement can save lives</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/video-prenatal-visits-and-fundal-height-measurement-can-save-lives/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/video-prenatal-visits-and-fundal-height-measurement-can-save-lives/</guid><description>Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to speak about something that happens in every prenatal visit&amp;mdash;or at least it should in any prenatal visit with an OB/GYN&amp;mdash;and that&amp;rsquo;s the fundal height measurement.
I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you one of the most exciting things that ever happened in my life is when I learned that I was going to be a father&amp;mdash;a dad. And, of course, once we learned of this news my wife started having a lot of prenatal visits with her OB/GYN.</description></item></channel></rss>