<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>brain on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/brain/</link><description>Recent content in brain on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/brain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Two risks for families in accepting a rushed diagnosis of brain death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/two-risks-for-families-in-accepting-a-rushed-diagnosis-of-brain-death/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/two-risks-for-families-in-accepting-a-rushed-diagnosis-of-brain-death/</guid><description>As a Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I have frequently spoken with families about what to do when a doctor tells them that a loved one is brain dead.
Most people faced with this will have a sudden flood of emotions including emotions of grief and shock. On top of that, they have to confront trying to understand brain death and whether their loved one is really brain dead. This is always a topic of discussion when I speak with families going through this type of situation.</description></item><item><title>Hyponatremia after a head injury can cause brain damage or death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/hyponatremia-after-a-head-injury-can-cause-brain-damage-or-death/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/hyponatremia-after-a-head-injury-can-cause-brain-damage-or-death/</guid><description>Any time I hear about someone who has had a head trauma in a car wreck I find myself concerned about sodium, of all things. I can&amp;rsquo;t help it, because I have handled a number of cases where patients suffered brain injuries, and almost death, because of low sodium levels. I have also seen this in cases where patients had a sinus infection that spread to the brain.
For example, just a few weeks ago, I spoke with the father of young man in his 20s.</description></item><item><title>How mothers can prevent infant brain injuries during birth</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-mothers-can-prevent-infant-brain-injuries-during-birth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-mothers-can-prevent-infant-brain-injuries-during-birth/</guid><description>One of the interesting things about a law practice focusing on medical malpractice cases is that I get to study and learn a lot about the medical issues surrounding my cases. I have handled a lot of cases involving brain injuries, including birth-related brain injuries. In many of those cases, the pregnancy was normal and the baby was healthy right until the very end. This is one of a series of articles I will share on how many of these permanent brain injuries could have been avoided with proper medical and nursing care.</description></item><item><title>'Stat' means 'now': How hospitals bungle urgent CT and MRI orders</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/stat-means-now-how-hospitals-bungle-urgent-ct-and-mri-orders/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/stat-means-now-how-hospitals-bungle-urgent-ct-and-mri-orders/</guid><description>A doctor orders radiology studies for a patient when a physical exam suggests a preliminary diagnosis but additional information is necessary to be certain. Having the correct diagnosis is essential for selecting the correct treatment.
Frequently, a doctor orders a radiology scan, like computer aided tomography (CT or &amp;ldquo;CAT scan&amp;rdquo;) or magnetic resonance image (MRI), when he or she needs detailed information about an internal part of the body.
After the CT or MRI is ordered, a nurse or hospital administrative staff gets the order to a radiology department.</description></item><item><title>Painter Law Firm wins medical malpractice settlement of $3,925,000</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-wins-medical-malpractice-settlement-of-3925000/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-wins-medical-malpractice-settlement-of-3925000/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm attorney Robert Painter recently settled a Houston medical malpractice lawsuit for $3,925,000. We cannot identify the defendants because of a confidentiality agreement.
We represented a teenager who sustained a permanent, severely-disabling brain injury at a hospital after she developed hyponatremia while in the hospital.
Hyponatremia is a condition where a person develops a low serum sodium level. It is fairly common among runners who get dehydrated. In a hospital setting, it can be life-threatening.</description></item></channel></rss>