<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>the minute lawyer series on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/the-minute-lawyer-series/</link><description>Recent content in the minute lawyer series on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/the-minute-lawyer-series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney Robert Painter video: Good hospital communication saves lives</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-video-good-hospital-communication-saves-lives/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-video-good-hospital-communication-saves-lives/</guid><description>Many people do not realize that hospitals are dangerous places. Studies have shown that nearly 100,000 people die each year from preventable medical errors. In my practice, the most common culprit I see for hospital medical errors will probably surprise you&amp;mdash;poor or entirely absent communication.
I have handled a lot of cases where a doctor has given a nurse in order for some urgent lab work or a CT exam or maybe some sort of test&amp;mdash;and the unbelievable happens, it doesn&amp;#39;t get done.</description></item><item><title>Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney Robert Painter video: Watch fetal movements &amp; prevent brain injury</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-video-watch-fetal-movements-prevent-brain-injury/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-video-watch-fetal-movements-prevent-brain-injury/</guid><description>One of most rewarding things about helping people as an attorney in the area of medical malpractice is I get to learn a lot about narrow areas of medicine as they relate to the law. One of the areas where I spend a lot on time is cases is brain injuries and, in particular, the tragedies of brain injured babies. And as a father of four, these types of injuries are particularly bothersome to me.</description></item><item><title>Video: Hospital death panels in Texas</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/video-hospital-death-panels-in-texas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/video-hospital-death-panels-in-texas/</guid><description>Learn the shocking truth about how hospitals and doctors in Texas, not patients and their families, get to make the final decision as to whether health care continues or ends--ultimately meaning that they decide whether the patient lives or dies.
Resources
Video: Hospital Death Panels in Texas
Painter Law Firm&amp;#39;s &amp;#39;Surviving Hospitals&amp;#39; website on medical futility law in Texas
Transcript of the video :
Did you know Texas law is the worst in the nation when it comes to protecting patient rights when they may be coming to the end of life?</description></item></channel></rss>