<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dnr end of life on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/dnr-end-of-life/</link><description>Recent content in dnr end of life on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/dnr-end-of-life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Four questions to ask when confronted with potential brain death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/four-questions-to-ask-when-confronted-with-potential-brain-death/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/four-questions-to-ask-when-confronted-with-potential-brain-death/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s rare that for a week to go by that we don&amp;rsquo;t have a conversation with a grieving, stressed-out family confronting end-of-life questions involving a loved one.
Last week, a friend of mine, who&amp;rsquo;s familiar with the medical malpractice and health law work of Painter Law Firm, called to discuss the unexpected medical situation of his neighbor at home. He went to the neighbor&amp;rsquo;s house for a visit and discovered that he had just collapsed.</description></item><item><title>Texas DNR orders: Mechanics, abuse, and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-dnr-orders-mechanics-abuse-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-dnr-orders-mechanics-abuse-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>Under a new law that went into effect in 2018, Texas law did a horrible job at protecting patients from renegade doctors and their &amp;ldquo;do not resuscitate&amp;rdquo; or DNR orders. Like any order in a hospital, a DNR order is signed by a physician and instructs healthcare providers not to start cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR) or other life-saving measures when a patient has a cardiac or respiratory arrest.
The stories of DNR abuse that we have heard first-hand from clients are horrific and heart-wrenching.</description></item><item><title>Hawaii becomes latest state to have assisted-death law</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/hawaii-becomes-latest-state-to-have-assisted-death-law/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/hawaii-becomes-latest-state-to-have-assisted-death-law/</guid><description>On this New Year&amp;rsquo;s Day 2019, Hawaii became the latest state to have an assisted-death or assisted-suicide law active and on the books.
The controversial &amp;ldquo;Our Care, Our Choice Act&amp;rdquo; allows Hawaii residents with a medical prognosis of six months or less to live to request a prescription for lethal medications to cause their death. To take advantage of this un-Aloha death law, patients must meet these requirements:
&amp;middot; An adult resident of Hawaii.</description></item><item><title>Guardianships and alternatives in Texas, and why you should plan ahead</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/guardianships-and-alternatives-in-texas-and-why-you-should-plan-ahead/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/guardianships-and-alternatives-in-texas-and-why-you-should-plan-ahead/</guid><description>I attended the Houston Bar Association&amp;rsquo;s (HBA) annual all-day guardianship seminar today. By the way, the HBA was founded in 1870, and I was elected to its board of directors this year.
As the seminar got underway, I thought about the different situations where I have represented clients in guardianships, as well as the alternatives to guardianship. As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, these issues come up from time to time, and I think everyone should think about them far in advance.</description></item><item><title>Profits over patients in hospice and end-of-life care</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/profits-over-patients-in-hospice-and-end-of-life-care/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/profits-over-patients-in-hospice-and-end-of-life-care/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I have had a lot of cases involving end-of-life and hospice care. While for most patients and families, this type of care is compassionate, helpful, and appreciated. In other instances, healthcare providers suggest hospice care for selfish reasons.
Frisco, Texas hospice debacle
In May 2018, a hospice executive in Frisco, Texas admitted to her role in overdosing patients to &amp;ldquo;hasten their deaths.&amp;rdquo; According to court documents, an operations director for Novus Health Services, Inc.</description></item><item><title>Patient safety and end-of-life decision-making</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/patient-safety-and-end-of-life-decision-making/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/patient-safety-and-end-of-life-decision-making/</guid><description>American Medical Association (AMA) Medical Ethics Opinion 5.7 describes the organization&amp;rsquo;s position against physician-assisted suicide. The opinion states that, &amp;ldquo;permitting physicians to engage in assisted suicide would ultimately cause more harm than good. Physician-assisted suicide is fundamentally incompatible with the physician&amp;rsquo;s role as healer . . . .&amp;rdquo;
In June 2018, the AMA voted down a recommendation of its Council on Ethical and Judicial Affairs to maintain its position on physician-assisted suicide.</description></item><item><title>The sad story of British baby Alfie Evans could happen in Texas under current law</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-sad-story-of-british-baby-alfie-evans-could-happen-in-texas-under-current-law/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-sad-story-of-british-baby-alfie-evans-could-happen-in-texas-under-current-law/</guid><description>I have followed with profound sadness the story Alfie Evans, a British toddler whose family is fighting hospital administrators, doctors, and British courts to keep him alive.
In my experience as a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, Alfie&amp;rsquo;s story is different from what I typically see in Texas cases, yet there are some profound similarities that should cause grave concern for Texans. Both in Texas and Great Britain, the fight is over a question called medical futility.</description></item><item><title>Do-not-resuscitate (DNR) orders increase likelihood of ICU death, less overall care</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/do-not-resuscitate-dnr-orders-increase-likelihood-of-icu-death-less-overall-care/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/do-not-resuscitate-dnr-orders-increase-likelihood-of-icu-death-less-overall-care/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, patients and family members frequently ask me questions about the legal impact of advance directives.
An advance directive is a written document that summarizes a person&amp;rsquo;s health care wishes and preferences. I think it is a good idea to have an advance directive because it benefits both healthcare providers and family members in making treatment decisions when a person is incapacitated.
Some people create advance directives that request all measures to be taken to preserve life.</description></item><item><title>New study exposes Texas nursing home anti-psychotic drug over-medication problem</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-study-exposes-texas-nursing-home-anti-psychotic-drug-over-medication-problem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-study-exposes-texas-nursing-home-anti-psychotic-drug-over-medication-problem/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I frequently handle cases involving nursing home and hospital medication errors. Unfortunately, in my experience, it seems that many nursing home healthcare providers use overmedication as a means of silencing patients and keeping them out of their hair.
I recall handling a case against skilled nursing facility (SNF) in the Sugar Land, Texas area. The family members of an elderly patient/resident of the facility told me how their loved one had been experiencing a lot of pain.</description></item><item><title>New Texas law will protect patients from hostile do-not-resuscitate/DNR orders</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-texas-law-will-protect-patients-from-hostile-do-not-resuscitate/dnr-orders/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-texas-law-will-protect-patients-from-hostile-do-not-resuscitate/dnr-orders/</guid><description>In my experience as a Houston , Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I believe that the most shocking Texas laws that I share with clients is that doctors can enter a do not resuscitate (DNR) without the patient or family&amp;rsquo;s consent&amp;mdash;or even knowledge.
Thanks to recent legislation, though, it will not be long before this practice will end.
Before discussing the current Texas DNR law, and how it is about to change, we should really talk about what a DNR order is in the first place.</description></item><item><title>Texas law lets hospitals and doctors override your advance directive and terminate curative care</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-law-lets-hospitals-and-doctors-override-your-advance-directive-and-terminate-curative-care/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-law-lets-hospitals-and-doctors-override-your-advance-directive-and-terminate-curative-care/</guid><description>On September 22, 2017, I attended a hearing in the 189th District Court of Harris County, Texas, where Judge Bill Burke was presiding. The case is styled Evelyn Kelly, Individually and On Behalf of the Estate of David Christopher Dunn v. The Methodist Hospital; Cause No. 2015-69681. Ms. Kelly is Mr. Dunn&amp;rsquo;s mother. Mr. Dunn died while a patient at Houston Methodist Hospital.
This very interesting oral hearing addressed competing motions for summary judgment filed by both sides over whether Texas Health &amp;amp; Safety Code Section 166.</description></item><item><title>Children's Memorial Hermann Hospital CAPS Team &amp; what you should know about it</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/childrens-memorial-hermann-hospital-caps-team-what-you-should-know-about-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/childrens-memorial-hermann-hospital-caps-team-what-you-should-know-about-it/</guid><description>I recently met with a new father whose infant has been bounced around three Memorial Hermann hospitals in her short life.
She was born at one Memorial Hermann suburban hospital and then transferred to another one of the system&amp;rsquo;s suburban hospitals that had a more-equipped neonatal intensive care unit (NICU). When she arrived at the second Memorial Hermann hospital, her family recalls the doctors and nurses saying that she should be fine.</description></item><item><title>Can money play a role in the hospital and doctor's decision to pull the plug?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/can-money-play-a-role-in-the-hospital-and-doctors-decision-to-pull-the-plug/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/can-money-play-a-role-in-the-hospital-and-doctors-decision-to-pull-the-plug/</guid><description>A California judge recently ruled that it would be up to the jury to determine whether a teenage girl is deceased. Many people may reasonably think that questions of life and death are well settled, but in modern medicine and law that is not always the case.
The California judge is presiding over a medical malpractice lawsuit involving a 13-year-old girl who went into cardiac arrest after a routine procedure to remove her tonsils.</description></item><item><title>Texas hospitals can stop treating and feeding patients even when patients and families disagree</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-hospitals-can-stop-treating-and-feeding-patients-even-when-patients-and-families-disagree/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-hospitals-can-stop-treating-and-feeding-patients-even-when-patients-and-families-disagree/</guid><description>News outlets all over the world have told the sad story of Charlie Gard. Charlie was born in September 2017 with a rare medical disorder called mitochondrial DNA depletion syndrome. As a result of this disorder, Charlie is blind, deaf, and in need of life support for breathing.
Charlie&amp;rsquo;s parents want to transfer him from a hospital in London to the United States, where a long-shot experimental treatment is available. Charlie was even the subject of a sympathetic Tweet by President Donald Trump: &amp;ldquo;If we can help little #Charlie Gard .</description></item><item><title>Two documents you need now to plan ahead for end-of-life health care</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/two-documents-you-need-now-to-plan-ahead-for-end-of-life-health-care/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/two-documents-you-need-now-to-plan-ahead-for-end-of-life-health-care/</guid><description>The case of Charlie Gard has revived the end-of-life health care debate that has been going on since death panels were first mentioned a decade again. In case you do not recognize Charlie&amp;rsquo;s name, he is an infant in a London hospital whose parents want to bring him to the United States to receive experimental treatment. British courts are standing in the way, though.
Setting aside the ethical issues of allowing a court or death panel to make health care treatment decisions instead of a patient or her family, planning ahead is an&amp;nbsp;important concern when it comes to end-of-life care, as well as senior care more generally.</description></item><item><title>Texas allows doctors to sign unauthorized do not resuscitate (DNR) orders without telling you</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-allows-doctors-to-sign-unauthorized-do-not-resuscitate-dnr-orders-without-telling-you/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-allows-doctors-to-sign-unauthorized-do-not-resuscitate-dnr-orders-without-telling-you/</guid><description>An Illinois family recently filed a wrongful death lawsuit against a nursing home facility after the healthcare providers failed to resuscitate their 52-year-old loved one.&amp;nbsp;
According to the lawsuit, the woman had indicated her desire that the nursing home &amp;ldquo;render full treatment including all resuscitation efforts medically available to her in the event of a cardiac or respiratory arrest.&amp;rdquo;
This type of advance directive decision refers to a patient&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;do not resuscitate&amp;rdquo; or DNR status.</description></item><item><title>Robert Painter testifies before Texas House of Representatives</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/robert-painter-testifies-before-texas-house-of-representatives/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/robert-painter-testifies-before-texas-house-of-representatives/</guid><description>Robert Painter testified before the Texas House of Representatives Human Services Committee on April 12, 2011, in support of House Bill 3520. This legislation would amend the Texas &amp;#39;death panel&amp;#39; statute (Advance Directives Act of 1999).
Under current law, a hospital &amp;#39;ethics&amp;#39; committee can override the wishes of a patient or family for care to continue, if the committee decides that care is &amp;#39;medically futile&amp;#39;. The committee can meet with just 48 hours of notice to the patient, and if the committee finds against the patient the hospital only has to wait 10 days before terminating all curative care, nutrition and hydration.</description></item><item><title>Video: Hospital death panels in Texas</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/video-hospital-death-panels-in-texas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/video-hospital-death-panels-in-texas/</guid><description>Learn the shocking truth about how hospitals and doctors in Texas, not patients and their families, get to make the final decision as to whether health care continues or ends--ultimately meaning that they decide whether the patient lives or dies.
Resources
Video: Hospital Death Panels in Texas
Painter Law Firm&amp;#39;s &amp;#39;Surviving Hospitals&amp;#39; website on medical futility law in Texas
Transcript of the video :
Did you know Texas law is the worst in the nation when it comes to protecting patient rights when they may be coming to the end of life?</description></item><item><title>A new idea to fix the Texas 'death panel' law</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/a-new-idea-to-fix-the-texas-death-panel-law/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/a-new-idea-to-fix-the-texas-death-panel-law/</guid><description>The Advance Directives Act of 1999 has been in place for over a decade. Session after session, the Texas legislature has failed to amend it despite a terrible controversy over the provisions governing end-of-life care.
As it stands now, hospital committees, not patients and their families, have the ultimate say-so in whether a person receives curative care, food and water&amp;mdash;in other words, they make the &amp;#39;life and death&amp;#39; decision.
Plus, the due process provisions of the law are dubious: (1) Hospitals only need to give a patient and family 48-hours&amp;#39; notice of the committee meeting.</description></item><item><title>Video: Robert Painter speaks about the Texas futile care (death panel) law</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/video-robert-painter-speaks-about-the-texas-futile-care-death-panel-law/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/video-robert-painter-speaks-about-the-texas-futile-care-death-panel-law/</guid><description>Robert Painter addressed the Houston Disability Elder Law Association on the Texas &amp;#39;Futile Care&amp;#39; law on October 19, 2010 at The Downtown Club at the Met, in Houston. This article provides links to the video from that presentation as well as other resources. Many Texans are surprised to learn that the Advance Directives Act of 1999 allows a hospital committee to act as a &amp;#39;death panel&amp;#39; that can override a patient or family&amp;#39;s treatment wishes, even to the point of withholding care, treatment, food and water from a patient.</description></item><item><title>Developments in Texas Advance Directives</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/developments-in-texas-advance-directives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/developments-in-texas-advance-directives/</guid><description>This article was originally printed in&amp;nbsp;October 2009 edition of The Houston Lawyer magazine.
The balance of power between patients and physicians about end-of-life health care decisions has seesawed over the years. The development of "advance directives," led to a nationwide shift in favor of patients. Advance directives allow patients the opportunity to convey end-of-life decisions prior to a need arising. In Texas, these patient rights have diminished as legislators focus on development and implementation of the futility review process that authorizes health-care providers to have the final say under certain circumstances.</description></item><item><title>Death panels already exist</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/death-panels-already-exist/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/death-panels-already-exist/</guid><description>This op-ed was published in the August 19, 2009 edition of The Washington Times.
Former Alaska Gov. Sarah Palin, who says President Obama&amp;#39;s heath care reform would result in "death panels," needs to look no further than Texas to see a slippery slope like the one she envisions.
In Texas, a legislative provision that many thought was an innocuous proposal to help people has been twisted to snatch end-of-life decisions out of the hands of families.</description></item></channel></rss>