<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>prevention on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/prevention/</link><description>Recent content in prevention on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/prevention/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to prevent birth injuries and death during labor &amp; delivery</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-prevent-birth-injuries-and-death-during-labor-delivery/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-prevent-birth-injuries-and-death-during-labor-delivery/</guid><description>As a father of four who has been in the hospital room for every minute of each labor and delivery, I know that having a baby is one of the most exciting and precious events that anyone can experience.
We all have seen the preparations that would-be parents undertake to prepare for the new baby&amp;rsquo;s arrival&amp;ndash;choosing the perfect name, going to baby showers, painting and furnishing the nursery, stocking up on supplies, and selecting that special outfit the baby will wear when leaving the hospital.</description></item><item><title>Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney Robert Painter video: Good hospital communication saves lives</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-video-good-hospital-communication-saves-lives/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-video-good-hospital-communication-saves-lives/</guid><description>Many people do not realize that hospitals are dangerous places. Studies have shown that nearly 100,000 people die each year from preventable medical errors. In my practice, the most common culprit I see for hospital medical errors will probably surprise you&amp;mdash;poor or entirely absent communication.
I have handled a lot of cases where a doctor has given a nurse in order for some urgent lab work or a CT exam or maybe some sort of test&amp;mdash;and the unbelievable happens, it doesn&amp;#39;t get done.</description></item><item><title>Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney Robert Painter video: Watch fetal movements &amp; prevent brain injury</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-video-watch-fetal-movements-prevent-brain-injury/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-video-watch-fetal-movements-prevent-brain-injury/</guid><description>One of most rewarding things about helping people as an attorney in the area of medical malpractice is I get to learn a lot about narrow areas of medicine as they relate to the law. One of the areas where I spend a lot on time is cases is brain injuries and, in particular, the tragedies of brain injured babies. And as a father of four, these types of injuries are particularly bothersome to me.</description></item><item><title>Holidays are a good time to avoid hospitals</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/holidays-are-a-good-time-to-avoid-hospitals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/holidays-are-a-good-time-to-avoid-hospitals/</guid><description>Have you ever noticed that any time you or family member gets sick, it seems to happen on an evening, weekend or holiday? That certainly seems how it goes in our family. Did you know, though, that during these times the risk of medical and nursing errors in the hospital is much higher than normal?
If possible, avoid hospitals on weekends, evenings and holidays
No matter the occupation or workplace, most people enjoy taking time off from work around the holidays and during the summer.</description></item><item><title>Three secrets about how hospitals and doctors hide their past mistakes from the public</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-secrets-about-how-hospitals-and-doctors-hide-their-past-mistakes-from-the-public/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-secrets-about-how-hospitals-and-doctors-hide-their-past-mistakes-from-the-public/</guid><description>There is not a week that goes by when a client does not ask me &amp;ldquo;Has the doctor done this to anyone else?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Why did the hospital let the doctor practice at its facility?&amp;rdquo;
These are straightforward and understandable questions. After all, people regularly check out service providers at sites like the Better Business Bureau or Angie&amp;rsquo;s List. Yet, the medical profession is unique in that its self-policing is shrouded in secrecy.</description></item><item><title>U.S. government study shows that hospitals cover up when they injure patients</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/u.s.-government-study-shows-that-hospitals-cover-up-when-they-injure-patients/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/u.s.-government-study-shows-that-hospitals-cover-up-when-they-injure-patients/</guid><description>A study released in January 2012 once again highlights the risks to patients of going to hospitals and getting injured by medical malpractice.
In particular, hospitals get a failing grade when it comes to reporting incidents that are harmful to patients. When they cover up instead of report, doctors, nurses and hospital administrators are less likely to learn from their mistakes and make changes for the good so that future patients will not be harmed.</description></item><item><title>How mothers can prevent infant brain injuries during birth</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-mothers-can-prevent-infant-brain-injuries-during-birth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-mothers-can-prevent-infant-brain-injuries-during-birth/</guid><description>One of the interesting things about a law practice focusing on medical malpractice cases is that I get to study and learn a lot about the medical issues surrounding my cases. I have handled a lot of cases involving brain injuries, including birth-related brain injuries. In many of those cases, the pregnancy was normal and the baby was healthy right until the very end. This is one of a series of articles I will share on how many of these permanent brain injuries could have been avoided with proper medical and nursing care.</description></item><item><title>Instead of pointing fingers at each other, doctors and nurses need to focus on patient care and safety</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/instead-of-pointing-fingers-at-each-other-doctors-and-nurses-need-to-focus-on-patient-care-and-safety/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/instead-of-pointing-fingers-at-each-other-doctors-and-nurses-need-to-focus-on-patient-care-and-safety/</guid><description>Study after study has shown that one of the biggest contributors to medical errors and negligence is poor communication among healthcare providers. In a race, one runner does his or her part and then passes the baton to a team member for the next segment of the race. In the health care setting, the baton is frequently not passed, it is dropped.
In an effort to stop this breakdown in communication that endangers patient safety, the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations (JCAHO) requires hospitals to train nurses and physicians on &amp;lsquo;handoff communications.</description></item><item><title>Medicare: 1 in 7 patients is harmed during hospitalization</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medicare-1-in-7-patients-is-harmed-during-hospitalization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medicare-1-in-7-patients-is-harmed-during-hospitalization/</guid><description>According to a new report by the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services, about 15,000 Medicare patients per month experience a complication or error while hospitalized that contributes to death.
During the month-long study that was the basis for the report, 134,000 Medicare patients suffered at least one adverse event while hospitalized, and an astounding 44 percent of those errors were preventable.
Dr. Donald Berwick, a patient safety advocate, seemed to suggest that the best way to avoid hospital errors is to avoid hospitals.</description></item><item><title>Surgical errors can be reduced with a simple checklist</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/surgical-errors-can-be-reduced-with-a-simple-checklist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/surgical-errors-can-be-reduced-with-a-simple-checklist/</guid><description>Unfortunately many hospitals, nurses and physicians have poor communication practices. Time and time again studies have shown that poor communications increase medical errors and patient deaths.
As a Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I frequently see cases in which doctors give orders, hospital nursing or technical staff do not complete the orders, and doctors do not check back for the results.
Without appropriate &amp;#39;hand off&amp;#39; communications (as required by the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations) or follow-up by a physician, quite often the patient suffers harm.</description></item><item><title>Texas finally takes first step in regulating 'pill mills'</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-finally-takes-first-step-in-regulating-pill-mills/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-finally-takes-first-step-in-regulating-pill-mills/</guid><description>When it comes to pain management physicians, it is not enough to find a &amp;#39;board certified&amp;#39; doctor. Multiple boards grant that label and many are not very strict in their standards.
What should you ask before selecting a pain management doctor? Click here to read my special report.
There is another big problem in the pain management field, the so-called &amp;#39;pill mills.&amp;#39; There are over 200 so-called pain clinics in Houston alone, and many of them are &amp;#39;supervised&amp;#39; by absentee physicians who are rarely on site, and dispense powerful drugs without a physical exam.</description></item><item><title>Pain management: Check your doctor’s qualifications carefully</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/pain-management-check-your-doctor%C3%A2s-qualifications-carefully/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/pain-management-check-your-doctor%C3%A2s-qualifications-carefully/</guid><description>In most states, a physician may be licensed to practice medicine by merely graduating from medical school, taking a basic licensing exam, and then applying for licensure. At that point, a doctor can &amp;ldquo;hang a shingle&amp;rdquo; and start practicing medicine. Hospitals have the responsibility for verifying the licensure status and competence of physicians they allow to practice in their facilities through a process called credentialing.
Hospitals credential doctors to practice in certain areas of medicine or to perform specific procedures or surgeries.</description></item><item><title>'Stat' means 'now': How hospitals bungle urgent CT and MRI orders</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/stat-means-now-how-hospitals-bungle-urgent-ct-and-mri-orders/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/stat-means-now-how-hospitals-bungle-urgent-ct-and-mri-orders/</guid><description>A doctor orders radiology studies for a patient when a physical exam suggests a preliminary diagnosis but additional information is necessary to be certain. Having the correct diagnosis is essential for selecting the correct treatment.
Frequently, a doctor orders a radiology scan, like computer aided tomography (CT or &amp;ldquo;CAT scan&amp;rdquo;) or magnetic resonance image (MRI), when he or she needs detailed information about an internal part of the body.
After the CT or MRI is ordered, a nurse or hospital administrative staff gets the order to a radiology department.</description></item><item><title>Poor nursing communication causes needless hospital injuries and deaths</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/poor-nursing-communication-causes-needless-hospital-injuries-and-deaths/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/poor-nursing-communication-causes-needless-hospital-injuries-and-deaths/</guid><description>When a patient is admitted to a hospital one of the most important factors for achieving treatment goals is competent nursing care.
Physicians perform assessments and make orders, and most often then delegate it to the nursing staff to monitor the patient, follow the orders, and report back when there are any changes in the patient&amp;rsquo;s status.
For nurses to be able to fulfill this role, hospitals must be serious about their role to hire only qualified nurses and then to use proper testing and assessment to ensure that those nurses have the skills to take care of particular types of patients.</description></item></channel></rss>