<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mediation on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/mediation/</link><description>Recent content in mediation on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/mediation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What you should know about future medical bills and Texas medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-future-medical-bills-and-texas-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-future-medical-bills-and-texas-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>Any time there&amp;rsquo;s a Texas medical malpractice case involving a plaintiff with a permanent brain or other serious, disabling injury, there&amp;rsquo;s an elephant in the room. The elephant is there at mediation. The elephant is there at trial. The elephant is there during appeal.
What&amp;rsquo;s the elephant?
I&amp;rsquo;ll frontload. The elephant is cost of future medical care.
For medical malpractice plaintiffs with a profound birth injury, brain injury, or other permanent and serious disabling injury, the largest line item of recovery is typically the cost of future medical expenses.</description></item><item><title>Taxable court costs in a Texas medical malpractice lawsuit</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/taxable-court-costs-in-a-texas-medical-malpractice-lawsuit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/taxable-court-costs-in-a-texas-medical-malpractice-lawsuit/</guid><description>In Texas, medical malpractice cases are expensive to pursue. There are numerous case-related expenses, with the largest one being fees paid to medical, nursing, and other expert witnesses. Other costs of the lawsuit include items such as filing fees, court reporter fees for deposition transcripts, videographer fees for depositions, travel expenses, records fees, investigators fees, and on and on.
Often, near the end of the mediation or after a jury verdict, there&amp;rsquo;s a discussion about taxable court costs.</description></item><item><title>Mediation and attorney's fees in Texas medical malpractice cases</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/mediation-and-attorneys-fees-in-texas-medical-malpractice-cases/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/mediation-and-attorneys-fees-in-texas-medical-malpractice-cases/</guid><description>Mediation is a time set aside when the parties to a claim or lawsuit get together to try to resolve the matter without having to go to trial. The mediator is a neutral person, usually an attorney, retired judge, or insurance company adjuster, who facilitate settlement discussions.
Unlike arbitration or trial, the mediator can&amp;rsquo;t impose a decision on the parties. It&amp;rsquo;s up to both sides show up with authority to negotiate in good faith and, if possible, settle the claim.</description></item><item><title>What happens at the mediation of a Texas medical malpractice case?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-happens-at-the-mediation-of-a-texas-medical-malpractice-case/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-happens-at-the-mediation-of-a-texas-medical-malpractice-case/</guid><description>Mediation is a word that isn&amp;rsquo;t used very often outside the context of litigation. In Texas medical malpractice lawsuits, though, it&amp;rsquo;s used all the time. If you&amp;rsquo;re considering a lawsuit or are a plaintiff wondering what to expect at mediation, this article will help answer some common questions.
Mediation is a meeting where the parties to a dispute get together to try to work it out with the assistance of an experienced neutral third party.</description></item><item><title>Mediation ins and outs for medical malpractice cases</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/mediation-ins-and-outs-for-medical-malpractice-cases/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/mediation-ins-and-outs-for-medical-malpractice-cases/</guid><description>Mediation is a part of virtually every civil lawsuit in Texas.
In Harris County, for instance, most judges issue standard scheduling orders that require mediation, or an objection to be filed, by a certain deadline. If there is not a good ground for an objection, it is often overruled.
I read a horror story today about a judge&amp;rsquo;s ruling in a case in Conroe, Montgomery County, Texas. The attorneys appeared at a docket call (pre-trial hearing) to announce ready for trial.</description></item></channel></rss>