<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>metroplex on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/metroplex/</link><description>Recent content in metroplex on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/metroplex/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dallas area trauma center hospital skips cervical spine CT scan, car wreck patient is rendered quadriplegic</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-area-trauma-center-hospital-skips-cervical-spine-ct-scan-car-wreck-patient-is-rendered-quadriplegic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-area-trauma-center-hospital-skips-cervical-spine-ct-scan-car-wreck-patient-is-rendered-quadriplegic/</guid><description>I recently finished taking several depositions of defendant healthcare providers in a case involving a Level I trauma center hospital in the Dallas-Fort Worth Metroplex area. I have to admit that even after these depositions I&amp;rsquo;m still just as puzzled as to how and organize trauma team so thoroughly dropped the ball.
First, let me tell you about what happened that brought our client to the hospital.
Our client was driving on a DFW freeway when his brakes went out.</description></item><item><title>Defeating a defense medical malpractice summary judgment in Texas</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/defeating-a-defense-medical-malpractice-summary-judgment-in-texas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/defeating-a-defense-medical-malpractice-summary-judgment-in-texas/</guid><description>Defense attorneys for hospitals and physicians have some procedural tools available to them that can be used to ask a trial court to dismiss a plaintiff&amp;rsquo;s medical malpractice lawsuit.
Expert report dismissal
The most commonly used dispositive tool is likely the motion to dismiss early in the litigation process for an alleged failure of a plaintiff to comply with the preliminary expert report requirements. This tort reform statute is codified at Texas Civil Practice &amp;amp; Remedies Code Section 74.</description></item><item><title>Dallas court of appeals: Visitor slip and fall in hallway is not health care liability claim</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-court-of-appeals-visitor-slip-and-fall-in-hallway-is-not-health-care-liability-claim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-court-of-appeals-visitor-slip-and-fall-in-hallway-is-not-health-care-liability-claim/</guid><description>I recently wrote an article about a Houston court of appeals opinion dealing with a slip and fall injury at the hospital in the Texas Medical Center. It addresses the safety duty owed by hospital to visitors.
In a December 2020 opinion, the Dallas Court of Appeals considered another thorny issue for health care facility visitors injured in a slip and fall, namely whether the tort reform requirements and limitations of the Texas Medical Liability Act apply.</description></item><item><title>Medical malpractice wrongful death lawsuit: Routine CT scan with contrast ends in death at Gateway Diagnostic Imaging, LLC d/b/a Gateway Diagnostic Mid-Cities</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medical-malpractice-wrongful-death-lawsuit-routine-ct-scan-with-contrast-ends-in-death-at-gateway-diagnostic-imaging-llc-d/b/a-gateway-diagnostic-mid-cities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medical-malpractice-wrongful-death-lawsuit-routine-ct-scan-with-contrast-ends-in-death-at-gateway-diagnostic-imaging-llc-d/b/a-gateway-diagnostic-mid-cities/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm filed a medical malpractice wrongful death lawsuit yesterday against Gateway Diagnostic Imaging, LLC d/b/a Gateway Diagnostic Mid-Cities and three physicians arising from the death of a healthy 52-year-old man following a CT scan of the abdomen and pelvis for suspected kidney stones.
The case is pending in the 101st District Court of Dallas County, Texas, where the presiding judge is The Hon. Staci Williams. You can read the original petition here.</description></item><item><title>Baylor Scott &amp; White Medical Center Plano (formerly known as Baylor Regional Medical Center at Plano) medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-scott-white-medical-center-plano-formerly-known-as-baylor-regional-medical-center-at-plano-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-scott-white-medical-center-plano-formerly-known-as-baylor-regional-medical-center-at-plano-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I handle medical negligence cases throughout the State of Texas, including those involving care hospitals and Plano.
One of the major facilities and Plano is Baylor Scott &amp;amp; White Medical Center&amp;mdash;Plano (formerly known as Baylor Regional Medical Center at Plano), which is located at 4700 Alliance Boulevard, Plano, TX 75093, in Collin County. This hospital has 160 beds.
Baylor Scott &amp;amp; White Medical Center&amp;mdash;Plano offers specialty services including allergy and immunology, anesthesiology, asthma care, back and spine care, behavioral and psychological health, breast imaging, cancer care, cosmetic and plastic surgery, critical and intensive care (ICU), dentistry and oral surgery, dermatology, diabetes, digestive diseases, ear, nose, and throat, emergency room, endocrinology, eye care, footcare, heart/cardiac/vascular, hematology, diagnostic imaging and radiology, infectious diseases, inpatient medicine and hospitalists, kidney disease, liver disease, lung care/pulmonary, men&amp;rsquo;s health, neurosurgery, neurology, occupational and environmental medicine, orthopedic surgery, pharmacy, primary care, rehabilitation and physical therapy, rheumatology, scoliosis care, sports medicine, supportive and palliative care, surgery services, urology, weight-loss surgery, wellness and fitness, women&amp;rsquo;s health, and wound care.</description></item><item><title>Baylor Scott &amp; White Medical Center Grapevine medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-scott-white-medical-center-grapevine-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baylor-scott-white-medical-center-grapevine-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I handle cases throughout the State of Texas, including hospitals located in Grapevine, which is largely within Tarrant County, Texas.
Baylor Scott &amp;amp; White Medical Center Grapevine is located at 1650 W College St., Grapevine, Texas 76051. This 302-bed hospital offers medical services for heart and vascular, women and children (including birthing, labor, and delivery services), neurosciences (including neurosurgery), stroke, orthopedics, spine, diagnostic imaging, intensive care (ICU), neonatal intensive care (NICU), and emergency care (ER).</description></item><item><title>Methodist Dallas Medical Center medical malpractice lawyer/attorney</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/methodist-dallas-medical-center-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/methodist-dallas-medical-center-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I represent patients and family members in medical malpractice and wrongful death lawsuits in the Houston area, as well as all over the State of Texas.
Methodist Dallas Medical Center Methodist Dallas Medical Center is located at 1441 N. Beckley Avenue, Dallas, TX 75203. The hospital is part of the nonprofit Methodist Health System, which has multiple locations throughout the Dallas/Fort Worth Metroplex area.</description></item><item><title>Dallas Medical Center medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-medical-center-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dallas-medical-center-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>Although my law office is in Houston, Texas, I handle medical malpractice cases all over Texas, including the Dallas area.
One of the hospitals in the Dallas area is Dallas Medical Center, located at 7 Medical Parkway, Dallas, TX 75234. Located in the Farmers Branch part of the city, the 155-bed hospital offers an emergency room, a complete laboratory, digital x-ray machines, a CT scanner, an MRI machine, ultrasound equipment, a heart catheterization lab, and operating room suites.</description></item><item><title>Mammogram interpretations botched at Arlington, Texas hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/mammogram-interpretations-botched-at-arlington-texas-hospital/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/mammogram-interpretations-botched-at-arlington-texas-hospital/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I have handled cases involving patients who suffered serious injury or death as a result of cancer misdiagnosis.
One of the most popular cancer-screening tests is the mammogram. Mammograms are specialized x-rays of the breasts that, when done properly, allow early detection of cancer-related abnormalities.
American Cancer Society guidelines for the early detection of cancer recommend that women ages 40-44 should have the choice to start annual breast cancer screening with mammograms.</description></item></channel></rss>