<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>chiropractic on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/chiropractic/</link><description>Recent content in chiropractic on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/chiropractic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Woman in her 20s has stroke, brain injury after chiropractic neck manipulation</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/woman-in-her-20s-has-stroke-brain-injury-after-chiropractic-neck-manipulation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/woman-in-her-20s-has-stroke-brain-injury-after-chiropractic-neck-manipulation/</guid><description>A young lady&amp;rsquo;s story is rare, but still familiar.
Darlene Jensen, in her 20s, had recently graduated from college with a degree in biology and chemistry, and had a promising career and life ahead of her. She had neck tension from sitting at her desk studying and decided to see a chiropractor to help loosen everything up.
Over a two-month period, she saw the chiropractor a few times. One Thursday morning, she went for a follow-up appointment for what she thought would be a routine neck adjustment.</description></item><item><title>Can chiropractic adjustment cause a brachial plexus nerve injury?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/can-chiropractic-adjustment-cause-a-brachial-plexus-nerve-injury/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/can-chiropractic-adjustment-cause-a-brachial-plexus-nerve-injury/</guid><description>A man in his 30s&amp;ndash;we&amp;rsquo;ll call him Brandon&amp;ndash; went to a chiropractor for relief from tight, sore shoulders, hands, and arms.
What is a chiropractor?
Although chiropractors are not physicians, they&amp;rsquo;re referred to as &amp;ldquo;doctors&amp;rdquo; because they hold doctoral degrees from a chiropractic school.
Chiropractors are healthcare professionals who are best known for managing back and neck pain through manipulations of the spine and neck. Many patients feel they benefit from chiropractic care and its focus on proper alignment and balance.</description></item><item><title>Chiropractic neck manipulation causes stroke, heart attack, and paralysis in woman in her 20s</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/chiropractic-neck-manipulation-causes-stroke-heart-attack-and-paralysis-in-woman-in-her-20s/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/chiropractic-neck-manipulation-causes-stroke-heart-attack-and-paralysis-in-woman-in-her-20s/</guid><description>A recent college graduate in her 20s walked into a chiropractor for a neck adjustment. Within minutes of the treatment, she:
&amp;bull; Had a heart attack
&amp;bull; Had a stroke
&amp;bull; Was unconscious for 10 minutes, requiring cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR)
&amp;bull; Was hauled out by on a gurney to an ambulance to be rushed to a hospital for emergency care
Chiropractic neck manipulations can cause deadly problems
How could this happen?</description></item><item><title>Chiropractic neck manipulation and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/chiropractic-neck-manipulation-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/chiropractic-neck-manipulation-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>For many people, chiropractors are the go-to providers of choice for back and neck pain.&amp;nbsp;
According to the National Center for Complementary and Integrated Health, chiropractors are licensed healthcare providers who emphasize the body’s ability to heal itself. Chiropractors often focus their care on the musculoskeletal system, using manual therapy and spinal manipulation to attempt to restore spinal alignment and improve joint motion.
Despite the popularity of chiropractic care, it doesn't come without risk.</description></item><item><title>Texas Supreme Court delves into allowed scope of chiropractic care</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-supreme-court-delves-into-allowed-scope-of-chiropractic-care/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-supreme-court-delves-into-allowed-scope-of-chiropractic-care/</guid><description>Recent decades have seen a struggle between physicians&amp;mdash;medical doctors and doctors of osteopathic&amp;mdash;and providers and other specialties.
As many physicians and their professional associations see it: podiatrists invade the territory of orthopedic surgeons; certified registered nurse anesthetists (CRNAs) trespass on grounds owned by anesthesiologists; optometrists encroach on areas reserved for ophthalmologists. and chiropractors expand their practice in the areas covered by physicians of all numerous specialties. Meanwhile, nurse practitioners and physician assistants are lobbying for expanded rights to practice without physician supervision.</description></item><item><title>Texas Supreme Court: Chiropractors must inform patients of known risk of vertebral artery dissection and stroke before performing neck manipulations or adjustments</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-supreme-court-chiropractors-must-inform-patients-of-known-risk-of-vertebral-artery-dissection-and-stroke-before-performing-neck-manipulations-or-adjustments/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-supreme-court-chiropractors-must-inform-patients-of-known-risk-of-vertebral-artery-dissection-and-stroke-before-performing-neck-manipulations-or-adjustments/</guid><description>In a 2012 opinion that seemed to get little attention, the Texas Supreme Court did a rare thing&amp;mdash;ruling in favor of a medical malpractice plaintiff.
Although there&amp;rsquo;s some welcome evidence that times are changing in the intermediate appellate courts, over the past two decades the Texas Supreme Court has routinely found novel ways to reverse jury verdicts in favor of victims of medical malpractice.
On November 30, 2012, the Texas Supreme Court took a surprising turn in its opinion in the case styled Aaron Felton v.</description></item><item><title>Is chiropractic care for neck pain dangerous?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/is-chiropractic-care-for-neck-pain-dangerous/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/is-chiropractic-care-for-neck-pain-dangerous/</guid><description>In my career as a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I&amp;rsquo;ve investigated a number of chiropractic malpractice cases.
While many people seem to benefit from chiropractic care, there&amp;rsquo;s a particular risk at play when a chiropractor manipulates a patient&amp;rsquo;s neck. Vertebral arteries run vertically along both sides of the back of the neck in the same area that a chiropractor adjusts. If the chiropractor&amp;rsquo;s technique is off just a bit, it can tear one of these blood vessels and cause a devastating stroke.</description></item><item><title>Chiropractor adjusts woman's neck, tears vertebral artery, causes stroke</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/chiropractor-adjusts-womans-neck-tears-vertebral-artery-causes-stroke/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/chiropractor-adjusts-womans-neck-tears-vertebral-artery-causes-stroke/</guid><description>A Texas attorney recently called Painter Law Firm to refer a client who had some shocking injuries after a chiropractic adjustment. Because medical malpractice is such a complex area of the law, we get referral calls like this frequently and are happy to step in and help.
The story started with a healthy, active woman in her 20s who was sore after a workout at her local gym. Someone from work suggested that she go see a chiropractor, and that&amp;rsquo;s what she did.</description></item><item><title>Texas chiropractor medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-chiropractor-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-chiropractor-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I handle many types of medical negligence cases, including those involving chiropractic care.
I am currently handling two cases where patients experienced a stroke because of the dissection (tear) of an artery carrying blood to the brain. In both cases, the patients presented to a hospital emergency room with unusual symptoms that should have alerted the emergency physicians of the possibility of a dissection injury that could cause a stroke.</description></item></channel></rss>