<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>methodist on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/methodist/</link><description>Recent content in methodist on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/methodist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Houston Methodist charges almost double for a surgery than the cost at a nearby academic hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-charges-almost-double-for-a-surgery-than-the-cost-at-a-nearby-academic-hospital/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-charges-almost-double-for-a-surgery-than-the-cost-at-a-nearby-academic-hospital/</guid><description>According to the focus group research, the number one reason that people select a hospital is location. Not quality. Not whether you&amp;rsquo;ll be seen by a physician as opposed to a physician assistant (PA) or nurse practitioner (NP). Not even cost. Location.
I believe some of this phenomenon is because of the lack of information available to consumers. Most hospitals advertise that they offer top-notch care. Texas law allows hospitals to conceal the credentials and performance reviews of their physicians.</description></item><item><title>When does the willful and wanton standard of proof apply in Texas ER medical malpractice cases?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/when-does-the-willful-and-wanton-standard-of-proof-apply-in-texas-er-medical-malpractice-cases/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/when-does-the-willful-and-wanton-standard-of-proof-apply-in-texas-er-medical-malpractice-cases/</guid><description>Texas law treats medical malpractice lawsuits differently from other types of negligence cases. One of the significant differences is a heightened standard of proof in some types of claims.
Texas Civil Practice &amp;amp; Remedies Code Section 74.153 mandates a standard of proof called “willful and wanton negligence” for certain emergency medical care cases. If you’re confused by what that means, join the club. Willful conduct is inconsistent with any theory of negligence, but that discussion is for another day.</description></item><item><title>Feds slap Houston Methodist Willowbrook Hospital with citation after nurse fails to give patient medication</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/feds-slap-houston-methodist-willowbrook-hospital-with-citation-after-nurse-fails-to-give-patient-medication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/feds-slap-houston-methodist-willowbrook-hospital-with-citation-after-nurse-fails-to-give-patient-medication/</guid><description>Registered nurses and physicians caring for hospitalized patients share a lot of responsibility and tasks. When it comes to medications, though, the decision to start or stop a drug is one that falls in the doctor&amp;rsquo;s lap.
In 2019, an intensive care unit (ICU) registered nurse at Houston Methodist Willowbrook Hospital learned this the hard way. Based on the nurse&amp;rsquo;s mistake, the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services issued a&amp;nbsp; violation to the hospital, on May 21, 2019, related to administration of drugs.</description></item><item><title>Painter Law Firm files medical malpractice lawsuit against Houston Methodist Hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-medical-malpractice-lawsuit-against-houston-methodist-hospital/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-medical-malpractice-lawsuit-against-houston-methodist-hospital/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm recently filed a lawsuit against Houston Methodist Hospital on behalf of a client who had lower back surgery at the hospital. The Harris County District Clerk assigned the matter as cause number 2019-27855, in the 164th District Court, where The Hon. Alexandra Smoots-Thomas is the presiding judge.
Houston Methodist Hospital, located in the Texas Medical Center, is a major academic/teaching hospital with over 2200 licensed beds. Its slogan is &amp;ldquo;Leading Medicine.</description></item><item><title>Medical malpractice/wrongful death lawsuit: Plaintiff alleges that surgeon and anesthesiologist at Houston Methodist Willowbrook Hospital injure patient, cause death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medical-malpractice/wrongful-death-lawsuit-plaintiff-alleges-that-surgeon-and-anesthesiologist-at-houston-methodist-willowbrook-hospital-injure-patient-cause-death/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medical-malpractice/wrongful-death-lawsuit-plaintiff-alleges-that-surgeon-and-anesthesiologist-at-houston-methodist-willowbrook-hospital-injure-patient-cause-death/</guid><description>On August 30, 2018, Painter Law Firm filed a medical malpractice and wrongful death lawsuit&amp;nbsp;against two physicians on the medical staff at Houston Methodist Willowbrook Hospital, which is located at 18220 Texas 249 Access Road, Houston, TX 77070. The lawsuit named a colon and rectal surgeon and an anesthesiologist&amp;nbsp;as defendants.
The lawsuit is pending in the 157th District Court of Harris County, Texas, where the Honorable Randy Wilson is the presiding judge.</description></item><item><title>Houston Methodist The Woodlands Hospital medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-the-woodlands-hospital-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-the-woodlands-hospital-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I have handled many cases involving healthcare provided at hospitals in the Houston Methodist system. Houston Methodist operates its flagship hospital in the Texas Medical Center and six community hospitals all over the greater Houston area.
The most recent addition to the Houston Methodist system, Houston Methodist The Woodlands Hospital, opened in June 2017, and is located at 17201 Interstate 45 S., The Woodlands, TX 77385.</description></item><item><title>Portal vein thrombosis diagnosis, treatment, and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/portal-vein-thrombosis-diagnosis-treatment-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/portal-vein-thrombosis-diagnosis-treatment-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I have handled many cases involving complications after surgery that led to devastating patient outcomes when they went undiagnosed and untreated for too long.
A recent case that went to trial in Harris County, Texas dealt with one such complication, portal vein thrombosis. The case is styled Kara Nguyen v. Ziad Amr., M.D., Anna Belcheva, M.D., Jorge Leiva, M.D., Andre Arash Lighvani, M.D., and The Methodist Hospital; Cause No.</description></item><item><title>Painter Law Firm files medical malpractice lawsuit against Methodist Willowbrook Hospital and spine surgeon</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-medical-malpractice-lawsuit-against-methodist-willowbrook-hospital-and-spine-surgeon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-medical-malpractice-lawsuit-against-methodist-willowbrook-hospital-and-spine-surgeon/</guid><description>I filed a medical malpractice lawsuit last Friday against Methodist Willowbrook Hospital and a spine surgeon&amp;nbsp;on behalf of our clients, Larry and Susan.
Larry walked into Methodist Willowbrook Hospital for a spine surgeon to perform L4-S1 fusion surgery to help relieve some lower back pain that was radiating into his legs. Before the surgery, Larry was able to walk, bike, and lead a healthy and active lifestyle for a 71-year-old man.</description></item><item><title>Methodist Dallas Medical Center medical malpractice lawyer/attorney</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/methodist-dallas-medical-center-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/methodist-dallas-medical-center-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I represent patients and family members in medical malpractice and wrongful death lawsuits in the Houston area, as well as all over the State of Texas.
Methodist Dallas Medical Center Methodist Dallas Medical Center is located at 1441 N. Beckley Avenue, Dallas, TX 75203. The hospital is part of the nonprofit Methodist Health System, which has multiple locations throughout the Dallas/Fort Worth Metroplex area.</description></item><item><title>Houston Methodist Hospital (Texas Medical Center) medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-hospital-texas-medical-center-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-hospital-texas-medical-center-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>Houston Methodist Hospital, located at 6565 Fannin Street, Houston, Texas 77030, in the Texas Medical Center, is the flagship institution in the Houston Methodist system.
The 2,502-bed hospital describes itself as having six multidisciplinary centers of excellence, including the DeBakey Heart &amp;amp; Vascular Center, J.C. Walter, Jr. Transplant Center, Orthopedics &amp;amp; Sports Medicine, Cancer Center, Neurological Institute, Lynda K. and David M. Underwood Center for Digestive Disorders.
In addition to offering a range of other medical specialties, Houston Methodist Hospital has a Level III trauma center and a Comprehensive Stroke Center.</description></item><item><title>Houston Methodist Sugar Land Hospital medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-sugar-land-hospital-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-sugar-land-hospital-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>Methodist Sugar Land Hospital is located at 16655 Southwest Freeway, Sugar Land, TX 77479, which is in Fort Bend County.
The hospital is a full-service acute care facility offering services and specialties including a cancer center, gastroenterology, gastrointestinal surgery, heart and vascular, neurology and neurosurgery, orthopedics and sports medicine, stroke, organ transplants, labor/delivery/birth of children, and breast care center. Methodist Sugar Land Hospital also has an emergency room and&amp;nbsp;intensive care unit (ICU).</description></item><item><title>Houston Methodist West Hospital Katy medical malpractice lawyer/attorney</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-west-hospital-katy-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-west-hospital-katy-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I represent patients and their families in medical negligence and wrongful death lawsuits involving numerous hospitals.
Three hospital chains have opened facilities all over the Houston/Harris County area. These chains include Houston Methodist, CHI St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s, and Memorial Hermann.
Houston Methodist West Hospital
Houston Methodist West Hospital is the fifth hospital in the Houston Methodist system. It is located in the West Houston/Katy area, at 18500 Katy Freeway, Houston, Texas 77094.</description></item><item><title>Houston Methodist Willowbrook Hospital medical malpractice lawyer/attorney</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-willowbrook-hospital-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-willowbrook-hospital-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I have represented a number of clients in investigating negligence claims involving Houston Methodist Willowbrook Hospital.
About the hospital
Houston Methodist Willowbrook Hospital opened in December 2000, at 18220 State Highway 249, in Houston, Harris County, Texas.
It is a 312-bed hospital that advertises itself as a regional referral hospital offering services including emergency care, cardiology, orthopedics, sports medicine, women&amp;rsquo;s services, neurology, oncology, and primary and general medicine.</description></item><item><title>Lawsuit: The Methodist Hospital ignores stroke symptoms and causes permanent brain injury</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-the-methodist-hospital-ignores-stroke-symptoms-and-causes-permanent-brain-injury/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-the-methodist-hospital-ignores-stroke-symptoms-and-causes-permanent-brain-injury/</guid><description>The Texas medical malpractice lawyers at Painter Law Firm filed a lawsuit against The Methodist Hospital (now called Houston Methodist Hospital), as well as an&amp;nbsp;emergency room doctor,&amp;nbsp;attending neurologist and neurology resident who worked at that facility. The case is pending the 113th District Court of Harris County, Texas, where Judge Michael Landrum is presiding.&amp;nbsp;
We filed the case on behalf of our client, Binti Lee, who was a 34-year-old African American woman in December 2012, when a medical malpractice tragedy occurred.</description></item></channel></rss>