<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>baby brain injury on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/baby-brain-injury/</link><description>Recent content in baby brain injury on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/baby-brain-injury/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Baby brain and birth injury cases need experienced lawyers</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baby-brain-and-birth-injury-cases-need-experienced-lawyers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baby-brain-and-birth-injury-cases-need-experienced-lawyers/</guid><description>When a newborn is needlessly injured during labor and delivery, because of poor doctor, hospital or nursing care, parents have to make an important choice in selecting a lawyer to investigate the case.
The harms and losses to the baby and family are quite often staggering. Depending on the type of injury, the baby may need a lifetime of around the clock care and therapy, as a result of brain damage or a birth injury.</description></item><item><title>How mothers can prevent infant brain injuries during birth</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-mothers-can-prevent-infant-brain-injuries-during-birth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-mothers-can-prevent-infant-brain-injuries-during-birth/</guid><description>One of the interesting things about a law practice focusing on medical malpractice cases is that I get to study and learn a lot about the medical issues surrounding my cases. I have handled a lot of cases involving brain injuries, including birth-related brain injuries. In many of those cases, the pregnancy was normal and the baby was healthy right until the very end. This is one of a series of articles I will share on how many of these permanent brain injuries could have been avoided with proper medical and nursing care.</description></item></channel></rss>