<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Awards and Honors on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/awards/</link><description>Recent content in Awards and Honors on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/awards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Receives 2024 BBB Award for Excellence</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/awards/painter-law-firm-bbb-award-for-excellence-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/awards/painter-law-firm-bbb-award-for-excellence-2024/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice has been honored with the 2024 Better Business Bureau (BBB) Award for Excellence, a testament to the firm&amp;rsquo;s unwavering dedication to serving clients with integrity, compassion, and exceptional legal expertise.
Robert Painter, founder of Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice, expressed his gratitude for the recognition in an interview with the BBB. &amp;ldquo;Our mission has always been to advocate for patients and families who have experienced life-altering injuries due to healthcare errors.</description></item><item><title>Raising the Bar: Robert Painter of Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Wins 2024 Super Lawyer Award</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/awards/super-lawyer-award-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/awards/super-lawyer-award-2024/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice, a leading Texas law firm specializing in medical malpractice, is proud to announce that its founder, Attorney Robert Painter, has been honored with the prestigious 2024 Super Lawyer Award by Thomson Reuters. This distinction is a testament to Painter&amp;rsquo;s exceptional legal expertise, his commitment to justice for injured patients, and the firm’s ongoing dedication to upholding the highest standards in the legal profession.
The Super Lawyer Award is one of the most respected accolades in the legal industry, recognizing the top five percent of attorneys nationwide who demonstrate unparalleled excellence in their fields.</description></item><item><title>Elevating Legal Standards: Painter Law Firm's Robert Painter Clinches Super Lawyer Award</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/awards/painter-law-firm-super-lawyer-award/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/awards/painter-law-firm-super-lawyer-award/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm, a renowned medical malpractice firm in Texas, dedicated to providing exceptional legal representation to clients, is thrilled to announce Attorney Robert Painter&amp;rsquo;s recent designation and achievement of the prestigious 2023 Super Lawyer Award by Thompson Reuters. This remarkable accolade underscores the firm&amp;#39;s commitment to excellence and its unwavering dedication to serving clients with the utmost professionalism and competence.&amp;nbsp;
Super Lawyers, a widely recognized and respected authority in the legal industry, identifies and celebrates the nation&amp;#39;s top attorneys across various practice areas and firm sizes.</description></item><item><title>Painter Law Firm awarded Better Business Bureau's (BBB) Award for Excellence</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/awards/painter-law-firm-bbb-award-for-excellence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/awards/painter-law-firm-bbb-award-for-excellence/</guid><description>In an interview with the Better Business Bureau (BBB), Robert Painter shared his thoughts on various aspects of the business after receiving the annual award for business excellence. When asked to describe his business and its customers, he said, "Our core law practice is to help people who have been seriously injured during health care."
Painter also explained that he started the firm to improve patient safety and the quality of healthcare, and its culture is defined by the mission to hold those responsible for medical malpractice financially accountable in the legal system.</description></item><item><title>Martindale-Hubbell recognizes Robert Painter with prestigious AV rating</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/awards/martindale-hubbell-av-rating/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/awards/martindale-hubbell-av-rating/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm is pleased to announce that Martindale-Hubbell has awarded attorney Robert Painter with the prestigious AV &amp;reg; Rating. Martindale-Hubbell has maintained ratings for lawyers for more than a century, and currently reviews or assigns ratings for over 150,000 lawyers each year. Ratings reflect the confidential opinions of bar members and the judiciary, and attest to the individual lawyer&amp;#39;s legal ability and adherence to accepted professional standards of ethics. Exclusively developed and assigned by the Martindale-Hubbell &amp;reg; Law Directory, ratings are considered valuable benchmarks intended for use by members of the profession.</description></item></channel></rss>