<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>birth injuries on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/birth-injuries/</link><description>Recent content in birth injuries on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/birth-injuries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cord Blood Gases in Birth Injury Cases: A Misunderstood Marker</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/cord-blood-gases-birth-injury/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/cord-blood-gases-birth-injury/</guid><description>During labor and delivery, obstetricians (OB/GYNs) often order umbilical cord blood gas testing to assess a newborn&amp;rsquo;s wellbeing and acid-base status at birth. While cord blood gas results can provide insight into a baby&amp;rsquo;s condition, defense experts in birth injury lawsuits often wrongly argue that normal values completely rule out hypoxic-ischemic encephalopathy (HIE), brain injuries, and other neurologic injuries.
If your child has suffered brain damage and you&amp;rsquo;re being told their cord blood gases were normal, do not accept this at face value - there is much more to the story.</description></item><item><title>Caution: Normal Apgar Scores and Prompt Legal Action for Birth Injuries</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/apgar-scores-legal-action-birth-injuries/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/apgar-scores-legal-action-birth-injuries/</guid><description>The birth of a baby boy or girl is a milestone event of life that every parent remembers. In the hustle and bustle of labor and delivery, a lot of things happen. One of the first assessments performed on a newborn is the Apgar score, a quick evaluation that’s been around since the 1950s to look at the baby&amp;rsquo;s overall health.
However, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to understand that a normal Apgar score doesn’t necessarily mean that the baby has not suffered a brain injury during labor and delivery.</description></item><item><title>Legal Time Bomb: Birth Injury Lawsuit Limitations in Texas Explained</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/birth-injury-lawsuit-limitations-in-texas-explained/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/birth-injury-lawsuit-limitations-in-texas-explained/</guid><description>Over the past few weeks, our team has talked with three sets of parents who have three and four year old children with brain injuries called hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy (HIE). Although they all believe that the injuries occurred around birth, they’ve only now started to try and hire an attorney to get much-needed help.
There are a lot of reasons parents in this situation might wait a year, or two, or three before contacting a Texas medical malpractice birth injury lawyer.</description></item></channel></rss>