<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>wrongful death on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/wrongful-death/</link><description>Recent content in wrongful death on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/wrongful-death/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Texas Supreme Court Raises Bar on ER Malpractice Cases, Leaving Victims with Limited Options</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-supreme-court-marsillo-er-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-supreme-court-marsillo-er-malpractice/</guid><description>Since 2003, tort reform measures that became law in Texas have made medical malpractice cases more difficult to pursue. When it comes to hospital emergency room (ER) care, some medical malpractice claims are downright impossible to pursue under existing law.
On January 12, 2024, the Texas Supreme Court entered an opinion to make it even harder for victims of medical malpractice in hospital emergency rooms to seek justice in Texas courtrooms.</description></item><item><title>Sickle Cell Crisis: Neglected Symptoms Cost African American Man's Life</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/sickle-cell-neglected-symptoms-african-american/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/sickle-cell-neglected-symptoms-african-american/</guid><description>Ray was a man of African descent in his late 30s. He was a married electrical engineer with three children. As a child in Africa, he&amp;rsquo;d been diagnosed with sickle cell trait. Sickle cell trait is a condition where the person carries one sickle hemoglobin gene. It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t cause severe pain or big problems.
People with sickle cell disease, on the other hand, inherit sickle hemoglobin gene from both parents. It&amp;rsquo;s a serious condition where hemoglobin and the red blood cells that carry it are sickle shaped.</description></item><item><title>How to prove a DVT/pulmonary embolism medical malpractice case in Texas</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-prove-a-dvt/pulmonary-embolism-medical-malpractice-case-in-texas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-prove-a-dvt/pulmonary-embolism-medical-malpractice-case-in-texas/</guid><description>Pulmonary embolism is a dangerous condition that starts with the formation of a blood clot, usually in the deep veins of the legs (DVT and pulmonary embolism diagnosis, treatment, and medical malpractice). When a clot breaks loose, travels, and blocks an artery supplying the lung, it is called a pulmonary embolism. When a pulmonary embolism is not diagnosed and treated properly, the mortality rate is around 30 percent. When promptly treated, the death rate is less than 10 percent.</description></item><item><title>Patient dies from nursing home fall despite documented high risk</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/patient-dies-from-nursing-home-fall-despite-documented-high-risk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/patient-dies-from-nursing-home-fall-despite-documented-high-risk/</guid><description>A physician friend of mine recently commented on social media that, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m old enough to remember when surgeons would take patients to the OR [operating room] for appys [appendix removal surgery] or cholecystitis [gallbladder inflammation] based on the physical exam and history. I still love those old school surgeons.&amp;rdquo;
Her comment got me thinking about how old school medical care is different than what’s touted as improved care today. Some hospitals and facilities create systems that try and force physicians, physician assistants, nurse practitioners, and nurses to serve metrics and computers rather than the patients they&amp;rsquo;re supposed to be taking care of.</description></item><item><title>$4 million for pregnant mom who died after C-Section</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/4-million-for-pregnant-mom-who-died-after-c-section/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/4-million-for-pregnant-mom-who-died-after-c-section/</guid><description>The parties to a preeclampsia medical negligence lawsuit reached a $4 million settlement after a pregnant mother died in the hospital shortly after an emergency C-section delivery.
Preeclampsia is a type of high blood pressure that affects some pregnant women, typically developing in the last half of pregnancy. The two classic signs that obstetricians (OB/GYNs) look for in prenatal care are high blood pressure and abnormally high levels of protein in the urine (proteinuria).</description></item><item><title>Houston Court of Appeals rules against hospitalist physician in Houston Methodist Hospital fall case</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-court-of-appeals-rules-against-hospitalist-physician-in-houston-methodist-hospital-fall-case/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-court-of-appeals-rules-against-hospitalist-physician-in-houston-methodist-hospital-fall-case/</guid><description>Everyone who works in healthcare should know that patient falls should never occur in a hospital or nursing home setting. That&amp;rsquo;s why they&amp;rsquo;re called sentinel or never events.
A recent opinion entered by Houston&amp;rsquo;s 14th Court of Appeals illustrates how fall prevention is a responsibility shared by physicians and nurses. The case is styled Dhruti B. Patel, MD v. Michael Baker, Individually and As Representative of the Estate of Deanne Baker; No.</description></item><item><title>Outpatient imaging centers and the increased risk of brain injury or death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/outpatient-imaging-centers-and-the-increased-risk-of-brain-injury-or-death/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/outpatient-imaging-centers-and-the-increased-risk-of-brain-injury-or-death/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a tragic case involving the death of a middle-aged man who went for a routine CT scan for contrast at an outpatient imaging center in the Dallas area. His primary care doctor referred him there because of suspected kidney stones.
The autopsy revealed that this father and husband died from an anaphylactic reaction to the iodine-containing CT contrast media that a CT technologist administered to him intravenously (by IV) shortly before his CT scan.</description></item><item><title>Texas medical malpractice tort reform restrictions apply to events that occur after a patient's death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-medical-malpractice-tort-reform-restrictions-apply-to-events-that-occur-after-a-patients-death/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-medical-malpractice-tort-reform-restrictions-apply-to-events-that-occur-after-a-patients-death/</guid><description>I had an interesting conversation this morning with an attorney friend about whether Texas tort reform law applies to circumstances following a patient&amp;rsquo;s death. When time allows, I enjoy being a resource for other lawyers with questions about medical malpractice or health law matters.
The specific situation involved a patient who died at a hospital. The body was dropped as it was being moved within the facility, causing facial damage that resulted in a closed-casket funeral.</description></item><item><title>San Antonio lawsuit: Pulmonologist discharged post-surgical patient with unrepaired cut artery, bleed-out risk</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/san-antonio-lawsuit-pulmonologist-discharged-post-surgical-patient-with-unrepaired-cut-artery-bleed-out-risk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/san-antonio-lawsuit-pulmonologist-discharged-post-surgical-patient-with-unrepaired-cut-artery-bleed-out-risk/</guid><description>It seems that you would need a medical expert to tell you that it would be negligence to discharge a patient from the hospital has an unrepaired cut artery. That was the issue before the San Antonio Court of Appeals recently, though, in case styled Pradyumna Mummady, MD v. Zulema Cabrera, No. 04-21-00012-CV. You can read the opinion here.
The facts of this medical malpractice wrongful death case began with the patient being admitted to Laredo Medical Center to have his tonsils and adenoids removed.</description></item><item><title>Houston court of appeals dismisses Pseudomonas infant death case</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-court-of-appeals-dismisses-pseudomonas-infant-death-case/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-court-of-appeals-dismisses-pseudomonas-infant-death-case/</guid><description>Houston&amp;rsquo;s 14th Court of Appeals recently entered an opinion in a medical malpractice wrongful death claim involving the death of a twin infant who was born prematurely at 25 weeks into pregnancy. The case is styled C-HCA, Inc d/b/a Clear Lake Regional Medical Center v. Cornett; No. 14-1900580-CV, In the 14th Court of Appeals. You can read the court&amp;rsquo;s opinion here.
Body part versus baby
I&amp;rsquo;m always saddened when a parent experiences the death of a child because of medical malpractice.</description></item><item><title>COVID-19's impact on medical malpractice cases</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/covid-19s-impact-on-medical-malpractice-cases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/covid-19s-impact-on-medical-malpractice-cases/</guid><description>I keep reading a lot online or in the media about how some are expecting a delusion of medical malpractice lawsuits arriving from COVID-19 care. I&amp;rsquo;ve told everyone who’s asked me that I don&amp;rsquo;t see that happening.
Competent, experienced medical malpractice lawyers in Texas realize that one requirement to pursue any medical malpractice case is to produce expert testimony that defines the applicable standard of care. Generally speaking, the standard of care is what a reasonably prudent hospital/doctor/health care provider would have done under the same or similar circumstances.</description></item><item><title>What can the trial court consider at a Chapter 74 preliminary expert report hearing in a Texas medical malpractice case?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-can-the-trial-court-consider-at-a-chapter-74-preliminary-expert-report-hearing-in-a-texas-medical-malpractice-case/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-can-the-trial-court-consider-at-a-chapter-74-preliminary-expert-report-hearing-in-a-texas-medical-malpractice-case/</guid><description>Texas law requires medical malpractice plaintiffs to produce one or more medical expert reports within 120 days of each defendant filing an answer and a lawsuit. The standards for these reports are demanding, requiring separate statements of the applicable standard of care (what should have been done), how the standard of care was violated (what wasn&amp;rsquo;t done correctly), and how those medical mistakes proximately caused harm to the plaintiff.
How do defendants respond to the preliminary expert reports, and what are the potential consequences?</description></item><item><title>When does the willful and wanton standard of proof apply in Texas ER medical malpractice cases?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/when-does-the-willful-and-wanton-standard-of-proof-apply-in-texas-er-medical-malpractice-cases/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/when-does-the-willful-and-wanton-standard-of-proof-apply-in-texas-er-medical-malpractice-cases/</guid><description>Texas law treats medical malpractice lawsuits differently from other types of negligence cases. One of the significant differences is a heightened standard of proof in some types of claims.
Texas Civil Practice &amp;amp; Remedies Code Section 74.153 mandates a standard of proof called “willful and wanton negligence” for certain emergency medical care cases. If you’re confused by what that means, join the club. Willful conduct is inconsistent with any theory of negligence, but that discussion is for another day.</description></item><item><title>How do caps apply to what I can recover in a wrongful death medical malpractice lawsuit in Texas?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-do-caps-apply-to-what-i-can-recover-in-a-wrongful-death-medical-malpractice-lawsuit-in-texas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-do-caps-apply-to-what-i-can-recover-in-a-wrongful-death-medical-malpractice-lawsuit-in-texas/</guid><description>Unfortunately, Texas victims of medical malpractice face the toughest, least fair caps on damages in America. With the lack of financial accountability that Texas hospitals and physicians have under so-called tort reform laws, there&amp;rsquo;s little wonder why Texas healthcare ranks near the bottom when it comes to patient safety.
In wrongful death medical malpractice cases, there are actually two separate caps that apply to every case.
The first cap, on non-economic damages, applies to every medical malpractice case in Texas courts.</description></item><item><title>How does a Texas wrongful death lawsuit work when multiple family members are involved?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-does-a-texas-wrongful-death-lawsuit-work-when-multiple-family-members-are-involved/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-does-a-texas-wrongful-death-lawsuit-work-when-multiple-family-members-are-involved/</guid><description>Like other states, the Texas wrongful death statute defines which family members can file a lawsuit when a person&amp;rsquo;s death is caused by another&amp;rsquo;s negligence. Relatives that are legally allowed to file a wrongful death lawsuit are called wrongful death beneficiaries.
States differ in how they defined these wrongful death beneficiaries. Under Texas law, wrongful death beneficiaries include the following relatives of the deceased person:
&amp;bull; Spouse (whether a ceremonial or common-law marriage)</description></item><item><title>How does the wrongful death cap work in a Texas medical malpractice lawsuit?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-does-the-wrongful-death-cap-work-in-a-texas-medical-malpractice-lawsuit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-does-the-wrongful-death-cap-work-in-a-texas-medical-malpractice-lawsuit/</guid><description>When it comes to a wrongful death claim that&amp;rsquo;s related to medical malpractice, there are two different types of caps that you need to be aware of.
The first cap applies to all medical malpractice cases, whether a death is involved or not. Texas law imposes a cap on non-economic damages. Non-economic damages are those serious, yet intangible, injuries including pain-and-suffering, mental anguish, physical impairment, physical disfigurement, and even the loss of a loved one.</description></item><item><title>Texas nursing home wrongful death lawsuit alleges poor bedsore prevention and treatment</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-nursing-home-wrongful-death-lawsuit-alleges-poor-bedsore-prevention-and-treatment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-nursing-home-wrongful-death-lawsuit-alleges-poor-bedsore-prevention-and-treatment/</guid><description>Many families turn to nursing homes for help in providing the best care to their aging or ailing loved ones.
I&amp;rsquo;ve had numerous clients who explained to me that they wanted to take care of their family members themselves but couldn&amp;rsquo;t do so because of work, space, or their own physical limitations. When placing a family member in a nursing home, they expected their loved one to be properly cared for.</description></item><item><title>Federal report: Patient dies in Houston hospital ER because of lab communication breakdown</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/federal-report-patient-dies-in-houston-hospital-er-because-of-lab-communication-breakdown/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/federal-report-patient-dies-in-houston-hospital-er-because-of-lab-communication-breakdown/</guid><description>Another hospital in Houston&amp;rsquo;s Texas Medical Center was recently sanctioned by the federal government over a patient death. This time it was Ben Taub Hospital, the flagship public hospital of the Harris Health System.
According to both state and federal investigations, a patient died because of the failure to communicate critical lab values to appropriate personnel. As a former hospital administrator, I was disappointed, but not surprised, to see that Ben Taub leadership did not self-report this serious violation of the standard of care.</description></item><item><title>Who can file a Texas wrongful death medical malpractice lawsuit?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/who-can-file-a-texas-wrongful-death-medical-malpractice-lawsuit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/who-can-file-a-texas-wrongful-death-medical-malpractice-lawsuit/</guid><description>The Texas wrongful death statute defines who&amp;rsquo;s legally able to file a lawsuit related to the negligence that caused the death of a person. These individuals are called wrongful death beneficiaries and are limited to the spouse, parents, and children of the deceased person (decedent).
In a medical malpractice context, the plaintiffs still have to prove that a hospital or physician proximately caused the death of the decedent by not meeting the standard of care.</description></item><item><title>Who can file a Texas medical malpractice lawsuit when a patient dies?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/who-can-file-a-texas-medical-malpractice-lawsuit-when-a-patient-dies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/who-can-file-a-texas-medical-malpractice-lawsuit-when-a-patient-dies/</guid><description>Each state has a wrongful death statute that answers the question of who can file a lawsuit when a person dies because of someone else&amp;rsquo;s negligence. These individuals are called wrongful death beneficiaries and under Texas law they&amp;rsquo;re limited to the surviving parents, spouse, and children of the deceased person.
A surviving spouse can be from a traditional ceremonial marriage or a common law marriage. Texas has rather liberal standards for recognizing a common law marriage.</description></item><item><title>Painter Law Firm files medical malpractice lawsuit involving man's death at Christus St. Elizabeth Hospital in Beaumont, Texas</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-medical-malpractice-lawsuit-involving-mans-death-at-christus-st.-elizabeth-hospital-in-beaumont-texas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-medical-malpractice-lawsuit-involving-mans-death-at-christus-st.-elizabeth-hospital-in-beaumont-texas/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm recently filed a medical malpractice wrongful death lawsuit against Christus St. Elizabeth Hospital, in Beaumont, Texas. The Jefferson County District Clerk assigned the case a cause number B-203726, in the 60th District Court, where The Hon. Justin Sanderson is the presiding judge. You can read the original petition here.
Christus St. Elizabeth Hospital is a 431-bed acute care hospital located at 2830 Calder Avenue, Beaumont, Texas 77702.</description></item><item><title>What to do when you think thereâ€™s a hospital cover-up</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-to-do-when-you-think-there%C3%A2s-a-hospital-cover-up/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-to-do-when-you-think-there%C3%A2s-a-hospital-cover-up/</guid><description>I frequently have conversations with clients who have a gut feeling that their doctors, nurses, and hospital representatives aren&amp;rsquo;t being totally honest with them. Sometimes, they believe they&amp;rsquo;re outright lying to them about something bad that happened during a hospitalization.
How we investigate medical coverups
As an experienced medical malpractice attorney and a former hospital administrator, I know where to look to get to the bottom of mysteries like this.</description></item><item><title>Medical malpractice/wrongful death lawsuit: Plaintiff alleges that surgeon and anesthesiologist at Houston Methodist Willowbrook Hospital injure patient, cause death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medical-malpractice/wrongful-death-lawsuit-plaintiff-alleges-that-surgeon-and-anesthesiologist-at-houston-methodist-willowbrook-hospital-injure-patient-cause-death/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medical-malpractice/wrongful-death-lawsuit-plaintiff-alleges-that-surgeon-and-anesthesiologist-at-houston-methodist-willowbrook-hospital-injure-patient-cause-death/</guid><description>On August 30, 2018, Painter Law Firm filed a medical malpractice and wrongful death lawsuit&amp;nbsp;against two physicians on the medical staff at Houston Methodist Willowbrook Hospital, which is located at 18220 Texas 249 Access Road, Houston, TX 77070. The lawsuit named a colon and rectal surgeon and an anesthesiologist&amp;nbsp;as defendants.
The lawsuit is pending in the 157th District Court of Harris County, Texas, where the Honorable Randy Wilson is the presiding judge.</description></item><item><title>Painter Law Firm files medical malpractice wrongful death lawsuit against Kirby Surgical Center, others</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-medical-malpractice-wrongful-death-lawsuit-against-kirby-surgical-center-others/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-medical-malpractice-wrongful-death-lawsuit-against-kirby-surgical-center-others/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm filed a lawsuit today on behalf of our client, a widow and wrongful death beneficiary,&amp;nbsp;involving the care that her husband, Bobby Meeks, received at Kirby Surgical Center, leading to his death in March 2018.
Bobby, who was 36-years -old when he died, was a popular school teacher at Dekaney High School. He injured his left shoulder while breaking up a fight between two students and was referred to for an arthroscopy shoulder surgery at Kirby Surgical Center.</description></item><item><title>High school senior dies after doctors botch diagnosis and treatment of acute disseminated encephalomalacia (ADEM)</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/high-school-senior-dies-after-doctors-botch-diagnosis-and-treatment-of-acute-disseminated-encephalomalacia-adem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/high-school-senior-dies-after-doctors-botch-diagnosis-and-treatment-of-acute-disseminated-encephalomalacia-adem/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, every day my law firm hears tragic stories from clients&amp;nbsp;about how lives were changed or ended because of poor medical care.
This week, we met with new clients about a terribly sad situation. Let me tell you their story.
One morning, the parents of a Houston-area high school senior found her on the floor in a room, nauseated and unable to get up or walk.</description></item><item><title>Medical malpractice lawsuit by Bill Paxton's family shows how wrongful death claims work</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medical-malpractice-lawsuit-by-bill-paxtons-family-shows-how-wrongful-death-claims-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medical-malpractice-lawsuit-by-bill-paxtons-family-shows-how-wrongful-death-claims-work/</guid><description>Around a year ago, Fort Worth, Texas native Bill Paxton died just 11 days after surgery in a Los Angeles hospital. His family recently filed a wrongful death and medical malpractice lawsuit against the hospital.
What is a wrongful death claim?
At common law, when a person died, all claims and causes actions of that person also died, as did all losses of family members as a result of the loved one&amp;rsquo;s death.</description></item><item><title>Medical malpractice lawsuit: Former co-lead singer of The Eagles died from poor medical diagnosis and treatment</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medical-malpractice-lawsuit-former-co-lead-singer-of-the-eagles-died-from-poor-medical-diagnosis-and-treatment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medical-malpractice-lawsuit-former-co-lead-singer-of-the-eagles-died-from-poor-medical-diagnosis-and-treatment/</guid><description>Singer and guitarist Glenn Frey was a co-founder and former co-lead singer of The Eagles. According to a recent wrongful death lawsuit, he was a victim of medical malpractice. He died in January 2016, at the age of 67, from complications from acute ulcerative colitis, pneumonia, and rheumatoid arthritis.
Frey&amp;rsquo;s widow sued a New York hospital and gastroenterologist, alleging a failure to properly treat his ulcerative colitis, diagnose and treat an infection, and advise of the risks and side effects from treatment.</description></item><item><title>Lawsuit alleges freestanding ER and trainee doctor cause girlâ€™s death of bacterial meningitis</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-alleges-freestanding-er-and-trainee-doctor-cause-girl%C3%A2s-death-of-bacterial-meningitis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-alleges-freestanding-er-and-trainee-doctor-cause-girl%C3%A2s-death-of-bacterial-meningitis/</guid><description>In my law practice as a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I have represented many clients in cases involving bad emergency room care.
Texas is home to more freestanding emergency rooms than any other state in America. You probably have seen them before&amp;mdash;they are popping up in strip malls and neighborhoods all over Houston. They are called &amp;ldquo;freestanding&amp;rdquo; because they are not connected to a hospital.
Regardless of whether a patient goes to a hospital emergency room or a freestanding ER, there is an expectation of being treated by a trained emergency physician.</description></item><item><title>Two risks for families in accepting a rushed diagnosis of brain death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/two-risks-for-families-in-accepting-a-rushed-diagnosis-of-brain-death/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/two-risks-for-families-in-accepting-a-rushed-diagnosis-of-brain-death/</guid><description>As a Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I have frequently spoken with families about what to do when a doctor tells them that a loved one is brain dead.
Most people faced with this will have a sudden flood of emotions including emotions of grief and shock. On top of that, they have to confront trying to understand brain death and whether their loved one is really brain dead. This is always a topic of discussion when I speak with families going through this type of situation.</description></item><item><title>Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer Robert Painter files lawsuit that claims: Doctor &amp; CVS prescription error causes patient death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-lawyer-robert-painter-files-lawsuit-that-claims-doctor-cvs-prescription-error-causes-patient-death/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-lawyer-robert-painter-files-lawsuit-that-claims-doctor-cvs-prescription-error-causes-patient-death/</guid><description>The Houston medical malpractice attorneys at Painter Law Firm filed a wrongful death lawsuit against CVS Pharmacy, Inc. and a local OB/GYN doctor, concerning the tragic and needless death of a 37-year-old wife and mother of two.
In August 2012, this lady saw an OB/GYN because her monthly cycle had lasted for 14 days, and it was heavy and unusually painful. The OB/GYN prescribed Lysteda, a medication that prevents blood clots from breaking down, which the patient then filled at CVS Pharmacy, Inc.</description></item><item><title>Memorial Hermann Southeast Hospital anesthesia team overdoses Propofol, causing death of 45-year-old woman</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-southeast-hospital-anesthesia-team-overdoses-propofol-causing-death-of-45-year-old-woman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-southeast-hospital-anesthesia-team-overdoses-propofol-causing-death-of-45-year-old-woman/</guid><description>Attorney Robert Painter&amp;nbsp;filed a wrongful death medical malpractice lawsuit against Memorial Hermann Southeast Hospital, and an anesthesiologist and certified registered nurse anesthetist (CRNA) who work at the hospital, concerning the needless death of 45-year-old Michelle Hunt. The case is pending in the 127th District Court of Harris County, Texas, where Judge R.K. Sandhill presides.
In April 2014, Michelle walked into Memorial Hermann Southeast Hospital, for what she expected would be a short, in-and-out evaluation.</description></item><item><title>Rising health care costs aren't because of medical malpractice claims</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/rising-health-care-costs-arent-because-of-medical-malpractice-claims/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/rising-health-care-costs-arent-because-of-medical-malpractice-claims/</guid><description>Fewer medical malpractice payments were made on behalf of doctors in 2009 than any year on record, according to an update of the National Practitioner Data Bank that was released this week.
The data contradict claims by some that medical malpractice litigation is to blame for rising health care costs. In contrast, the recent data show that changing the liability system to the detriment of patients will not curb health care costs.</description></item></channel></rss>