<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>drugs and medications on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/drugs-and-medications/</link><description>Recent content in drugs and medications on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/drugs-and-medications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Did a Hospital's Medication Error Cause Your Loved One's Heart Attack?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medication-error-plavix/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medication-error-plavix/</guid><description>When 62-year-old Michael Thompson had a cardiac stent procedure at his local hospital in north Texas, he and his wife Sharon believed that the worst was behind them.
About a week earlier, Michael saw his cardiologist because he had new chest pain and shortness of breath when he took short walks. His cardiologist scheduled him for a stent placement at the cardiac catheterization lab (cath lab) to open a blocked coronary artery - a condition sometimes called the &amp;ldquo;widow maker.</description></item><item><title>Pharmacy Malpractice in Texas: All You Need to Know</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/pharmacy-malpractice-texas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/pharmacy-malpractice-texas/</guid><description>When you fill a prescription at your local, grocery, or chain pharmacy, you trust that the highly trained pharmacist will dispense the correct medication at the proper dosage. But far too often, pharmacy errors lead to dangerous drug interactions, overdoses, and even death. If you or a loved one has been seriously harmed by a medication mistake, you may be entitled to significant compensation under Texas law.
Types of Pharmacy Errors Pharmacy errors can take many forms, but some of the most common include:</description></item><item><title>One state's investigation finds CVS errors in 20% of prescriptions</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/one-states-investigation-finds-cvs-errors-in-20-of-prescriptions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/one-states-investigation-finds-cvs-errors-in-20-of-prescriptions/</guid><description>Would you be surprised to learn that the fourth largest company in the United States is the pharmacy chain CVS Health? (That&amp;rsquo;s according to 2022 total revenue data).
Despite all of those resources, some pharmacists and pharmacy techs complain that mega pharmacy CVS stores are plagued by understaffing that put patients at needless risk.
One state&amp;rsquo;s pharmacy board investigated CVS pharmacies in its jurisdiction in 2019&amp;ndash;2020 and found an error rate of over 20%&amp;mdash;that&amp;rsquo;s 1 out of every 5 prescriptions filled!</description></item><item><title>Medication mix-up causes death of shoulder surgery patient</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medication-mix-up-causes-death-of-shoulder-surgery-patient/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medication-mix-up-causes-death-of-shoulder-surgery-patient/</guid><description>An academic orthopedic surgeon who&amp;rsquo;s part of a medical school faculty was recently ordered to get more training for remedial education by a state medical board over operating room care. What happened that led to this?
A patient&amp;mdash;we&amp;rsquo;ll call him Bill&amp;mdash;was a man in his late 50s who went to an ambulatory surgery center (ASC) for left shoulder arthroscopy (shoulder surgery) with rotator cuff repair.
Before the surgery began, the operating room (OR) team observed a surgical time-out or huddle.</description></item><item><title>Crisis center ignores signs of toxic lithium levels, cause brain damage in patient</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/crisis-center-ignores-signs-of-toxic-lithium-levels-cause-brain-damage-in-patient/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/crisis-center-ignores-signs-of-toxic-lithium-levels-cause-brain-damage-in-patient/</guid><description>A woman in her 40s went to a Texas crisis unit. Let&amp;rsquo;s call her Lorena.
The Texas Department of Health and Human Services explains that a crisis unit is a respite unit where people deemed to have a low risk of harm to themselves or others can stay for as long as seven days. Although crisis units aren&amp;rsquo;t normal acute-care hospitals, they do have professional staff on hand to provide counseling and medication.</description></item><item><title>Pitocin causes excessive contractions, brain injury in baby</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/pitocin-causes-excessive-contractions-brain-injury-in-baby/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/pitocin-causes-excessive-contractions-brain-injury-in-baby/</guid><description>Obstetricians (OB/GYNs) sometimes recommend induction of labor when a pregnant woman reaches full term but hasn&amp;rsquo;t delivered her baby.
What is induction of labor?
Doctors and labor and delivery nurses induce labor by injecting Pitocin (a manufactured form of oxytocin) into an intravenous (IV) line. Pitocin causes the uterus to start contracting and often succeeds in getting active labor underway before it would&amp;rsquo;ve happened on its own.
Sometimes induction of labor is largely for convenience, but there are a variety of medical reasons why a physician may recommend it:</description></item><item><title>The nurse's role in medication safety</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-nurses-role-in-medication-safety/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-nurses-role-in-medication-safety/</guid><description>When I take the deposition of a registered nurse (RN), I often ask questions about the administration of medications. Nurses and their attorneys often try the &amp;ldquo;Nuremberg defense&amp;rdquo; of &amp;ldquo;I was just following orders,&amp;rdquo; but in reality, nurses owe their patients a higher level of care.
Texas Board of Nursing Rule 217.11(1)(C) requires all nurses (not just RNs) to know the rationale for and the effects of medications and to correctly administer them.</description></item><item><title>Gabapentin linked to overdose deaths, medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/gabapentin-linked-to-overdose-deaths-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/gabapentin-linked-to-overdose-deaths-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>Gabapentin (Neurontin) is a frequently prescribed medication that has recently been in the news for causing serious complications and injuries even death.
FDA-approved uses
According to the U.S. Food &amp;amp; Drug Administration (FDA), gabapentin is indicated for two uses:
&amp;bull; Post-herpetic neuralgia in adults.
&amp;bull; Treatment of seizures. The product label lists warnings and precautions including drug reactions, anaphylaxis, driving impairment, somnolence/sedation, dizziness, and even suicidal thoughts.
Off-label uses
When the Neurontin patent expired in 2004, it became available as a generic medication called gabapentin.</description></item><item><title>Ativan and opioids are a risky duo</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/ativan-and-opioids-are-a-risky-duo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/ativan-and-opioids-are-a-risky-duo/</guid><description>Ativan (lorazepam) is a medication in a class of drugs called benzodiazepines.
The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approved Ativan to treat anxiety, sleep disturbances, and seizures. It&amp;rsquo;s also sometimes administered shortly before anesthesia.
Ativan overdoses
This common drug has been in the news from time to time over claims that it&amp;rsquo;s been involved in causing patients to commit self-harm or suicide. For example, in 2017, rock star Chris Cornell was found dead from suicide.</description></item><item><title>Lawsuit alleges Walgreens pharmacist gave man wrong prescription drug</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-alleges-walgreens-pharmacist-gave-man-wrong-prescription-drug/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-alleges-walgreens-pharmacist-gave-man-wrong-prescription-drug/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s a CVS pharmacy down the street from our office. Day and night, that place stays busy. Chain and independent pharmacies in Texas and throughout the United States fill and dispense thousands of prescriptions every day.
Most of the time, the drug-filling process starts with an electronic prescription generated and transmitted by a physician, physician assistant, or nurse practitioner. Some prescriptions, though, begin with the patient delivering a paper prescription to the pharmacy.</description></item><item><title>4 questions you can ask to help avoid anesthesia malpractice in dental offices</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/4-questions-you-can-ask-to-help-avoid-anesthesia-malpractice-in-dental-offices/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/4-questions-you-can-ask-to-help-avoid-anesthesia-malpractice-in-dental-offices/</guid><description>Pediatric dental anesthesia is in the news again after a Houston district court jury awarded a verdict of nearly $100 million to the family of a brain-injured little girl named Nevaeh Hall. The award will be subject to reduction by the court to comply with Texas tort reform laws, but still communicates the jury&amp;rsquo;s outrage at what happened to this four-year-old dental patient.
Bethaniel Jefferson, DDS was Nevaeh&amp;rsquo;s treating dentist. The following information is from the dental malpractice lawsuit pleadings.</description></item><item><title>When nurses override medication warnings, it places patients at a higher risk</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/when-nurses-override-medication-warnings-it-places-patients-at-a-higher-risk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/when-nurses-override-medication-warnings-it-places-patients-at-a-higher-risk/</guid><description>Giving medication in a hospital setting isn&amp;rsquo;t always as straight-forward as it seems. It&amp;rsquo;s certainly not something to be rushed.
One nursing publication describes the 10 rights of drug administration as:
&amp;bull; Right drug
&amp;bull; Right patient
&amp;bull; Right dose
&amp;bull; Right route
&amp;bull; Time and frequency
&amp;bull; Documentation
&amp;bull; History and assessment
&amp;bull; Drug-drug interaction and evaluation
&amp;bull; Drug approach and right to refuse
&amp;bull; Education and information
Hospital pharmacists have robust responsibilities when it comes to patient safety.</description></item><item><title>Surgical patients may require anticoagulation medications because of DVT risk</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/surgical-patients-may-require-anticoagulation-medications-because-of-dvt-risk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/surgical-patients-may-require-anticoagulation-medications-because-of-dvt-risk/</guid><description>A significant risk of virtually any major surgery is developing blood clots in the deep veins of the legs. This is a condition called deep vein thrombosis (DVT). DVTs most commonly develop in the veins of the calf or thigh.
The danger of DVTs happens if part of the blood clot breaks off. The traveling clot is called an embolism. More particularly, it&amp;rsquo;s called a pulmonary embolism if the dislodged blood clot reaches the lungs, where it can cause the deadly complication of disrupting blood flow to the lungs and heart.</description></item><item><title>Direct oral anticoagulants (DOACs) and surgical risk</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/direct-oral-anticoagulants-doacs-and-surgical-risk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/direct-oral-anticoagulants-doacs-and-surgical-risk/</guid><description>One of the important shared responsibilities that nurses, doctors, and patients have upon hospital admission is medication reconciliation. This is the process where a list of the patient&amp;rsquo;s existing medications is assembled and documented in the medical record.
It&amp;rsquo;s critical that patients provide a complete and accurate list to the nursing staff and physicians because this information is necessary to prevent drug-drug interactions, appropriately plan treatment, and to implement certain precautions.</description></item><item><title>Herpes simplex virus encephalitis treatment and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/herpes-simplex-virus-encephalitis-treatment-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/herpes-simplex-virus-encephalitis-treatment-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>A recent opinion entered by the Amarillo Court of Appeals provides some interesting insights about the standard of care for treatment of herpes simplex virus type 2 (HSV-2) and encephalitis. The case is styled Alexandra Boske, MD and St. David&amp;rsquo;s Neurology, PLLC, Gayatri Velayudhan Nair, MD and Austin Infectious Disease Consultants, PA v. Kristin Rougeau, No. 07&amp;ndash;20-002285-CV. You can read the opinion here.
Of course, based on the nature of this interrogatory appeal, the defendant healthcare providers felt that the reports from plaintiff&amp;rsquo;s infectious diseases and neurology expert physicians failed to provide sufficient evidence about the allegations.</description></item><item><title>Errors in medication management are in 2020's top 10 list of most common sentinel/never events</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/errors-in-medication-management-are-in-2020s-top-10-list-of-most-common-sentinel/never-events/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/errors-in-medication-management-are-in-2020s-top-10-list-of-most-common-sentinel/never-events/</guid><description>The Joint Commission, the nation&amp;rsquo;s oldest healthcare accrediting organization, recently announced that errors in medication management was in the top 10 list of sentinel events in 2020.
Sentinel events are also called never events because they&amp;rsquo;re considered to be avoidable with proper policies, procedures, and staff training. When they occur, hospitals leaders must conduct a root cause analysis to find out what system and personnel failures led to the sentinel event, and what changes can be made to avoid them from harming future patients.</description></item><item><title>What you should know about pharmacy and medication errors</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-pharmacy-and-medication-errors/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-pharmacy-and-medication-errors/</guid><description>Study after study has found that some the most common causes of death in the United States are related to healthcare events. One is medication errors, accounting for 7,000 to 9,000 deaths a year.
As a former hospital administrator, it&amp;rsquo;s confounding to me that the healthcare industry can&amp;rsquo;t consistently correct this common mistake.
On the other hand, with nearly 7,000 prescription and over-the-counter drugs available in America, along with innumerable supplements, it&amp;rsquo;s foreseeable pharmacists and prescribers could encounter occasional problems.</description></item><item><title>Hyponatremia, managing sodium levels, and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/hyponatremia-managing-sodium-levels-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/hyponatremia-managing-sodium-levels-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>Sodium is a natural electrolyte that must be kept in careful balance in our bodies because of its critical role in fluid balance.
Serum sodium is the laboratory test used to measure the level of sodium in the blood. Laboratories have a reference range for any test. For most labs, a normal serum sodium level is 135&amp;ndash;145 mEq/L. When a serum sodium is below 135 mEq/L, its abnormally low and is described by the diagnosis of hyponatremia.</description></item><item><title>Medication error temporarily paralyzes Houston patient, causes brain injury</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medication-error-temporarily-paralyzes-houston-patient-causes-brain-injury/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medication-error-temporarily-paralyzes-houston-patient-causes-brain-injury/</guid><description>Medication errors come in all shapes and sizes.
We&amp;rsquo;ve recently been working on a case where a major pharmacy chain dispensed and filled a prescription for a heart medication. The same bottle contained some pills for the correct medication that was ordered by the patient&amp;rsquo;s doctor and other pills that were a different medication. When the man took the medication, he became extremely dizzy and had an irregular heartbeat. His coworkers called an ambulance that took him to a hospital, where his doctors and nurses fortunately discovered the medication error.</description></item><item><title>What you should know about the four most common medication errors</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-the-four-most-common-medication-errors/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-the-four-most-common-medication-errors/</guid><description>Medical malpractice or negligence happens when a doctor, nurse, tech, or hospital makes a mistake that&amp;rsquo;s beneath the standard of care.
There are some health care mistakes that should never be made, though. They&amp;rsquo;re called sentinel events, or never events. Any time they occur, the standard of care requires a root cause analysis. A root cause analysis allows hospital leaders to figure out what went wrong and identify the root cause so the sentinel event won&amp;rsquo;t be repeated in the future.</description></item><item><title>Coumadin (warfarin) prescription, management, and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/coumadin-warfarin-prescription-management-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/coumadin-warfarin-prescription-management-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>Coumadin generally
Coumadin (generic name warfarin) is a prescription drug that&amp;rsquo;s a blood thinner, or anticoagulant. Warfarin has been around since the 1940s and works by reducing the formation of blood clots.
Doctors frequently write long-term prescriptions for coumadin to prevent heart attacks, strokes, or other cardiovascular conditions.
Coumadin/warfarin use doesn&amp;rsquo;t come without risks, though. The most prominent risks are that it can decrease the body&amp;rsquo;s ability to stop internal bleeding and even cause death if the dosage is incorrect.</description></item><item><title>The peril of automatically blaming concerning signs and symptoms on narcotic medication effect</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-peril-of-automatically-blaming-concerning-signs-and-symptoms-on-narcotic-medication-effect/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-peril-of-automatically-blaming-concerning-signs-and-symptoms-on-narcotic-medication-effect/</guid><description>When a hospitalized patient is recovering from a surgery, there must be a careful balance between pain control and over-medication, which can mask signs and symptoms that there&amp;rsquo;s a serious complication.
Carefully monitoring how a patient responds to pain medications is a responsibility that is shared by surgeons, other physicians, and hospital nursing staff. While doctors write orders for pain medications, registered nurses are the ones who typically administer medications and continuously see what&amp;rsquo;s going on with the patient.</description></item><item><title>Under-staffing at pharmacies may lead to medication errors, danger to patients</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/under-staffing-at-pharmacies-may-lead-to-medication-errors-danger-to-patients/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/under-staffing-at-pharmacies-may-lead-to-medication-errors-danger-to-patients/</guid><description>A Texas pharmacist made an alarming admission in an anonymous letter to the Texas State Board of Pharmacy last year. The pharmacist wrote, &amp;ldquo;I am a danger to the public working for CVS.&amp;rdquo;
The anonymous letter went on to explain that CVS imposes an &amp;ldquo;absolutely dangerous&amp;rdquo; amount of busy work that pharmacists are expected to do on top of their principal concern of verifying prescriptions.
If this problem isn&amp;rsquo;t isolated, but instead is chain-wide, the risk to patients is staggering.</description></item><item><title>Opioid prescriptions, use, misuse, and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/opioid-prescriptions-use-misuse-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/opioid-prescriptions-use-misuse-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>I recently spoke with a national reporter who called to ask some questions about the state of medical malpractice in Texas. Specifically, our conversation focused on whether the Texas Medical Board is effective.
I quickly commented that, in my opinion, the Texas Medical Board is largely a worthless joke. I qualified my opinion by noting that there are a few types of matters that the Board takes seriously.
One of them, in my experience and opinion, is not the quality of care provided by Texas physicians.</description></item><item><title>Can supplements or medications injure a baby during pregnancy?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/can-supplements-or-medications-injure-a-baby-during-pregnancy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/can-supplements-or-medications-injure-a-baby-during-pregnancy/</guid><description>Pregnancy is a wonderful time of life for parents. Seeking early prenatal care with an OB/GYN physician is important to keep the mom and baby safe during pregnancy.
One of the important safety considerations during prenatal care is for the doctor to obtain a complete list of all prescription medications, over-the-counter drugs, and supplements that the mom is taking.
Some medications and supplements are safe to take during pregnancy. Others aren&amp;rsquo;t and can cause birth defects, brain injuries, or other serious medical conditions.</description></item><item><title>Doctor prescribes wrong dose of ADHD drug, causes death of grade-school child</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/doctor-prescribes-wrong-dose-of-adhd-drug-causes-death-of-grade-school-child/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/doctor-prescribes-wrong-dose-of-adhd-drug-causes-death-of-grade-school-child/</guid><description>One of the common prescription medication errors occurs when a doctor, physician&amp;rsquo;s assistant, or nurse practitioner prescribes the wrong dosage of a medication. In some cases, this can be life-threatening.
That&amp;rsquo;s exactly what happened to an elementary-school boy whose physician wrote a new prescription for a drug to treat his attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD).
Many medications, like this one, instruct prescribers to calculate the correct dosage based on the patient&amp;rsquo;s weight in kilograms.</description></item><item><title>Primary care doctor, pharmacy medication error leaves patient with Stevens-Johnson Syndrome</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/primary-care-doctor-pharmacy-medication-error-leaves-patient-with-stevens-johnson-syndrome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/primary-care-doctor-pharmacy-medication-error-leaves-patient-with-stevens-johnson-syndrome/</guid><description>After twisting his ankle, a 60-year-old man called his primary care physician because he was experiencing a great deal of pain.
The patient had an established relationship with the doctor, and his records reflected the patient&amp;rsquo;s past medical history of lupus, hypertension (high blood pressure), rheumatoid arthritis, chronic anemia, and kidney disease. The medical records also recorded that the patient was allergic to medications including naproxen (marketed under various brand names including Aleve), codeine, penicillin, and diphenhydramine.</description></item><item><title>Nuedexta prescription errors, falls, and medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/nuedexta-prescription-errors-falls-and-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/nuedexta-prescription-errors-falls-and-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>A little red pill called Nuedexta is a prescription drug manufactured by Avanir Pharmaceuticals that&amp;rsquo;s been approved by the U.S. Food &amp;amp; Drug Administration (FDA) to treat a medical condition called PseudoBulbar Affect (PBA). It&amp;rsquo;s currently only available under the brand name Nuedexta and there are no generic equivalents.
One of the big questions since Nuedexta blasted onto the scene in 2012 is whether it&amp;rsquo;s being overprescribed to elderly people who don&amp;rsquo;t need it&amp;mdash;and for whom it can actually be dangerous.</description></item><item><title>Feds slap Houston Methodist Willowbrook Hospital with citation after nurse fails to give patient medication</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/feds-slap-houston-methodist-willowbrook-hospital-with-citation-after-nurse-fails-to-give-patient-medication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/feds-slap-houston-methodist-willowbrook-hospital-with-citation-after-nurse-fails-to-give-patient-medication/</guid><description>Registered nurses and physicians caring for hospitalized patients share a lot of responsibility and tasks. When it comes to medications, though, the decision to start or stop a drug is one that falls in the doctor&amp;rsquo;s lap.
In 2019, an intensive care unit (ICU) registered nurse at Houston Methodist Willowbrook Hospital learned this the hard way. Based on the nurse&amp;rsquo;s mistake, the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services issued a&amp;nbsp; violation to the hospital, on May 21, 2019, related to administration of drugs.</description></item><item><title>Conroe doctor's over-prescriptions lead to death, arrest, and suspended medical license</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/conroe-doctors-over-prescriptions-lead-to-death-arrest-and-suspended-medical-license/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/conroe-doctors-over-prescriptions-lead-to-death-arrest-and-suspended-medical-license/</guid><description>All licensed physicians in the State of Texas are required to understand how prescribed drugs work, the therapeutic purposes for prescribing them, and when they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be ordered&amp;mdash;that&amp;rsquo;s called a contraindication. When a doctor prescribes a medication for which there isn&amp;rsquo;t a therapeutic purpose or when there&amp;rsquo;s a contraindication, it violates the standard of care.
These patient safety rules are true for every type of doctor, from pediatricians to geriatric physicians.</description></item><item><title>The risks you need to know about mail-order pharmacy services</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-risks-you-need-to-know-about-mail-order-pharmacy-services/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-risks-you-need-to-know-about-mail-order-pharmacy-services/</guid><description>A wrongful death medical malpractice lawsuit against a mail-order pharmacy highlights some of the unique risks to using this type of service to fill your prescriptions.
It&amp;rsquo;s well-known that health insurance companies are putting the squeeze on everything imaginable to boost their profits. One of the health insurance industry&amp;rsquo;s most recent ideas, which has been widely implemented, is to require patients to fill regular prescriptions through the mail, rather than at brick and mortar pharmacies.</description></item><item><title>One of the most common drug errors is giving 10 times the correct dose</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/one-of-the-most-common-drug-errors-is-giving-10-times-the-correct-dose/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/one-of-the-most-common-drug-errors-is-giving-10-times-the-correct-dose/</guid><description>Prescription drug overdose is a common type of medical malpractice caused by doctors, other prescribers, and pharmacists. I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about overdoses caused by patients who decide to swallow too many pills. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about the problem of doctors writing prescriptions for the wrong dosage and pharmacists filling them.
As part of the prescription drug approval process regulated by the U.S. Food &amp;amp; Drug Administration (FDA), drug manufacturers publish detailed prescription instructions that are printed on package inserts that are provided with the drugs.</description></item><item><title>Three ways you can improve your prescription drug safety</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-ways-you-can-improve-your-prescription-drug-safety/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-ways-you-can-improve-your-prescription-drug-safety/</guid><description>It seems like there&amp;rsquo;s a drug for everything. Just turn on a TV news station for an hour and count how many pharmaceutical ads you hear. What always strikes me about those ads is when the narrator goes over all the known risks at a super-fast speed.
For example, a new study recently published in JAMA Internal Medicine revealed that a common class of drugs called anticholinergics has been linked to an almost 50% increase in the odds of developing dementia.</description></item><item><title>What you should know about the unique risks of using a compounding pharmacy</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-the-unique-risks-of-using-a-compounding-pharmacy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-the-unique-risks-of-using-a-compounding-pharmacy/</guid><description>An Austin compounding pharmacy was recently in the news for allegedly overdosing a woman with a 54,000% higher dosage than what her doctor ordered.
Compounding pharmacies are regulated by the Texas State Board of Pharmacy and are legally allowed to create and mix tailor-made prescription drugs. While regular prescription drugs require rigorous advanced testing and approval by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA), that&amp;rsquo;s not the case for medications created by compounding pharmacies.</description></item><item><title>Suburban Houston rehab facility overdoses elderly patient on painkillers, causing aspiration pneumonia and death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/suburban-houston-rehab-facility-overdoses-elderly-patient-on-painkillers-causing-aspiration-pneumonia-and-death/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/suburban-houston-rehab-facility-overdoses-elderly-patient-on-painkillers-causing-aspiration-pneumonia-and-death/</guid><description>I recently met with a man who unexpectedly lost his wife because of medical malpractice.
The lady, in her late 60s, was active and in good shape for her age. She had an accidental fall that caused worsening intense pain around her tailbone.
She went to an urgent care center and then to a hospital in northwest Houston, Texas. She was diagnosed with a fractured sacrum (tailbone), probably because of age-related osteopenia, and a urinary tract infection.</description></item><item><title>Dentist prescriptions for unnecessary opioid painkillers increase addiction risk in teens and young adults</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dentist-prescriptions-for-unnecessary-opioid-painkillers-increase-addiction-risk-in-teens-and-young-adults/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dentist-prescriptions-for-unnecessary-opioid-painkillers-increase-addiction-risk-in-teens-and-young-adults/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s hard not to see a story in the media about opioid addiction. The statistics are sobering.
Around 130 people die in the United States daily after an opioid overdose. A significant chunk of that statistic comes from overdoses of prescription pain relievers and synthetic opioids like fentanyl. Around one fourth of chronic pain patients prescribed opioids misuse them and 8-12% of them become addicted.
Then there&amp;rsquo;s the issue of prescription drugs acting as gateways to illicit use.</description></item><item><title>Three steps you can take to prevent pharmacy errors</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-steps-you-can-take-to-prevent-pharmacy-errors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-steps-you-can-take-to-prevent-pharmacy-errors/</guid><description>Pharmacy medication mistakes happen more often than you might think.
A potential new client recently contacted Painter Law Firm about a prescription that a national pharmacy chain bungled. It all started when she hurt her ankle and her orthopedic surgeon prescribed pain medication. For about four months, the painkillers seemed to work well.
The next time she refilled her prescription, though, this lady noticed that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t taking care of the pain.</description></item><item><title>Two little-known ways to protect yourself from pharmacy errors</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/two-little-known-ways-to-protect-yourself-from-pharmacy-errors/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/two-little-known-ways-to-protect-yourself-from-pharmacy-errors/</guid><description>I bet there&amp;rsquo;s not a month that goes by when someone doesn&amp;rsquo;t call Painter Law Firm to get help after being seriously injured from a drug error.
I had a case involving M.D. Anderson Cancer Center where the pharmacy dispensed a medication for the patient&amp;rsquo;s pain pump that was several times the dosage prescribed.
In another case, a woman died on the operating room table during her hysterectomy because her OB/GYN doctor wrote her a prescription for a drug that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be taken while taking another medicine she had been prescribed.</description></item><item><title>New anticoagulant blood thinner regulations hit hospitals</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-anticoagulant-blood-thinner-regulations-hit-hospitals/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-anticoagulant-blood-thinner-regulations-hit-hospitals/</guid><description>Lots of people are prescribed anticoagulant drugs, also called blood thinners. These medications reduce blood clotting and are commonly prescribed to people who&amp;rsquo;ve experienced a stroke or heart attack and to reduce the risk of deep vein thrombosis (DVT), pulmonary embolism and other conditions.
Common anticoagulation medications include heparin, warfarin (Coumadin), rivaroxaban (Xarelto), dabigatran (Pradaxa), apixaban (Eliquis), edoxaban (Savaysa), enoxaparin (Lovenox), and fondaprinux (Arixtra).
According to The Joint Commission, the major hospital-accrediting organization in the United States, there has been a rise in adverse drug events associated with oral anticoagulation medications.</description></item><item><title>What to do when you think there’s a hospital cover-up</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-to-do-when-you-think-there%C3%A2s-a-hospital-cover-up/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-to-do-when-you-think-there%C3%A2s-a-hospital-cover-up/</guid><description>I frequently have conversations with clients who have a gut feeling that their doctors, nurses, and hospital representatives aren&amp;rsquo;t being totally honest with them. Sometimes, they believe they&amp;rsquo;re outright lying to them about something bad that happened during a hospitalization.
How we investigate medical coverups
As an experienced medical malpractice attorney and a former hospital administrator, I know where to look to get to the bottom of mysteries like this.</description></item><item><title>Opioid narcotic pain medication medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/opioid-narcotic-pain-medication-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/opioid-narcotic-pain-medication-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>It seems everywhere you look someone is either suffering from or talking about the opioid crisis.
Opioids are a highly-regulated class of powerful narcotic medications including painkillers like fentanyl, oxycodone, hydrocodone, codeine, and morphine.
Like their illegal cousin, heroin, prescription opioids are highly addictive and can get people hooked on them in as little as one dose. Knowing that, it&amp;rsquo;s not surprising that, since 2000, over 300,000 people have died from opioid overdoses in the United States alone.</description></item><item><title>Hospital, physician, and nursing medication error malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/hospital-physician-and-nursing-medication-error-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/hospital-physician-and-nursing-medication-error-malpractice/</guid><description>Any time that a patient is hospitalized, transferred to a new facility, or sees a new physician in an office setting, a healthcare provider&amp;mdash;typically a registered nurse (RN)&amp;mdash;obtains a medication history from the patient. This is the first step in a process that is called medication reconciliation.
At some doctor&amp;rsquo;s offices, clerks hand patients a stack of paperwork to fill out, burying the medication history form among them. Patients can understandably get fatigued after filling out their Social Security number and birthdate on five different forms and may not put much thought into the medication history form.</description></item><item><title>New law gives Texas pharmacists exclusive authority on whether to fill a prescription</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-law-gives-texas-pharmacists-exclusive-authority-on-whether-to-fill-a-prescription/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-law-gives-texas-pharmacists-exclusive-authority-on-whether-to-fill-a-prescription/</guid><description>A new Texas law gives pharmacists &amp;ldquo;exclusive authority&amp;rdquo; to decide whether or not to dispense a drug&amp;mdash;and they have no obligation to explain why.
House Bill 2561, which became effective on September 1, 2017, as Texas Occupations Code Section 551.006, was originally envisioned as a tool to make it easier for pharmacists to turn away patients who might be abusing opiates and painkillers. During the legislative process, though, language was added to the bill that would allow refusals to fill prescriptions on any ground.</description></item><item><title>Pharmacy malpractice: Pharmacist fills prescription at 15 times the prescribed dosage</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/pharmacy-malpractice-pharmacist-fills-prescription-at-15-times-the-prescribed-dosage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/pharmacy-malpractice-pharmacist-fills-prescription-at-15-times-the-prescribed-dosage/</guid><description>A mother recently called my office about a prescription error by one of the major national pharmacy chains.
She explained that her young son was having some depression issues, so she made an appointment with his pediatrician. The doctor wrote a prescription for Aripiprazole (also known under the brand name Abilify), an anti-depression medication, for dosage of 2 mg per day.
Aripiprazole is an antipsychotic medication typically used to treat schizophrenia and bipolar disorder.</description></item><item><title>Three factors affecting anesthesia safety and malpractice in the operating room</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-factors-affecting-anesthesia-safety-and-malpractice-in-the-operating-room/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-factors-affecting-anesthesia-safety-and-malpractice-in-the-operating-room/</guid><description>In May 2018, the&amp;nbsp;Journal of Patient Safety&amp;nbsp;published an article about how label design for medications affects patient safety during an operating room (OR) crisis.
The idea behind the study is straightforward. If an operating room supply drawer contains several bags of medication that look the same, it would be easy for a physician or nurse to grab the wrong one in a high-stress emergency situation.
To prove their point, researchers recruited nearly 100 anesthesia providers who were still in training.</description></item><item><title>Learn which high blood pressure medications raise pancreatic cancer risk by 66% in women</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/learn-which-high-blood-pressure-medications-raise-pancreatic-cancer-risk-by-66-in-women/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/learn-which-high-blood-pressure-medications-raise-pancreatic-cancer-risk-by-66-in-women/</guid><description>Somewhere along the way, I was introduced to the concept of the law of unintended consequences. I am sure you have heard of it, too. When it comes to medical and prescription drug malpractice, I recently heard someone put it like this: today&amp;rsquo;s miracle drug is tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s class-action lawsuit.
Have you ever wondered why that is the case?
There is a natural tension among drug manufacturers, the U.S. Food &amp;amp; Drug Administration (FDA), consumers, and how much evidence should be required before a new drug is allowed to go on the market.</description></item><item><title>How to minimize the risk of medication errors when filling a prescription</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-minimize-the-risk-of-medication-errors-when-filling-a-prescription/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-minimize-the-risk-of-medication-errors-when-filling-a-prescription/</guid><description>I presented a hospitalist expert for deposition today in a pending case. The patient went into the hospital for a total knee replacement. Prior to that, he had been up and around, active and working. Within a few days after his surgery, he developed a hospital-acquired bedsore. His doctors felt he would benefit from a brief admission to the inpatient rehabilitation unit at the hospital.
During his stay at the inpatient rehab unit, his attending physician, a physical medicine and rehabilitation doctor, two wound consultants, and a variety of nurses dropped the ball and his condition dramatically deteriorated.</description></item><item><title>Why it may be dangerous for your doctor to prescribe Cipro or Levaquin</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/why-it-may-be-dangerous-for-your-doctor-to-prescribe-cipro-or-levaquin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/why-it-may-be-dangerous-for-your-doctor-to-prescribe-cipro-or-levaquin/</guid><description>In July 2016, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approved safety labeling changes for a class of antibiotics called fluoroquinolones.
Fluoroquinolones are prescribed to kill infection-causing bacteria or to stop them from growing. FDA-approved drugs in this class include levofloxacin (Levaquin), ciprofloxacin (Cipro), moxifloxacin (Avelox), ofloxacin, and Gemifloxacin (Factive).
The FDA ordered safety labeling changes for these drugs because of risks that were uncovered under an FDA safety review. Research has shown an association between fluoroquinolone use, whether in oral form or by injection, and severe and sometimes permanent side effects including damage to tendons, muscles, joints, nerves, and the central nervous system.</description></item><item><title>New study exposes Texas nursing home anti-psychotic drug over-medication problem</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-study-exposes-texas-nursing-home-anti-psychotic-drug-over-medication-problem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-study-exposes-texas-nursing-home-anti-psychotic-drug-over-medication-problem/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I frequently handle cases involving nursing home and hospital medication errors. Unfortunately, in my experience, it seems that many nursing home healthcare providers use overmedication as a means of silencing patients and keeping them out of their hair.
I recall handling a case against skilled nursing facility (SNF) in the Sugar Land, Texas area. The family members of an elderly patient/resident of the facility told me how their loved one had been experiencing a lot of pain.</description></item><item><title>Anesthesia and deep sedation increase colonoscopy risk</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/anesthesia-and-deep-sedation-increase-colonoscopy-risk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/anesthesia-and-deep-sedation-increase-colonoscopy-risk/</guid><description>This week, the family of an elderly lady who had gone to the hospital for a routine, elective colonoscopy, called to ask Painter Law Firm to investigate a potential wrongful death matter.
The family was shocked to hear that the patient had a heart attack during the colonoscopy and passed away. Upon reviewing the medical records, they discovered that the healthcare team proceeded with the colonoscopy without getting cardiac clearance first.</description></item><item><title>Four steps to improve your prescription medication/drug safety</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/four-steps-to-improve-your-prescription-medication/drug-safety/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/four-steps-to-improve-your-prescription-medication/drug-safety/</guid><description>In my legal practice as a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I have represented countless clients who experienced problems as a result of medication issues. These problems come in a number of shapes and sizes.
Pharmacy and dosage errors
One kind of medication problem is dosage or pharmacy errors. I recently settled a case against MD Anderson Cancer Center, in Houston, Texas, where the doctor ordered one dosage of a medication and the hospital pharmacy filled and dispensed a dosage 1,000 times stronger.</description></item><item><title>Overmedication causes death of Marine veteran at VA hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/overmedication-causes-death-of-marine-veteran-at-va-hospital/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/overmedication-causes-death-of-marine-veteran-at-va-hospital/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I have frequently represented patients who suffered serious injury or death as a result of overmedication in a hospital, skilled nursing facility, or other healthcare setting.
Recently, I was saddened to learn of the death of a young U.S. Marine Corps veteran at a Veterans Affairs (VA) Medical Center. The Marine was honorably discharged in 2002, and received his health care at the VA hospital.</description></item><item><title>Three tips to protect yourself from potentially deadly pharmacy errors</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-tips-to-protect-yourself-from-potentially-deadly-pharmacy-errors/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-tips-to-protect-yourself-from-potentially-deadly-pharmacy-errors/</guid><description>A man recently sued Walgreens after he was given the wrong prescription. His physician had ordered a prescription for a muscle relaxant, cyclobenzaprine (Flexeril), to help treat pain that he was experiencing from a car wreck. According to the lawsuit, the Walgreens pharmacist gave him another customer&amp;rsquo;s medication by mistake.
The medication meant for the other patient, who, by the way had the same first and last name as the plaintiff, was alprazolam (Xanax).</description></item><item><title>What happens when there is a medication error at a hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-happens-when-there-is-a-medication-error-at-a-hospital/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-happens-when-there-is-a-medication-error-at-a-hospital/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I commonly hear from patients that they feel that their doctors and nurses were just too busy to pay close attention to their condition and treatment.
When reviewing medical records in our lawsuits, I frequently encounter medication errors, which I believe are caused by healthcare providers speeding through their work without taking safety precautions.
In addition to experienced medical malpractice lawyers, accrediting organizations, like the Joint Commission, have unique insight into frequently-encountered medical errors.</description></item><item><title>Medication prescription errors can cause permanent injuries or death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medication-prescription-errors-can-cause-permanent-injuries-or-death/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medication-prescription-errors-can-cause-permanent-injuries-or-death/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I have represented many clients who were seriously injured from a medication error.
An actual case that settled provides a good illustration of this danger to patient safety. A teenaged autistic boy, who is typically uncooperative as a result of his condition, was admitted to a children&amp;rsquo;s hospital for several dental procedures. An oral surgeon attending physician and a resident physician, still in training, perform the procedures under general anesthesia.</description></item><item><title>New FDA contraindications &amp; warnings on Tramadol &amp; Codeine for young people</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-fda-contraindications-warnings-on-tramadol-codeine-for-young-people/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-fda-contraindications-warnings-on-tramadol-codeine-for-young-people/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas attorney focusing on medical malpractice cases, I have been frequently hired by clients who have suffered terrible injuries from a medication error.
In my experience, there are generally two types of medication errors. The first is an overdose or underdose of a medication that would otherwise be appropriate to give the patient. The second is administering a medication that should not have been given to the patient at all.</description></item><item><title>Some hospitals are set up to allow physician medication errors</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/some-hospitals-are-set-up-to-allow-physician-medication-errors/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/some-hospitals-are-set-up-to-allow-physician-medication-errors/</guid><description>When the government encouraged, and later forced, hospitals to transition to electronic medical records, one of the big selling points was that they would reduce medication errors. Now that electronic medical records systems are widely used at hospitals all over Texas and nationwide, experts agree that they have had little to no impact on reducing adverse drug events in hospitals.
In a recent podcast by the Journal of the American Medical Association (JAMA), a physician from the University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, in Dallas, Texas shared details about a scary medical error that left a patient unresponsive for days.</description></item><item><title>Antibiotic medications are not risk free</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/antibiotic-medications-are-not-risk-free/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/antibiotic-medications-are-not-risk-free/</guid><description>A new study revealed that adverse drug events are common in hospitalized patients who are placed on antibiotics.
In a report published in the Journal of the American Medical Association, Johns Hopkins University researchers concluded that 20% of patients who received at least 24 hours of oral or IV antibiotics in the hospital had at least one antibiotic-associated adverse drug event.
The study looked at two categories of bad events.</description></item><item><title>The dangerous risks of opioid painkillers like Dilaudid and morphine</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-dangerous-risks-of-opioid-painkillers-like-dilaudid-and-morphine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-dangerous-risks-of-opioid-painkillers-like-dilaudid-and-morphine/</guid><description>A trial started this week in a Waco, McLennan County state court for a wrongful death medical malpractice lawsuit brought by a former chaplain at Hillcrest Baptist Medical Center. The chaplain is suing the hospital, now known as Baylor Scott &amp;amp; White Hillcrest Medical Center, over the death of his 35-year-old wife, Sarah Gann.
Mrs. Gann went to the emergency room because of back pain similar to kidney stones. Doctors and nurses in the emergency room gave her a powerful opioid painkiller called Dilaudid (also called hydromorphone), which her husband said caused her to have a bad reaction.</description></item><item><title>Epidural steroid injections come with life-changing risks</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/epidural-steroid-injections-come-with-life-changing-risks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/epidural-steroid-injections-come-with-life-changing-risks/</guid><description>As a Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I have had the opportunity to represent many clients who have been injured by epidural steroid injections. Even this week, I spoke with two new clients who had bad experiences that were caused by a surgeon&amp;rsquo;s mistake.
What are epidural steroid injections?
Typically, orthopedic surgeons or neurosurgeons recommend these injections to people who suffer from have neck, lower back, arm, or leg (sciatica) pain. They are intended as temporary fixes to help alleviate pain.</description></item><item><title>Too many painkillers can mask the root cause and cause serious injury or death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/too-many-painkillers-can-mask-the-root-cause-and-cause-serious-injury-or-death/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/too-many-painkillers-can-mask-the-root-cause-and-cause-serious-injury-or-death/</guid><description>Pain medications are a touchy and controversial topic.
Come to think of it, the very concept of pain is hard to define because each person perceives and experiences pain differently.
Many people depend on powerful painkillers like hydrocodone (Vicodin or Lorcet), OxyContin (oxycodone), and other opioid drugs just to take the edge of the constant extreme pain that they feel from a bad back, severe arthritis, or nerve issues. Other people are able to tolerate these conditions with medicines that are less powerful.</description></item><item><title>Surgery/pharmacology expert: M.D. Anderson Hospital pain medication error kills patient</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/surgery/pharmacology-expert-m.d.-anderson-hospital-pain-medication-error-kills-patient/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/surgery/pharmacology-expert-m.d.-anderson-hospital-pain-medication-error-kills-patient/</guid><description>As a Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I have seen cases where medication errors caused death or severe injuries more times than I can even count.
I am currently working on a medication overdose case involving a young man who was severely injured in a car wreck. The crash rendered him quadriplegic, and his back pain was so bad that he had to have a pain pump surgically implanted. The pain pump delivered pain medications directly to his spinal cord and provided him some relief.</description></item><item><title>Pharmacy errors can lead to dangerous and deadly outcomes</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/pharmacy-errors-can-lead-to-dangerous-and-deadly-outcomes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/pharmacy-errors-can-lead-to-dangerous-and-deadly-outcomes/</guid><description>On February 3, 2017, KPRC Channel 2 aired an investigative piece on pharmacy errors in the Houston area. I appreciate Channel &amp;#39;s2 highlighting this problem, because, as a Texas medical malpractice attorney, I have seen pharmacy mistakes cause injuries or deaths in many cases.
The Channel 2 story started with the story of a seven-month-old boy who had a kidney condition that required him to take maintenance antibiotics. In October 2016, the doctor prescribed a new antibiotic.</description></item><item><title>Dangerous low sodium needs prompt and proper medical care</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dangerous-low-sodium-needs-prompt-and-proper-medical-care/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dangerous-low-sodium-needs-prompt-and-proper-medical-care/</guid><description>I recently was contacted by the family of a middle-aged man who died from complication of hyponatremia, following care at Christus St. Elizabeth&amp;rsquo;s Hospital, in Beaumont, Texas.
Hyponatremia is a dangerous condition caused when a person has a low serum sodium level. Sodium is a very important electrolyte for our bodies, with roles in maintaining blood pressure, nerve communication and fluid balance. When a person has hyponatremia, it requires urgent and correct medical attention.</description></item><item><title>Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer Robert Painter files lawsuit that claims: Doctor &amp; CVS prescription error causes patient death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-lawyer-robert-painter-files-lawsuit-that-claims-doctor-cvs-prescription-error-causes-patient-death/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-lawyer-robert-painter-files-lawsuit-that-claims-doctor-cvs-prescription-error-causes-patient-death/</guid><description>The Houston medical malpractice attorneys at Painter Law Firm filed a wrongful death lawsuit against CVS Pharmacy, Inc. and a local OB/GYN doctor, concerning the tragic and needless death of a 37-year-old wife and mother of two.
In August 2012, this lady saw an OB/GYN because her monthly cycle had lasted for 14 days, and it was heavy and unusually painful. The OB/GYN prescribed Lysteda, a medication that prevents blood clots from breaking down, which the patient then filled at CVS Pharmacy, Inc.</description></item><item><title>Anesthesia: Ask these questions before you're put under</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/anesthesia-ask-these-questions-before-youre-put-under/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/anesthesia-ask-these-questions-before-youre-put-under/</guid><description>When it comes to surgical procedures, informed consent is a crucial step that patients and their families should never allow to be glossed over by physicians or nurses. It is your chance to make sure that you truly understand the risks versus benefits of the proposed treatment or procedure, as well as who will actually be involved with your care.
In many hospitals around Texas, informed consent is treated as a check-the-box exercise with little thought or discussion.</description></item><item><title>Hyponatremia after a head injury can cause brain damage or death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/hyponatremia-after-a-head-injury-can-cause-brain-damage-or-death/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/hyponatremia-after-a-head-injury-can-cause-brain-damage-or-death/</guid><description>Any time I hear about someone who has had a head trauma in a car wreck I find myself concerned about sodium, of all things. I can&amp;rsquo;t help it, because I have handled a number of cases where patients suffered brain injuries, and almost death, because of low sodium levels. I have also seen this in cases where patients had a sinus infection that spread to the brain.
For example, just a few weeks ago, I spoke with the father of young man in his 20s.</description></item><item><title>Texas finally takes first step in regulating 'pill mills'</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-finally-takes-first-step-in-regulating-pill-mills/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/texas-finally-takes-first-step-in-regulating-pill-mills/</guid><description>When it comes to pain management physicians, it is not enough to find a &amp;#39;board certified&amp;#39; doctor. Multiple boards grant that label and many are not very strict in their standards.
What should you ask before selecting a pain management doctor? Click here to read my special report.
There is another big problem in the pain management field, the so-called &amp;#39;pill mills.&amp;#39; There are over 200 so-called pain clinics in Houston alone, and many of them are &amp;#39;supervised&amp;#39; by absentee physicians who are rarely on site, and dispense powerful drugs without a physical exam.</description></item></channel></rss>