<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dental malpractice on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/dental-malpractice/</link><description>Recent content in dental malpractice on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/dental-malpractice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lawsuit alleges Houston oral surgeon caused nerve injury when pulling wisdom tooth</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-alleges-houston-oral-surgeon-caused-nerve-injury-when-pulling-wisdom-tooth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-alleges-houston-oral-surgeon-caused-nerve-injury-when-pulling-wisdom-tooth/</guid><description>Today Painter Law Firm filed a lawsuit against a Houston oral surgeon who caused a permanent lingual nerve injury when pulling our client&amp;rsquo;s lower wisdom tooth. The case is pending in a Harris County, Texas district court. Let&amp;rsquo;s call our client Lydia. Let&amp;rsquo;s call the oral surgeon Dr. Rush.
Have you ever experienced general anesthesia? Remember the uncomfortable numb feeling in the tongue and inability to taste? That&amp;rsquo;s what Lydia will experience for the rest of her life because of the injury that Dr.</description></item><item><title>4 questions you can ask to help avoid anesthesia malpractice in dental offices</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/4-questions-you-can-ask-to-help-avoid-anesthesia-malpractice-in-dental-offices/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/4-questions-you-can-ask-to-help-avoid-anesthesia-malpractice-in-dental-offices/</guid><description>Pediatric dental anesthesia is in the news again after a Houston district court jury awarded a verdict of nearly $100 million to the family of a brain-injured little girl named Nevaeh Hall. The award will be subject to reduction by the court to comply with Texas tort reform laws, but still communicates the jury&amp;rsquo;s outrage at what happened to this four-year-old dental patient.
Bethaniel Jefferson, DDS was Nevaeh&amp;rsquo;s treating dentist. The following information is from the dental malpractice lawsuit pleadings.</description></item><item><title>Dentist breaks patient's jaw while pulling wisdom tooth</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dentist-breaks-patients-jaw-while-pulling-wisdom-tooth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dentist-breaks-patients-jaw-while-pulling-wisdom-tooth/</guid><description>Our client&amp;mdash;we&amp;rsquo;ll call her Sydney Kaye&amp;mdash;is a Houston woman in her 30s who was referred to a general dentist to have a wisdom tooth pulled.&amp;nbsp;
Sydney Kaye remembers the dentist being in a hurry. She remembers getting two or three injections of anesthesia and then the dentist starting pulling the tooth while she could still feel everything going on. She remembers going home and being in excruciating pain once the anesthesia wore off.</description></item><item><title>Oral cancer misdiagnosis and dental malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/oral-cancer-misdiagnosis-and-dental-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/oral-cancer-misdiagnosis-and-dental-malpractice/</guid><description>June is Oral Health Month. This brings to mind one of the important functions of regular dental visits, oral cancer screening.
The standard of care requires dentists to perform a complete examination of the mouth and tongue to look for signs of oral cancer. Otolaryngologists (ear, nose, and throat/ENT physicians) may also perform this type of exam when consulted.
According to the American Cancer Society, oral cancer is most common in the tongue, tonsils, throat (oropharynx), floor of the mouth, and other parts of the mouth.</description></item><item><title>Jury awards $2.75 million verdict against oral surgeon in dental/medical malpractice case</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/jury-awards-2.75-million-verdict-against-oral-surgeon-in-dental/medical-malpractice-case/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/jury-awards-2.75-million-verdict-against-oral-surgeon-in-dental/medical-malpractice-case/</guid><description>Perhaps the most common type of complaint we hear from potential dental malpractice clients involves problems after having a wisdom tooth pulled.&amp;nbsp;
Wisdom teeth are often more complicated to extract than other teeth. Common complications include nerve injury, broken jaws or sinuses, and damage to adjacent teeth. For these reasons, many experts recommend having wisdom teeth extracted by an oral surgeon rather than a general dentist.
Oral surgeons are specialists who attended both dental school and medical school and have advanced clinical and surgical training.</description></item><item><title>The providers and risks of dental anesthesia and sedation</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-providers-and-risks-of-dental-anesthesia-and-sedation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-providers-and-risks-of-dental-anesthesia-and-sedation/</guid><description>Years ago, our pediatric dentist recommended anesthesia for one of our children who needed a routine filling. Before consenting, I had several questions that I wanted answered. I could tell by the responses of the dentists and her staff that they weren&amp;rsquo;t used to parents asking questions.
My concern over in-office dental anesthesia is the risk that something could go wrong. Many dental offices aren&amp;rsquo;t equipped with staff or supplies to handle a medical emergency.</description></item><item><title>Dental malpractice lawsuit after patient swallows gold crown, it lodges in lung</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dental-malpractice-lawsuit-after-patient-swallows-gold-crown-it-lodges-in-lung/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dental-malpractice-lawsuit-after-patient-swallows-gold-crown-it-lodges-in-lung/</guid><description>One of the well-documented risks of dental work is having a patient accidentally swallow or breathe in a foreign body or dental instrument. This is called accidental aspiration or ingestion, the standard of care requires dentists to exercise careful attention precautions to avoid it from occurring.
A recent opinion, entered by the Beaumont Court of Appeals, involved a patient who had several teeth pulled. According to the dental malpractice lawsuit pleadings, the patient inhaled a gold crown that fell from one of his back teeth while it was being removed.</description></item><item><title>What you should know about pediatric dental anesthesia</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-pediatric-dental-anesthesia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-pediatric-dental-anesthesia/</guid><description>I still remember the day, years ago, that a friend from our church referred her cousin to our office. It was sad to hear the shocked, grieving voice of that dad sharing how his two-year-old daughter died in a dental office from anesthesia complications. No one would think that this could happen for a routine visit to the dentist to have some cavities filled.
Early childhood caries (cavities) is the most common chronic childhood disease.</description></item><item><title>Boy's death highlights risks of dental sedation</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/boys-death-highlights-risks-of-dental-sedation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/boys-death-highlights-risks-of-dental-sedation/</guid><description>As a father of four children, I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine what the family of a three-year-old boy is going through following the death of their son from a routine dental procedure.
The little boy&amp;rsquo;s gums were inflamed and infected, so his mom took him to a Kansas pediatric dentist, who recommended pulling some teeth. The news reports are sparse on details of what happened at the dental office. We do know, though, that the young patient was sedated for the procedure.</description></item><item><title>The risks of dental general anesthesia for patients with sleep apnea</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-risks-of-dental-general-anesthesia-for-patients-with-sleep-apnea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-risks-of-dental-general-anesthesia-for-patients-with-sleep-apnea/</guid><description>Sleep apnea is a significant risk factor that must be taken into account any time a patient receives general anesthesia.
There are different types of sleep apnea, but the most dangerous one is obstructive sleep apnea. As the name suggests, with this type of sleep apnea, the affected person&amp;rsquo;s upper airway becomes obstructed multiple times while sleeping. When the airway is obstructed, breathing and oxygenation temporarily stop, which can cause a disruption of sleep and plummeting levels of oxygen in arterial blood.</description></item><item><title>Dentist prescriptions for unnecessary opioid painkillers increase addiction risk in teens and young adults</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dentist-prescriptions-for-unnecessary-opioid-painkillers-increase-addiction-risk-in-teens-and-young-adults/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dentist-prescriptions-for-unnecessary-opioid-painkillers-increase-addiction-risk-in-teens-and-young-adults/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s hard not to see a story in the media about opioid addiction. The statistics are sobering.
Around 130 people die in the United States daily after an opioid overdose. A significant chunk of that statistic comes from overdoses of prescription pain relievers and synthetic opioids like fentanyl. Around one fourth of chronic pain patients prescribed opioids misuse them and 8-12% of them become addicted.
Then there&amp;rsquo;s the issue of prescription drugs acting as gateways to illicit use.</description></item><item><title>Wisdom tooth extraction, negligence, and dental malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/wisdom-tooth-extraction-negligence-and-dental-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/wisdom-tooth-extraction-negligence-and-dental-malpractice/</guid><description>I focus my law practice on representing clients in medical and dental malpractice cases. In Texas, both medical and dental negligence lawsuits are regulated by the same restrictive tort reform statutes. That is why it is important to hire an attorney who is competent and has specific experience in handling these types of healthcare liability claims.
Recently, a dental patient contacted our office about a serious nerve problem she has been experiencing ever since she had her wisdom teeth extracted.</description></item><item><title>Alleged pediatric dental malpractice lands Houston dentist in police custody</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/alleged-pediatric-dental-malpractice-lands-houston-dentist-in-police-custody/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/alleged-pediatric-dental-malpractice-lands-houston-dentist-in-police-custody/</guid><description>Houston&amp;rsquo;s ABC Channel 13 recently reported that Houston dentist Bethaniel Jefferson, DDS was indicted and in custody on the charge of &amp;ldquo;intentionally and knowingly by omission&amp;rdquo; causing serious bodily injury to a child by failing to seek and provide adequate medical attention.
It is shocking that a four-year-old little girl ended up with severe brain damage in what started as a visit to have a tooth pulled. Her family filed dental malpractice suit was filed in July 2016, and the 281st District Court, where Judge Sylvia Matthews presides.</description></item><item><title>Dental local anesthetic injections can cause nerve damage</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dental-local-anesthetic-injections-can-cause-nerve-damage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dental-local-anesthetic-injections-can-cause-nerve-damage/</guid><description>Most adults have had the experience of needing a cavity filled or some other type of minor dental work that would be more comfortable&amp;mdash;or even tolerable at all&amp;mdash;with local anesthesia.
Thinking back on my dental care over the years, I cannot recall a single instance when a dentist explained to me the risks that come with a local anesthetic injection into my gums. I guess I never really thought about what could go wrong, that is, until I started handling more and more nerve injury cases in my career as a Texas medical and dental malpractice lawyer.</description></item><item><title>Dental procedures are riskier than you may think</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dental-procedures-are-riskier-than-you-may-think/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/dental-procedures-are-riskier-than-you-may-think/</guid><description>As Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I have represented clients who have suffered serious injuries at the hands of dentists.
Let&amp;rsquo;s face it. No one enjoys going to the dentist. For most people, though, that is because a trip to a dental office is viewed as an inconvenient time of discomfort, rather than a risky undertaking that could result in permanent injury, or worse.
There are two major types of injuries that I have seen from dental or oral surgery treatment.</description></item><item><title>What to do when the pain won’t go away after a dental or oral surgery</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-to-do-when-the-pain-won%C3%A2t-go-away-after-a-dental-or-oral-surgery/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-to-do-when-the-pain-won%C3%A2t-go-away-after-a-dental-or-oral-surgery/</guid><description>As a Houston medical and dental malpractice attorney, I have represented lots of people who have suffered from terrible problems after a surgical procedure.
While practically no one really enjoys going to the dentist, many people are unaware of the serious risk that some dental oral surgeries present.
Recently, I met with a new client&amp;mdash;I will call her Marjorie in this article&amp;mdash;about serious, life-threatening problems she had after an oral surgery procedure called tori reduction.</description></item></channel></rss>