<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>baby brain injury video on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/baby-brain-injury-video/</link><description>Recent content in baby brain injury video on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/baby-brain-injury-video/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney Robert Painter video: Watch fetal movements &amp; prevent brain injury</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-video-watch-fetal-movements-prevent-brain-injury/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-video-watch-fetal-movements-prevent-brain-injury/</guid><description>One of most rewarding things about helping people as an attorney in the area of medical malpractice is I get to learn a lot about narrow areas of medicine as they relate to the law. One of the areas where I spend a lot on time is cases is brain injuries and, in particular, the tragedies of brain injured babies. And as a father of four, these types of injuries are particularly bothersome to me.</description></item><item><title>Video: Brachial plexus injuries/Erb's Palsy from birth</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/video-brachial-plexus-injuries/erbs-palsy-from-birth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/video-brachial-plexus-injuries/erbs-palsy-from-birth/</guid><description>Video transcript:
Hi Robert Painter, and today we are going to be talking about a birth injury called Erb&amp;#39;s palsy, or also known as a brachial plexus injury.
Now the brachial plexus refers to a bundle of nerves that is found in on both sides of our bodies, really in the armpit area. Now during the birth process those nerves can get injured, and those can have devastating effects because the brachial plexus takes care of the motor, or the movement, function, in our arms, as well as the in sensation we have in this whole area - and even into the chest to some extent.</description></item></channel></rss>