<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>elder on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/elder/</link><description>Recent content in elder on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/elder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Two risks for families in accepting a rushed diagnosis of brain death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/two-risks-for-families-in-accepting-a-rushed-diagnosis-of-brain-death/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/two-risks-for-families-in-accepting-a-rushed-diagnosis-of-brain-death/</guid><description>As a Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I have frequently spoken with families about what to do when a doctor tells them that a loved one is brain dead.
Most people faced with this will have a sudden flood of emotions including emotions of grief and shock. On top of that, they have to confront trying to understand brain death and whether their loved one is really brain dead. This is always a topic of discussion when I speak with families going through this type of situation.</description></item><item><title>Patients beware: Physician care at rehabilitation facilities can be sparse</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/patients-beware-physician-care-at-rehabilitation-facilities-can-be-sparse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/patients-beware-physician-care-at-rehabilitation-facilities-can-be-sparse/</guid><description>Rehabilitation hospitals market themselves as facilities where patients can continue to receive health care after they are ready to be discharged from a regular acute care hospital, but are not quite ready to go home.
Sometimes, though, I believe patients would be better off going home. Let me explain why.
I have handled a number of medical malpractice lawsuits concerning rehabilitation hospitals like the Triumph/Kindred system and Reliant Rehabilitation. One of the common themes I see in these cases is very limited physician involvement in the care that is provided.</description></item><item><title>Robert Painter testifies before Texas House of Representatives</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/robert-painter-testifies-before-texas-house-of-representatives/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/robert-painter-testifies-before-texas-house-of-representatives/</guid><description>Robert Painter testified before the Texas House of Representatives Human Services Committee on April 12, 2011, in support of House Bill 3520. This legislation would amend the Texas &amp;#39;death panel&amp;#39; statute (Advance Directives Act of 1999).
Under current law, a hospital &amp;#39;ethics&amp;#39; committee can override the wishes of a patient or family for care to continue, if the committee decides that care is &amp;#39;medically futile&amp;#39;. The committee can meet with just 48 hours of notice to the patient, and if the committee finds against the patient the hospital only has to wait 10 days before terminating all curative care, nutrition and hydration.</description></item><item><title>Video: Hospital death panels in Texas</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/video-hospital-death-panels-in-texas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/video-hospital-death-panels-in-texas/</guid><description>Learn the shocking truth about how hospitals and doctors in Texas, not patients and their families, get to make the final decision as to whether health care continues or ends--ultimately meaning that they decide whether the patient lives or dies.
Resources
Video: Hospital Death Panels in Texas
Painter Law Firm&amp;#39;s &amp;#39;Surviving Hospitals&amp;#39; website on medical futility law in Texas
Transcript of the video :
Did you know Texas law is the worst in the nation when it comes to protecting patient rights when they may be coming to the end of life?</description></item><item><title>A new idea to fix the Texas 'death panel' law</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/a-new-idea-to-fix-the-texas-death-panel-law/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/a-new-idea-to-fix-the-texas-death-panel-law/</guid><description>The Advance Directives Act of 1999 has been in place for over a decade. Session after session, the Texas legislature has failed to amend it despite a terrible controversy over the provisions governing end-of-life care.
As it stands now, hospital committees, not patients and their families, have the ultimate say-so in whether a person receives curative care, food and water&amp;mdash;in other words, they make the &amp;#39;life and death&amp;#39; decision.
Plus, the due process provisions of the law are dubious: (1) Hospitals only need to give a patient and family 48-hours&amp;#39; notice of the committee meeting.</description></item><item><title>Video: Robert Painter speaks about the Texas futile care (death panel) law</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/video-robert-painter-speaks-about-the-texas-futile-care-death-panel-law/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/video-robert-painter-speaks-about-the-texas-futile-care-death-panel-law/</guid><description>Robert Painter addressed the Houston Disability Elder Law Association on the Texas &amp;#39;Futile Care&amp;#39; law on October 19, 2010 at The Downtown Club at the Met, in Houston. This article provides links to the video from that presentation as well as other resources. Many Texans are surprised to learn that the Advance Directives Act of 1999 allows a hospital committee to act as a &amp;#39;death panel&amp;#39; that can override a patient or family&amp;#39;s treatment wishes, even to the point of withholding care, treatment, food and water from a patient.</description></item><item><title>Developments in Texas Advance Directives</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/developments-in-texas-advance-directives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/developments-in-texas-advance-directives/</guid><description>This article was originally printed in&amp;nbsp;October 2009 edition of The Houston Lawyer magazine.
The balance of power between patients and physicians about end-of-life health care decisions has seesawed over the years. The development of "advance directives," led to a nationwide shift in favor of patients. Advance directives allow patients the opportunity to convey end-of-life decisions prior to a need arising. In Texas, these patient rights have diminished as legislators focus on development and implementation of the futility review process that authorizes health-care providers to have the final say under certain circumstances.</description></item><item><title>Death panels already exist</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/death-panels-already-exist/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/death-panels-already-exist/</guid><description>This op-ed was published in the August 19, 2009 edition of The Washington Times.
Former Alaska Gov. Sarah Palin, who says President Obama&amp;#39;s heath care reform would result in "death panels," needs to look no further than Texas to see a slippery slope like the one she envisions.
In Texas, a legislative provision that many thought was an innocuous proposal to help people has been twisted to snatch end-of-life decisions out of the hands of families.</description></item></channel></rss>