<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>valley on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/valley/</link><description>Recent content in valley on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/valley/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Valley Medical Center Brownsville, Texas medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/valley-medical-center-brownsville-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/valley-medical-center-brownsville-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I handle medical negligence and wrongful death cases throughout the State of Texas, including Brownsville, Cameron County, Texas.
Valley Medical Center is located at 100-A Alton Gloor Blvd., Brownsville, Texas 78526. It is owned by the hospital mega-chain HCA, which is based in Nashville, Tennessee. The hospital offers services including bariatric surgery, an emergency room, heart/cardiac/vascular procedures, diagnostic radiology imaging, laboratory services, rehabilitation and therapy, stroke and neurosciences services, and different kinds of surgeries (including general, orthopedic, neurosurgery, back and spine, and ear, nose and throat [ENT] surgery), and women&amp;rsquo;s services, including labor, delivery, and birthing.</description></item><item><title>Doctors Hospital at Renaissance (Edinburg, Texas) medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/doctors-hospital-at-renaissance-edinburg-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/doctors-hospital-at-renaissance-edinburg-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>Doctors Hospital at Renaissance, located at 5501 S. McColl Rd. Edinburg Texas 78539, is a physician owned hospital that is officially owned by Day Surgery at Renaissance Ltd, which is also based in Edinburg, Texas.
This Hidalgo County hospital has over 500 beds, treating over 285,000 patients each year. It offers services including a women&amp;rsquo;s hospital, Level III-C neonatal intensive care unit (NICU), an emergency room, bariatric surgery, cardiology, cardiovascular and thoracic surgery, colon and rectal surgery, cosmetic and plastic surgery, endoscopy, gastroenterology, general surgery, OB/GYN, labor, delivery, and birthing services, neurosurgery, diagnostic radiology, radiation oncology, and other specialty services.</description></item><item><title>Valley Baptist Medical Center Brownsville medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/valley-baptist-medical-center-brownsville-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/valley-baptist-medical-center-brownsville-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>Valley Baptist Medical Center is a short term acute care hospital located at 1040 W. Jefferson Street, Brownsville, TX 78520. It has been open for nearly a century and currently has 280 patient beds.
The hospital offers medical care including back and spine, behavioral health, brain and neurology, children&amp;rsquo;s care, digestive and gastrointestinal care, an emergency room, a foot care clinic, cardiovascular and heart care, radiology imaging services (CT, MRI and CT angiography), an intensive care unit (ICU), orthopedics, palliative care, surgical services (including joint replacement, spine, laparoscopic, minimally invasive, and da Vinci robotic surgery), women&amp;rsquo;s health, a neonatal intensive care unit&amp;nbsp; (NICU), and wound care.</description></item><item><title>Lawsuit: Botched propofol anesthesia care kills 33-year old father and teacher</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-botched-propofol-anesthesia-care-kills-33-year-old-father-and-teacher/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-botched-propofol-anesthesia-care-kills-33-year-old-father-and-teacher/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm filed a wrongful death medical malpractice lawsuit involving the tragic, avoidable death of Eli Tella. Mr. Tella, age 33, died at Knapp Medical Center, in Weslaco, Texas.
In February 2013, Mr. Tella went to the emergency room at Knapp Medical Center, with stomach pain and nausea. Prior to this illness, he had had a pretty clean bill of health. The emergency room doctor diagnosed Mr. Tella with pancreatitis and related conditions and admitted him to the intensive care unit.</description></item></channel></rss>