<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sugar land on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/sugar-land/</link><description>Recent content in sugar land on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/sugar-land/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Decreased fetal/baby movement is not something to ignore</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/decreased-fetal/baby-movement-is-not-something-to-ignore/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/decreased-fetal/baby-movement-is-not-something-to-ignore/</guid><description>Medical experts in the fields of obstetrics/gynecology and perinatology (high risk pregnancies) believe that a Cesarean section (C-Section) rate of around 19% of births or deliveries provides the correct balance for the health and safety of mothers and their babies.
Recent data about United States births show that about one-third of deliveries are by C-Section, rather than vaginal births. Some doctors blame the increasing use of health technology in American hospitals for this trend.</description></item><item><title>Sugar Land, Texas hospital patient death, suspicious autopsy looks like a cover-up</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/sugar-land-texas-hospital-patient-death-suspicious-autopsy-looks-like-a-cover-up/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/sugar-land-texas-hospital-patient-death-suspicious-autopsy-looks-like-a-cover-up/</guid><description>Some cases really stick out to me as showing why it is important for patients and family members to contact an experienced medical malpractice attorney quickly after a serious healthcare-related injury or death.
While the general two-year Texas statute of limitations is a good reason to do so, today I am talking about something else.
I recently spoke with a new client about a strange situation that happened with his mother.</description></item><item><title>Obstetrician office nurse bungles patient call, baby born with brain damage</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/obstetrician-office-nurse-bungles-patient-call-baby-born-with-brain-damage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/obstetrician-office-nurse-bungles-patient-call-baby-born-with-brain-damage/</guid><description>One afternoon, a woman in her late 20s was shopping with her husband in Sugar Land, Texas. She was 32 weeks into her pregnancy with their first child. When she went to the restroom, she noticed some blood in her urine, so they went straight to a local hospital for her to get checked out.
She told the hospital&amp;rsquo;s Labor and Delivery Department nursing staff how her stomach had been tightening for a few weeks.</description></item><item><title>Houston Methodist Sugar Land Hospital medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-sugar-land-hospital-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-sugar-land-hospital-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>Methodist Sugar Land Hospital is located at 16655 Southwest Freeway, Sugar Land, TX 77479, which is in Fort Bend County.
The hospital is a full-service acute care facility offering services and specialties including a cancer center, gastroenterology, gastrointestinal surgery, heart and vascular, neurology and neurosurgery, orthopedics and sports medicine, stroke, organ transplants, labor/delivery/birth of children, and breast care center. Methodist Sugar Land Hospital also has an emergency room and&amp;nbsp;intensive care unit (ICU).</description></item><item><title>St. Luke's Sugar Land Hospital (CHI St. Luke's Health Sugar Land Hospital) medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/st.-lukes-sugar-land-hospital-chi-st.-lukes-health-sugar-land-hospital-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/st.-lukes-sugar-land-hospital-chi-st.-lukes-health-sugar-land-hospital-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>The Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services recently announced that St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Sugar Land Hospital will be penalized for the 2017-2018 fiscal period because of quality of care concerns.
The U.S. Hospital-Acquired Condition Reduction Program included St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Sugar Land Hospital on its annual list of hospitals performing in the bottom 25% of all general hospitals nationwide, based on several categories, including:
Infection rates for hysterectomies, colon surgeries, central lines, and urinary catheters.</description></item><item><title>Family alleges patient death cover-up at Kindred Hospital Sugar Land</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/family-alleges-patient-death-cover-up-at-kindred-hospital-sugar-land/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/family-alleges-patient-death-cover-up-at-kindred-hospital-sugar-land/</guid><description>The Houston Chronicle recently published a shocking story that blew the lid open on how an 87-year-old Manuela Chapa died at Kindred Hospital Sugar Land, in Fort Bend County, Texas. The story is dramatically different from what the family says that they were told by the doctors at Kindred.&amp;nbsp;
Manuela&amp;rsquo;s daughter, Cris Chapa, checked her mother into Kindred Hospital Sugar Land for care related to pneumonia. Admission to a hospital for pneumonia is very common for elderly patients.</description></item><item><title>Lawsuit: St. Luke's Sugar Land Hospital pain killer overmedication causes patient death</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-st.-lukes-sugar-land-hospital-pain-killer-overmedication-causes-patient-death/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-st.-lukes-sugar-land-hospital-pain-killer-overmedication-causes-patient-death/</guid><description>The Houston medical malpractice lawyers at Painter Law Firm filed a lawsuit, on behalf of the family of Nell Kerr, against St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Sugar Land Hospital and two doctors. The was filed in the 270th District Court of Harris County, Texas, with Judge Brent Gamble presiding.
In June 2012, Nell Kerr was an otherwise healthy 75 year old woman who saw an orthopedic surgeon, for back pain and numbness in her fingers.</description></item></channel></rss>