<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>army on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/army/</link><description>Recent content in army on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/army/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to file a VA Medical Center medical malpractice claim</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-file-a-va-medical-center-medical-malpractice-claim/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-file-a-va-medical-center-medical-malpractice-claim/</guid><description>When a veteran is seriously injured because of health care provided at a U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center (VA Medical Center), different rules apply for making a medical malpractice claim. By different, I mean the rules aren&amp;rsquo;t the same as if the injury occurred at a non-federal government hospital.
As a U.S. Army veteran, former U.S. Army hospital administrator (the photo is of General Leonard Wood Army Community Hospital, as it looked when I served there), and son of a former VA Medical Center administrator, I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with the unique legal process that applies to VA medical negligence claims.</description></item><item><title>Army hospital medical malpractice cases</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/army-hospital-medical-malpractice-cases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/army-hospital-medical-malpractice-cases/</guid><description>Before going to law school, I served as an officer in the U.S. Army Medical Service Corps, where my MOS was 67B, health care administration. I was stationed at Fort Leonard Wood, where I was the hospital administrator for the Community Medicine Division of the General Leonard Wood Army Community Hospital.
I am thankful for the opportunity that I had to serve our country in the Army. Through that experience I learned firsthand how military hospitals work and saw know the unique challenges to providing health care in a military setting.</description></item></channel></rss>