<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>baby brain damage on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/baby-brain-damage/</link><description>Recent content in baby brain damage on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/baby-brain-damage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Caution: Normal Apgar Scores and Prompt Legal Action for Birth Injuries</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/apgar-scores-legal-action-birth-injuries/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/apgar-scores-legal-action-birth-injuries/</guid><description>The birth of a baby boy or girl is a milestone event of life that every parent remembers. In the hustle and bustle of labor and delivery, a lot of things happen. One of the first assessments performed on a newborn is the Apgar score, a quick evaluation that’s been around since the 1950s to look at the baby&amp;rsquo;s overall health.
However, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to understand that a normal Apgar score doesn’t necessarily mean that the baby has not suffered a brain injury during labor and delivery.</description></item><item><title>Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney Robert Painter files lawsuit that claims: Cypress OBGYN doctors fail to do Rh factor test &amp; cause newborn brain damage</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-files-lawsuit-that-claims-cypress-obgyn-doctors-fail-to-do-rh-factor-test-cause-newborn-brain-damage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-texas-medical-malpractice-attorney-robert-painter-files-lawsuit-that-claims-cypress-obgyn-doctors-fail-to-do-rh-factor-test-cause-newborn-brain-damage/</guid><description>Every person is born with a blood type, which could be A, B, AB, or O. Blood type is also called positive or negative; if Rh factor is present, the blood type of called positive. For example, my blood is O negative, which means that I have O type blood without Rh factor.
Rh factor is the name of a protein on the surface of red bloods of people with Rh-positive blood.</description></item></channel></rss>