<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>COVID19 on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/covid19/</link><description>Recent content in COVID19 on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/covid19/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Here's how the new Texas tort reform law will impact COVID medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/heres-how-the-new-texas-tort-reform-law-will-impact-covid-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/heres-how-the-new-texas-tort-reform-law-will-impact-covid-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>Rahm Emanuel, a former mayor of Chicago and advisor to Barack Obama, famously said, &amp;ldquo;You never want a serious crisis to go waste. And what I mean by that is an opportunity to do things that you think you could not do before.
To tort reform aficionados in Texas, COVID-19 is a serious crisis that they didn&amp;rsquo;t want to waste without getting more tort reform on the book. And, as of June 1, 2021, it looks like they&amp;rsquo;ll be successful&amp;mdash;that&amp;rsquo;s when Senate Bill 6 went to the desk of Governor Greg Abbott, who almost certainly will sign it.</description></item><item><title>COVID-19's impact on medical malpractice cases</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/covid-19s-impact-on-medical-malpractice-cases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/covid-19s-impact-on-medical-malpractice-cases/</guid><description>I keep reading a lot online or in the media about how some are expecting a delusion of medical malpractice lawsuits arriving from COVID-19 care. I&amp;rsquo;ve told everyone who’s asked me that I don&amp;rsquo;t see that happening.
Competent, experienced medical malpractice lawyers in Texas realize that one requirement to pursue any medical malpractice case is to produce expert testimony that defines the applicable standard of care. Generally speaking, the standard of care is what a reasonably prudent hospital/doctor/health care provider would have done under the same or similar circumstances.</description></item></channel></rss>