<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>memorial hermann on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/memorial-hermann/</link><description>Recent content in memorial hermann on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/memorial-hermann/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Houston Methodist charges almost double for a surgery than the cost at a nearby academic hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-charges-almost-double-for-a-surgery-than-the-cost-at-a-nearby-academic-hospital/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-methodist-charges-almost-double-for-a-surgery-than-the-cost-at-a-nearby-academic-hospital/</guid><description>According to the focus group research, the number one reason that people select a hospital is location. Not quality. Not whether you&amp;rsquo;ll be seen by a physician as opposed to a physician assistant (PA) or nurse practitioner (NP). Not even cost. Location.
I believe some of this phenomenon is because of the lack of information available to consumers. Most hospitals advertise that they offer top-notch care. Texas law allows hospitals to conceal the credentials and performance reviews of their physicians.</description></item><item><title>Memorial Hermann Greater Heights Hospital hit with Medicare quality of care violation</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-greater-heights-hospital-hit-with-medicare-quality-of-care-violation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-greater-heights-hospital-hit-with-medicare-quality-of-care-violation/</guid><description>Generally, I think it&amp;rsquo;s safer to have emergency room care, radiology imaging, or surgery at a hospital rather than an outpatient or ambulatory facility or surgery center. The reason for this is if something goes wrong, outpatient facilities don&amp;rsquo;t have the emergency equipment, supplies, and personnel on hand that hospitals do.
In fact, in case after case that I&amp;rsquo;ve handled involving an outpatient facility or surgery center, the first thing they do when there&amp;rsquo;s a problem is call 911 to get the patient to a hospital immediately.</description></item><item><title>The sovereign/official immunity trap at Memorial Hermann hospitals</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-sovereign/official-immunity-trap-at-memorial-hermann-hospitals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-sovereign/official-immunity-trap-at-memorial-hermann-hospitals/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The king can do no wrong&amp;rdquo; is a phrase that sums up the basis of the ancient doctrines of sovereign immunity and official immunity.
Even today, you can only sue the government or one of its employees to the extent that there&amp;rsquo;s a statute that allows it. In Texas, the statute is called the Torts Claims Act, and it protects state, county, and local governments, and their employees.
Under the strange interrelation of different Texas laws, did you know that the Tort Claims Act protects many doctors who work at Memorial Hermann Hospital or Children&amp;rsquo;s Memorial Hermann Hospital in the Texas Medical Center?</description></item><item><title>What you should know about filing a medical malpractice lawsuit against a Memorial Hermann hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-filing-a-medical-malpractice-lawsuit-against-a-memorial-hermann-hospital/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-you-should-know-about-filing-a-medical-malpractice-lawsuit-against-a-memorial-hermann-hospital/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I have investigated and handled numerous lawsuits involving care provided to my clients at Memorial Hermann hospitals.
Memorial Hermann Health System is the largest non-profit health conglomeration in southeast Texas. This massive system includes 16 hospitals, eight cancer centers, three institutes for heart and vascular care, 27 sports medicine and rehabilitation centers, and many other outpatient centers.
When a patient is severely injured or dies because of questionable care in a Houston hospital, it&amp;rsquo;s important to immediately hire a top-rated Houston, Texas attorney with significant experience in handling medical malpractice cases.</description></item><item><title>TIRR Memorial Hermann Rehabilitation and Research faces Houston medical malpractice lawsuit</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/tirr-memorial-hermann-rehabilitation-and-research-faces-houston-medical-malpractice-lawsuit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/tirr-memorial-hermann-rehabilitation-and-research-faces-houston-medical-malpractice-lawsuit/</guid><description>TIRR Memorial Hermann Rehabilitation and Research was recently sued in a Harris County District Court over an alleged overdose of narcotic pain medications that caused a former Houston Police Department officer to suffer an anoxic brain injury. The patient was receiving rehabilitation treatment for paralysis from a gunshot wound that occurred in the line of duty.
TIRR is a well-known rehabilitation facility located at 1333 Moursund St, Houston, TX 77030. It has 134 licensed beds.</description></item><item><title>Medicare gives two-star ranking (next to lowest possible) to Memorial Hermann Texas Medical Center</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medicare-gives-two-star-ranking-next-to-lowest-possible-to-memorial-hermann-texas-medical-center/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/medicare-gives-two-star-ranking-next-to-lowest-possible-to-memorial-hermann-texas-medical-center/</guid><description>Memorial Hermann Texas Medical Center recently received a two-star ranking&amp;mdash;the next-to-lowest one possible&amp;mdash;from the federal government&amp;rsquo;s Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS). CMS releases its annual star rankings of hospitals nationwide based on data obtained from its Hospital Compare website.
This 1,082-bed hospital is located in Harris County, Texas, at 6411 Fannin Street Houston, TX 77030, which is in the massive Texas Medical Center. Memorial Hermann Texas Medical Center is a major academic and research hospital that attempts to offer basic and comprehensive specialized services to patients.</description></item><item><title>Memorial Hermann Northeast Hospital receives lowest one-star rating from Medicare</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-northeast-hospital-receives-lowest-one-star-rating-from-medicare/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-northeast-hospital-receives-lowest-one-star-rating-from-medicare/</guid><description>Memorial Hermann Northeast Hospital recently received a one-star ranking&amp;mdash;the lowest one possible&amp;mdash;from the federal government&amp;rsquo;s Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS). CMS makes its star rankings of hospitals nationwide based on data obtained from its Hospital Compare website.
This 255-bed hospital is located in Harris County, Texas, near Bush Intercontinental Airport (IAH), at 18951 North Memorial Drive, Humble, TX 77338. Memorial Hermann Northeast attempts to offer typical acute care hospital care plus various specialized services, including a neonatal intensive care unit (NICU), cancer center, and primary stroke center.</description></item><item><title>Surgical malpractice after the operating room</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/surgical-malpractice-after-the-operating-room/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/surgical-malpractice-after-the-operating-room/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I have represented many clients in lawsuits involving all kinds of surgical care, from heart surgery to hernias, from cholecystectomies (gallbladder removal) to colorectal surgeries.
Surgical anesthesia negligence
In many operating room cases, the problem is not really with the surgeon, but rather with the anesthesia provider.
Operating room anesthesia providers could be a medical doctor anesthesiologist or, more commonly, a certified registered nurse anesthetist (CRNA).</description></item><item><title>Memorial Hermann Texas Medical Center receives 2 out of 5 star overall rating from Medicare</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-texas-medical-center-receives-2-out-of-5-star-overall-rating-from-medicare/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-texas-medical-center-receives-2-out-of-5-star-overall-rating-from-medicare/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I am very familiar with Memorial Hermann Texas Medical Center, which is located at 6411 Fannin, Houston, Texas 77030. It is a major academic and research hospital that offers a variety of specialized services and cutting-edge surgical care.&amp;nbsp;
According to Medicare&amp;rsquo;s hospital comparison data, there are quality of care concerns that current and future patients should be aware of.
Medicare ranks hospitals nationwide based on 57 quality measures related to common conditions that hospitals treat, such as heart attacks, pneumonia, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), and stroke.</description></item><item><title>The sad story of British baby Alfie Evans could happen in Texas under current law</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-sad-story-of-british-baby-alfie-evans-could-happen-in-texas-under-current-law/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/the-sad-story-of-british-baby-alfie-evans-could-happen-in-texas-under-current-law/</guid><description>I have followed with profound sadness the story Alfie Evans, a British toddler whose family is fighting hospital administrators, doctors, and British courts to keep him alive.
In my experience as a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, Alfie&amp;rsquo;s story is different from what I typically see in Texas cases, yet there are some profound similarities that should cause grave concern for Texans. Both in Texas and Great Britain, the fight is over a question called medical futility.</description></item><item><title>Three types of neonatal meningitis medical malpractice</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-types-of-neonatal-meningitis-medical-malpractice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-types-of-neonatal-meningitis-medical-malpractice/</guid><description>No matter what the age of the person, meningitis is a dreaded diagnosis.
Meningitis is defined as the inflammation of the meninges (membranes) that surround the brain and spinal cord. Bacteria, viruses, fungi, parasites, and amoeba can all cause meningitis.
Meningitis is more common in the neonatal period, meaning babies less than 44 days old, than in any other age group. It is so common, in fact, that this condition is referred to as neonatal meningitis.</description></item><item><title>Patients are endangered when clinical and ER doctors do not communicate with radiologists</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/patients-are-endangered-when-clinical-and-er-doctors-do-not-communicate-with-radiologists/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/patients-are-endangered-when-clinical-and-er-doctors-do-not-communicate-with-radiologists/</guid><description>I recently read the results of an online survey conducted by a physician group that looks at ways to prevent medical malpractice. As a former hospital administrator, I love to see healthcare providers taking a proactive approach, like this, that can improve patient safety.
The survey dealt with whether emergency room (ER) physicians review diagnostic imaging studies, like x-rays, CT scans, and MRIs.
madmimi.com/p/be23fb
While this rather informal survey was not intended to be scientifically or statistically valid, the results &amp;nbsp;were interesting to me, based on my experience in handling many cases involving radiologists and other physicians missing significant findings on radiology studies.</description></item><item><title>Memorial Hermann Texas Medical Center &amp; Children's Memorial Hermann Hospital medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-texas-medical-center-childrens-memorial-hermann-hospital-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-texas-medical-center-childrens-memorial-hermann-hospital-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>Memorial Hermann Texas Medical Center is a hospital located at 6411 Fannin, Houston, TX 77030. It is the flagship hospital of the Memorial Hermann Health System mega-chain of hospitals.
Memorial Hermann Health System has 16 hospitals, eight cancer centers, three heart and vascular Institute, and 27 sports medicine and rehabilitation centers, and numerous other outpatient and rehabilitation centers.
Memorial Hermann Texas Medical Center has 1,082 licensed hospital beds, including 278 for children, 68 for women, 147 in its Heart &amp;amp; Vascular Institute, and 589 for adults.</description></item><item><title>Memorial Hermann Greater Heights Hospital medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-greater-heights-hospital-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-greater-heights-hospital-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I investigate and handle cases all over the Houston metropolitan area.
It will probably not surprise you that the Memorial Hermann Healthcare System is the largest non-profit health system in Houston, as well as Southeast Texas. The system has 12 hospitals and around 5,500 physicians on the combined medical staff.
One of the hospitals in the system is Memorial Hermann Greater Heights Hospital, which is located at 1635 N Loop W, Houston, TX 77008.</description></item><item><title>Memorial Hermann Northeast Hospital medical malpractice lawyer/attorney</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-northeast-hospital-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-northeast-hospital-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice lawyer, I have handled many cases involving care provided to patients at Memorial Hermann Northeast Hospital.
Memorial Hermann Northeast Hospital is located at 18951 Memorial North, Humble, TX 77338. It has 255 licensed hospital beds and annually discharges over 13,000 patients. It has a cancer center and heart and vascular care center, and offers services including an emergency room, neonatal intensive care unit (NICU), diagnostic radiology, lung and respiratory services, neurosurgery, orthopedic surgery, sports medicine, general surgery, women&amp;rsquo;s services, and wound care.</description></item><item><title>Children's Memorial Hermann Hospital CAPS Team &amp; what you should know about it</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/childrens-memorial-hermann-hospital-caps-team-what-you-should-know-about-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/childrens-memorial-hermann-hospital-caps-team-what-you-should-know-about-it/</guid><description>I recently met with a new father whose infant has been bounced around three Memorial Hermann hospitals in her short life.
She was born at one Memorial Hermann suburban hospital and then transferred to another one of the system&amp;rsquo;s suburban hospitals that had a more-equipped neonatal intensive care unit (NICU). When she arrived at the second Memorial Hermann hospital, her family recalls the doctors and nurses saying that she should be fine.</description></item><item><title>Memorial Hermann Hospital System medical malpractice lawyer/attorney</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-hospital-system-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-hospital-system-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</guid><description>Any time we accept representation in a new case, we obtain all of the relevant medical records for careful review, and also thoroughly investigate reports of prior instances of inappropriate care at the hospital at issue. It is always good to know whether an incident is isolated or part of a broader pattern of conduct.
In addition to the court records maintained by the Harris County District Clerk, another excellent source of information is the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services.</description></item><item><title>Lawsuit: Memorial Hermann Northeast Hospital doctors misdiagnose imminent stroke (filed by Attorney Robert Painter)</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-memorial-hermann-northeast-hospital-doctors-misdiagnose-imminent-stroke-filed-by-attorney-robert-painter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/lawsuit-memorial-hermann-northeast-hospital-doctors-misdiagnose-imminent-stroke-filed-by-attorney-robert-painter/</guid><description>How is it that a young man who goes to an emergency room three days in a row with the worst headache in his life, but keeps getting discharged, ends up having a massive stroke on the third day shortly after he gets home?
That is the subject of a medical malpractice lawsuit that attorney Robert Painter filed this week against doctors at Memorial Herman Northeast Hospital, in Humble, Texas. The case is styled Manfred v.</description></item><item><title>Have you been injured by medical malpractice at Memorial Hermann Northeast Hospital?</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/have-you-been-injured-by-medical-malpractice-at-memorial-hermann-northeast-hospital/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/have-you-been-injured-by-medical-malpractice-at-memorial-hermann-northeast-hospital/</guid><description>While our office is located in Houston, Painter Law Firm&amp;rsquo;s medical malpractice lawyers represent clients who have potential cases against hospitals all over Harris County. This includes hospitals in Houston, like Memorial Hermann Northeast Hospital.
The types of cases we handle include surgical mistakes, anesthesia errors, infections, sepsis, birth injuries, falls, stroke, nerve damage, birth injury, childbirth complications, brain damage, diagnosis mistakes, medical device failures, medication and drug errors, wrongful death, and many others.</description></item><item><title>Memorial Hermann sues uninsured patients for medical bills</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-sues-uninsured-patients-for-medical-bills/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-sues-uninsured-patients-for-medical-bills/</guid><description>Several years ago, Texas medical malpractice attorney Robert Painter uncovered Memorial Hermann Health System&amp;#39;s habit of suing uninsured patients. He discovered it after an attorney for the hospital commented that every dollar that the hospital spent on settling medical negligence cases took away from its charitable care.
While Memorial Hermann undoubtedly provides charitable care, this nonprofit health system also has several top employees who are paid over $1 million per year, posh facilities and an ongoing and hard-to-understand pattern of suing many uninsured patients.</description></item><item><title>Houston Press coverage of firm's Memorial Hermann lawsuit</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-press-coverage-of-firms-memorial-hermann-lawsuit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/houston-press-coverage-of-firms-memorial-hermann-lawsuit/</guid><description>Harris County District Clerk records show that Memorial Hermann, a so-called nonprofit hospital system, regularly files lawsuits to collect hundreds of thousands of dollars from its uninsured patients. When Memorial Hermann sued a severely injured patient, Ignacio Alaniz, for over $400,000 in medical bills, he retained Painter Law Firm to help.
Read the thorough coverage by the Houston Press by clicking here.</description></item><item><title>KTRK ABC Houston's coverage of Memorial Hermann billing case</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/ktrk-abc-houstons-coverage-of-memorial-hermann-billing-case/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/ktrk-abc-houstons-coverage-of-memorial-hermann-billing-case/</guid><description>Click here to view Houston KTRK&amp;nbsp;Channel 13&amp;#39;s coverage of Painter Law Firm&amp;#39;s counterclaim against Memorial Hermann Health System concerning its unfair billing and collection practices against its uninsured patients.</description></item><item><title>Memorial Hermann sues uninsured patient for double the fees it would charge someone with insurance</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-sues-uninsured-patient-for-double-the-fees-it-would-charge-someone-with-insurance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/memorial-hermann-sues-uninsured-patient-for-double-the-fees-it-would-charge-someone-with-insurance/</guid><description>Memorial Hermann Health System is a charitable, tax-exempt hospital system that sues some of its neediest uninsured patients to get money for the care that it provides to them.
What&amp;#39;s shocking, though, is that Memorial Hermann sues and tries to collect from&amp;nbsp; its uninsured patients double or more the amount it accepts from its insured patients.
Health care attorney Robert Painter said, "We believe that Memorial Hermann&amp;#39;s billing practices regarding the uninsured are unconscionable and violate the Deceptive Trade Practices Act.</description></item><item><title>Painter Law Firm files suit for family against Memorial Hermann The Woodlands Hospital</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-suit-for-family-against-memorial-hermann-the-woodlands-hospital/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-suit-for-family-against-memorial-hermann-the-woodlands-hospital/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm filed a lawsuit in Houston, Texas against Memorial Hermann The Woodlands Hospital, on behalf of the family of Irene Dixon.
In March 2010, Mrs. Dixon was a 78 year old lady who tripped at church and broke her hip. An ambulance took her to Memorial Hermann The Woodlands Hospital and doctors planned for a hip surgery.
Before that happened, though, she started acting confused and had a change in mental status.</description></item></channel></rss>