<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>protect your health care on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/protect-your-health-care/</link><description>Recent content in protect your health care on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/protect-your-health-care/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Patients beware: Physician care at rehabilitation facilities can be sparse</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/patients-beware-physician-care-at-rehabilitation-facilities-can-be-sparse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/patients-beware-physician-care-at-rehabilitation-facilities-can-be-sparse/</guid><description>Rehabilitation hospitals market themselves as facilities where patients can continue to receive health care after they are ready to be discharged from a regular acute care hospital, but are not quite ready to go home.
Sometimes, though, I believe patients would be better off going home. Let me explain why.
I have handled a number of medical malpractice lawsuits concerning rehabilitation hospitals like the Triumph/Kindred system and Reliant Rehabilitation. One of the common themes I see in these cases is very limited physician involvement in the care that is provided.</description></item><item><title>Holidays are a good time to avoid hospitals</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/holidays-are-a-good-time-to-avoid-hospitals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/holidays-are-a-good-time-to-avoid-hospitals/</guid><description>Have you ever noticed that any time you or family member gets sick, it seems to happen on an evening, weekend or holiday? That certainly seems how it goes in our family. Did you know, though, that during these times the risk of medical and nursing errors in the hospital is much higher than normal?
If possible, avoid hospitals on weekends, evenings and holidays
No matter the occupation or workplace, most people enjoy taking time off from work around the holidays and during the summer.</description></item><item><title>How to spot life-threatening infections and sepsis</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-spot-life-threatening-infections-and-sepsis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/how-to-spot-life-threatening-infections-and-sepsis/</guid><description>Infections occur when bacteria or fungi invade the human body and then start multiplying and feeding. There are many types of infections that we commonly hear about, including staph infections, MRSA infections (methicillin-resistant staph aureus), bedsores and infected catheters or lines.
It is always a serious matter when a patient has an active infection. Prompt diagnosis is important because the faster treatment begins, the more likely the infection can be killed and the patient can go on with his or her life.</description></item><item><title>Three secrets about how hospitals and doctors hide their past mistakes from the public</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-secrets-about-how-hospitals-and-doctors-hide-their-past-mistakes-from-the-public/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/three-secrets-about-how-hospitals-and-doctors-hide-their-past-mistakes-from-the-public/</guid><description>There is not a week that goes by when a client does not ask me &amp;ldquo;Has the doctor done this to anyone else?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Why did the hospital let the doctor practice at its facility?&amp;rdquo;
These are straightforward and understandable questions. After all, people regularly check out service providers at sites like the Better Business Bureau or Angie&amp;rsquo;s List. Yet, the medical profession is unique in that its self-policing is shrouded in secrecy.</description></item><item><title>New study shows tragic consequences of poor hospital communication</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-study-shows-tragic-consequences-of-poor-hospital-communication/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/new-study-shows-tragic-consequences-of-poor-hospital-communication/</guid><description>I have handled many medical malpractice cases where a gap in communication at a hospital causes a patient to get severely injured or even die.
It usually happens like this.
A doctor orders some lab work or a radiological study, like a CT scan or MRI. After the results are in, a nurse, lab tech or radiology tech does not information the physician who ordered the study. When the results are critical, this means that precious time is lost when the physician remains in the dark and cannot order life-saving treatment.</description></item></channel></rss>