<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>pitocin on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/pitocin/</link><description>Recent content in pitocin on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/pitocin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pitocin and Medical Negligence: What Every Expectant Parent Should Know</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/pitocin-baby-mother-labor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/pitocin-baby-mother-labor/</guid><description>As a Texas medical malpractice attorney who&amp;rsquo;s handled numerous birth injury cases, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen firsthand the devastating consequences that can result from the misuse of Pitocin during labor and delivery. While this synthetic hormone can be a valuable medication and tool for managing labor, its improper use can lead to serious complications for both mother and baby. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into what Pitocin is, its uses, risks, and the legal implications when things go wrong.</description></item><item><title>Pitocin causes excessive contractions, brain injury in baby</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/pitocin-causes-excessive-contractions-brain-injury-in-baby/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/pitocin-causes-excessive-contractions-brain-injury-in-baby/</guid><description>Obstetricians (OB/GYNs) sometimes recommend induction of labor when a pregnant woman reaches full term but hasn&amp;rsquo;t delivered her baby.
What is induction of labor?
Doctors and labor and delivery nurses induce labor by injecting Pitocin (a manufactured form of oxytocin) into an intravenous (IV) line. Pitocin causes the uterus to start contracting and often succeeds in getting active labor underway before it would&amp;rsquo;ve happened on its own.
Sometimes induction of labor is largely for convenience, but there are a variety of medical reasons why a physician may recommend it:</description></item><item><title>Oxytocin/Pitocin medication errors linked to fetal distress, brain injury, and uterine rupture</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/oxytocin/pitocin-medication-errors-linked-to-fetal-distress-brain-injury-and-uterine-rupture/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/oxytocin/pitocin-medication-errors-linked-to-fetal-distress-brain-injury-and-uterine-rupture/</guid><description>One of the top medication errors in 2020 involves the misuse of the powerful medication oxytocin.
Oxytocin is the generic version of the brand-name medication Pitocin. These drugs are used to induce, augment, or stimulate expectant mothers to go into labor. They work by causing the uterus to contract.
The prevalence of oxytocin in hospital labor and delivery units has dramatically grown; thus, so, too, have the risks. According to data from the Centers for Disease Control &amp;amp; Prevention (CDC) the rate of induction of labor is around 23%.</description></item></channel></rss>