<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>san antonio on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/san-antonio/</link><description>Recent content in san antonio on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/san-antonio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>San Antonio Medical Malpractice Attorney</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/areas-we-serve/san-antonio/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/areas-we-serve/san-antonio/</guid><description>Life in San Antonio, Texas, thrives with vibrant neighborhoods and exceptional medical facilities catering to the community&amp;#39;s health needs. Despite the city&amp;#39;s friendly nature, accidents do happen, and medical malpractice cases can leave individuals and families in distress. If you or your loved one have suffered harm due to medical negligence, rest assured that you have the right to seek just compensation under Texas law.
Understanding Medical Malpractice in San Antonio
In unfortunate circumstances, medical errors can lead to physical or psychological harm to innocent patients.</description></item><item><title>Patient dies from nursing home fall despite documented high risk</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/patient-dies-from-nursing-home-fall-despite-documented-high-risk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/patient-dies-from-nursing-home-fall-despite-documented-high-risk/</guid><description>A physician friend of mine recently commented on social media that, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m old enough to remember when surgeons would take patients to the OR [operating room] for appys [appendix removal surgery] or cholecystitis [gallbladder inflammation] based on the physical exam and history. I still love those old school surgeons.&amp;rdquo;
Her comment got me thinking about how old school medical care is different than what’s touted as improved care today. Some hospitals and facilities create systems that try and force physicians, physician assistants, nurse practitioners, and nurses to serve metrics and computers rather than the patients they&amp;rsquo;re supposed to be taking care of.</description></item><item><title>Baptist Medical Center San Antonio medical malpractice lawyer/attorney</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baptist-medical-center-san-antonio-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baptist-medical-center-san-antonio-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</guid><description>As a Houston, Texas medical malpractice attorney, I handle medical negligence and wrongful death cases throughout the State of Texas, including the San Antonio area.
One of the major San Antonio hospitals is Baptist Medical Center, which is located at 111 Dallas Street, San Antonio, TX 78205. According to the American Hospital Directory, this hospital has 1,487 beds and a total patient revenue exceeding $6.6 billion.
The hospital offers services including cancer care, cardiovascular care, digestive disorders, elder care, an emergency room, home health, diagnostic imaging services, neurology, orthopedic surgery, pediatric care, primary care, rehabilitation services, a sleep center, spinal care and surgery, stroke and vascular care, surgical services, robotic surgery, urgent care, weight loss/bariatric surgery, and women&amp;rsquo;s health, including maternity, labor, delivery, and birthing care.</description></item><item><title>Christus Santa Rosa Hospital San Antonio medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/christus-santa-rosa-hospital-san-antonio-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/christus-santa-rosa-hospital-san-antonio-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>As a medical malpractice attorney based in Houston, Texas, I handle lawsuits all over the State of Texas, including in the San Antonio area.
Christus Santa Rosa Health System, in the San Antonio area
The Christus Santa Rosa Health System is a division of Christus Health. It traces its roots to 1869, and, as a whole, has 1,159 licensed hospital beds and five full-service hospitals.
The Christus Santa Rosa Health System includes The Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital of San Antonio, Christus Santa Rosa Hospital Alamo Heights, Christus Santa Rosa Hospital Medical Center, Christus Santa Rosa Hospital New Braunfels, Christus Santa Rosa Hospital Westover Hills, Christus Santa Rosa Emergency Center Alon, Christus Santa Rosa Emergency Center Bandera, Christus Santa Rosa Emergency Center Creekside, Christus Transplant Institute, and Christus Santa Rosa Physicians Ambulatory Surgery Centers.</description></item><item><title>What to do when your doctor downplays your symptoms</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-to-do-when-your-doctor-downplays-your-symptoms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/what-to-do-when-your-doctor-downplays-your-symptoms/</guid><description>A new client recently called our office about poor health care he received at a primary care clinic in San Antonio.
The man went to see his primary care provider because of ear pain that radiated down into his jaw. Strangely, the physician did not examine or look into the patient&amp;rsquo;s ear but instead quickly concluded that he had arthritis.
Over the course of the next two months, the pain did not resolve so he returned to the primary care clinic on two more occasions.</description></item></channel></rss>