<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>beaumont on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/section/beaumont/</link><description>Recent content in beaumont on Painter Law Firm Medical Malpractice Attorneys</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://painterfirm.com/section/beaumont/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Painter Law Firm files medical malpractice lawsuit involving man's death at Christus St. Elizabeth Hospital in Beaumont, Texas</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-medical-malpractice-lawsuit-involving-mans-death-at-christus-st.-elizabeth-hospital-in-beaumont-texas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/painter-law-firm-files-medical-malpractice-lawsuit-involving-mans-death-at-christus-st.-elizabeth-hospital-in-beaumont-texas/</guid><description>Painter Law Firm recently filed a medical malpractice wrongful death lawsuit against Christus St. Elizabeth Hospital, in Beaumont, Texas. The Jefferson County District Clerk assigned the case a cause number B-203726, in the 60th District Court, where The Hon. Justin Sanderson is the presiding judge. You can read the original petition here.
Christus St. Elizabeth Hospital is a 431-bed acute care hospital located at 2830 Calder Avenue, Beaumont, Texas 77702.</description></item><item><title>Beaumont man dies from hospital-acquired infection during treatment from car wreck injuries</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/beaumont-man-dies-from-hospital-acquired-infection-during-treatment-from-car-wreck-injuries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/beaumont-man-dies-from-hospital-acquired-infection-during-treatment-from-car-wreck-injuries/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m working on a case in Beaumont, Texas dealing with the wrongful death of a middle-aged man. He survived a car wreck and died from medical malpractice at a local hospital.
When patients arrive at the hospital after a bad car wreck, the doctors must work them up for blunt trauma injuries. The challenging part of this task is that most of the time the patient&amp;rsquo;s entire body is involved, from head to toe.</description></item><item><title>Christus St. Elizabeth Hospital Beaumont medical malpractice attorney/lawyer</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/christus-st.-elizabeth-hospital-beaumont-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/christus-st.-elizabeth-hospital-beaumont-medical-malpractice-attorney/lawyer/</guid><description>Christus St. Elizabeth Hospital (Christus Southeast Texas&amp;mdash;St. Elizabeth Hospital), located at 2830 Calder St., Beaumont, Texas 77702, is a 431-bed hospital owned by Christus Southeast Texas, based in Beaumont.
The hospital provides healthcare in a variety of areas, including emergency medicine (emergency room) and Level III trauma center, labor and deliver, birthing, neonatal care, spine and orthopedic surgery, general surgery, bariatric surgery, cardiology, oncology (cancer), and critical care. The Joint Commission has designated Christus St.</description></item><item><title>Baptist Beaumont Hospital medical malpractice lawyer/attorney</title><link>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baptist-beaumont-hospital-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://painterfirm.com/medmal/baptist-beaumont-hospital-medical-malpractice-lawyer/attorney/</guid><description>Baptist Beaumont Hospital is a private hospital located at 3080 College Street, Beaumont, TX 77701. The hospital has been in business for over 60 years and is part of the Baptist Hospitals of Southeast Texas. It is licensed for 508 beds.
The health services at Baptist Beaumont Hospital include a cancer center, heart/cardiovascular services, pediatric/children services, surgical services (including minimally invasive, bariatric, heart, vascular, orthopedic, general, gynecologic, and ear, nose, and throat [ENT] surgery), radiology scans (including x-ray, CT, MRI, and mammograms), an emergency room, behavioral health, and advanced primary stroke care center, and accredited Cycle IV chest pain center, and women&amp;rsquo;s services.</description></item></channel></rss>